<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Ash Furrow</title>
    <description>Learning and teaching about interesting topics in iOS Development. Sometimes I diverge to talk about design, photography, or what-have-you.</description>
    <link>https://ashfurrow.com/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Bargainville</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/bargainville/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of my oldest memories are of riding in my father&amp;rsquo;s 1998 red Toyota 4runner listening to a cassette tape of the Moxy Früvous album &lt;em&gt;Bargainville&lt;/em&gt; (1993). I was walking this morning and I put the album on and it still really speaks to me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/6OGn8UPY9GnwhR1068nR7x" width="300" height="380" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was always fond of &lt;em&gt;River Valley&lt;/em&gt; because it&amp;rsquo;s a catchy tune, and I grew up in a river valley. Listening to it today, during the incipient climate collapse, is chilling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your favourite place controlled by developing ambitions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think you&amp;rsquo;ll have some power signing a petition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you fine with your surroundings? Are they gonna crumble?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anyway. I kept listening, and kept hearing the same sort of left wife anthems come through. I mean, this seems on the nose by contemporary standards, but in the 90&amp;rsquo;s this was somewhat subversive stuff.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clem had a daydream, a daydream from heaven&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picked up the headline, his country was made up of singers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no more right-wingers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wakes up to &amp;ldquo;Homeless are stupid, welfare is stupid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private investment, efficiency, cool fiscal plannin&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like more Pat Buchanan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in listening to 90&amp;rsquo;s Canadian folk rock, you could do a lot worse than &lt;em&gt;Bargainville&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;(giant pile of filth Jian Ghomeshi notwithstanding)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; javascript apologist (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/908311114685054976"&gt;September 14, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 18:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/bargainville/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And I Feel Fine</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/and-i-feel-fine/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling lately with political &amp;ldquo;feelpinions&amp;rdquo;, political opinions mostly informed by feelings. I have strong opinions about a lot of what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the world at the moment, but those opinions are backed by feelings instead of things like in-depth research. I just don&amp;rsquo;t have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can handle this, even when my opinions come into conflict with someone else&amp;rsquo;s. After all – their opinions are probably not more informed than mine. But when what &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; believe conflicts with mainstream narratives, life becomes hard. Reading the news or talking with colleagues is oftentimes difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Politic&amp;rsquo;s is back baby. It&amp;rsquo;s good again. Awoouu (wolf Howl)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; wint (@dril) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dril/status/568056615355740160"&gt;February 18, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I continue, I&amp;rsquo;d like to address the fact that that last paragraph probably sounded a bit conspiratorial. &amp;ldquo;Mainstream narratives&amp;rdquo; etc. My opinions aren&amp;rsquo;t really that extreme – they&amp;rsquo;re just outside the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overton_window"&gt;Overton window&lt;/a&gt;. For example, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty obvious to me that capitalism is wholly incapable of dealing with climate change. However, I still need to survive my day-to-day life in a society built on capitalism; it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to motivate myself to work building tools for the art market when I know that that market exists inside a system that&amp;rsquo;s thrusting our species towards its inescapable doom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And, obviously, I need to acknowledge that interacting with the rest of society has been even more difficult lately because of &lt;a href="/blog/some-updates/"&gt;some recent life changes&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help me cope, and maybe to let others of similar opinions know that they&amp;rsquo;re not alone, I&amp;rsquo;m going to rapid-fire some political feelpinions I have that go against the grain of what&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; – opinions I have that I haven&amp;rsquo;t necessarily interrogated in-depth, but opinions I hold nevertheless. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capitalism is responsible for a massive amount of worldwide suffering, and this suffering overwhelmingly affects women, people of colour, people living in poverty, and members of other marginalized groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Climate change is going to continue getting worse, and will get more worse more quickly as time goes on. Our species is likely headed to extinction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.dsausa.org"&gt;Democratic Socialists of America&lt;/a&gt; are a cool organization, but are not without their flaws. They do &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/neworleansdsa/status/901549034699194369"&gt;good work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many criticisms of Hillary Clinton are based in (and motivated by) misogyny. This fact is used by centrists to stifle legitimate criticisms of her policies. (For in-depth feminist critique of Clinton&amp;rsquo;s policies, check out &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2jbPzwd"&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many criticisms of Israel are based in (and motivated by) antisemitism. This fact is used by centrists to stifle legitimate criticisms of the country&amp;rsquo;s policies. After all, Israel is a country, and &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; countries&amp;rsquo; policies have flaws, therefore Israel&amp;rsquo;s policies have flaws. This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a controversial statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Democratic Party is deeply, deeply flawed. Probably irreparably. They represent the interests of their donors first and foremost, and have failed to offer a meaningful resistance to the rise of fascism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2016 Clinton presidential campaign banked too heavily on &amp;ldquo;not being Donald Trump&amp;rdquo; instead of presenting appealing social policies (for example, single payer health care).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew! That felt good. Certainly not an exhaustive list. If you agree with any of these, that&amp;rsquo;s cool. If not, don&amp;rsquo;t @ me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world, baby!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/and-i-feel-fine/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Updates</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/some-updates/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bit of a personal post, but wanted to updated after some tweets I made about my medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Recently found the perfect Rx combo to help me with depression. Works really well for me. Tuesday, I had to stop b/c a serious side-effect 😔&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; the javascript lover (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/901838857683038212"&gt;August 27, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Things have been going really well for me (which I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;a href="/blog/therapys-end/"&gt;recently written about&lt;/a&gt;) and this medication change kind of came out of the blue. It sucks to find a groove and then have it disrupted, but life is a journey and there are lots of other medications I can try. I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that the adverse side-effect that required me to suddenly stop taking one of my meds aren&amp;rsquo;t permanent (it&amp;rsquo;s a neurological problem, so it might be). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I went off this medication (which was a tapered change and not a hard stop, like this time) &lt;a href="/blog/feelings-are-hard/"&gt;things got really hard really quickly&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly two weeks now and while I&amp;rsquo;m definitely feeling down, but I&amp;rsquo;m also being proactive about managing the imminent mood problems. For example, I find getting out the door in the mornings to be difficult, and it kind of sets the tone for the whole day. So I have a schedule written out of what exactly to do in the mornings, including some self-care to make sure my mood stays stable throughout the day. It&amp;rsquo;s been helping a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good. We&amp;rsquo;ll see. I&amp;rsquo;m in high spirits, for now, but like I&amp;rsquo;ve said before: I&amp;rsquo;ve got a supportive partner, friends, and work environment. I&amp;rsquo;ll be fine, just need to remember that I&amp;rsquo;ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 15:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/some-updates/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music is Back</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/music-is-back/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I was in New Brunswick, Canada, visiting my family. It&amp;rsquo;d been a while since I had gotten out there, and I&amp;rsquo;m one of the few Furrows to have left our part of the world. After the trip, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling reconnected to my family profound way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I was excited to bring my saxophone back to New York with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve not really talked online about my past as a musician; I studied piano and saxophone from ages 11 to 18. And I was, like, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; into it. Even after taking a half-time job at RadioShack (aww yeah) I kept up with both throughout high school. Here&amp;rsquo;s a recording of the jazz band that I was a member of in high school. I played one of the saxophones, and take the first saxophone solo you hear (at the 1:50 mark).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/338714156&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But shortly after starting university, I gave up. I had my saxophone with me, but I was working hard to maintain my scholarship and without a band to play along with, it was hard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have free time now, and guitar has been awesome for me, so why not dig my sax out of storage while I&amp;rsquo;m home?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BX8VJkLgT67/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank"&gt;Hello again old friend. It feels so familiar, I know all it’s scrapes and dents, even after a decade apart.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;A post shared by Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow) on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-08-18T16:57:33+00:00"&gt;Aug 18, 2017 at 9:57am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Okay so first of all it was &lt;em&gt;wild&lt;/em&gt; how quickly things came back to me. I picked it up, wet the reed, and &lt;strong&gt;bam&lt;/strong&gt; I was playing the Concert B-flat blues scale. I had to buy a weaker reed (my &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embouchure"&gt;embouchure&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t what it used to be) and I definitely need some practice, but it all came back to me pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to record a cover of a great song from The Weakerthans; the song has two trumpets but I managed to recording a duet with myself near the end of the song. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing complicated, a fun experiment with recording over myself on different instruments. I really like how it all turned out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/338298000&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what&amp;rsquo;s next – I have another week of vacation, I&amp;rsquo;m learning new songs, practicing the sax, and even picked up a old, used clarinet. I plan to keep recording covers of my favourite songs (sometimes &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/ash-furrow/a-cold-night-close-to-the-end"&gt;with assistance&lt;/a&gt;), develop my skills on vocals and reed-based woodwinds, and (primarily still) the guitar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got an itch to play with other musicians, but I&amp;rsquo;m also feeling pretty introverted and shy lately, so who knows. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m having a tonne of fun. And it all &lt;a href="/blog/learning-guitar/"&gt;started with a ukulele&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 17:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/music-is-back/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Therapy's End</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/therapys-end/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had my final regularly scheduled therapy appointment. My therapist and I have been meeting less frequently over the summer, and we&amp;rsquo;ve talked before about the idea of stopping altogether. We ended today&amp;rsquo;s session early. He shook my hand and reminded me that the door was always open; I thanked him for his help, and I left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be back someday, or maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll talk with someone else. But I&amp;rsquo;ve worked through my feelings, and I&amp;rsquo;ve found the right medication, that I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;no longer experiencing a depressive episode&amp;rdquo; I think is the medical phrase. I&amp;rsquo;m doing hobbies, I&amp;rsquo;m less anxious about things, I&amp;rsquo;m just&amp;hellip; enjoying life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of then many tools therapy helped me with was recognizing when to ask for help so rest assured I&amp;rsquo;ll be on the lookout for any future problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therapy was a life-changing experience for me – I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to have access to mental health treatment. Well, kind of – you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe how difficult it is to live abroad with mental health issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with your emotions, ask yourself how that struggle is affecting your life. Talking to someone could really help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 20:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/therapys-end/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guitar Debut</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/guitar-debut/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday evening was &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/artsysalon/"&gt;Artsy&amp;rsquo;s third annual Salon&lt;/a&gt;, where everyone at Artsy is invited to show off the art that they create. Not everyone participates, and that&amp;rsquo;s okay, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to celebrate all my colleagues&amp;rsquo; creative outlets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I display some photographs, but this year I tried something different. The theme of the Salon was growth, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href="/blog/learning-guitar/"&gt;learning the guitar since December&lt;/a&gt;, so last night was my big debut!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should say, I guess, that I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning guitar &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; to sing. The singing was what I was most nervous about actually – I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why. I&amp;rsquo;ve performed piano and saxophone in front of much larger crowds, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t sang publicly since elementary school. My colleagues&amp;rsquo; opinions of me mean a lot, and I guess I was afraid of embarrassing myself. Or maybe I still hate my own voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I performed two songs – covers – one by The Weakerthans and another by their lead, John K Samson. A great Canadian group and artist. The first song was &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/5bil0D8WSuxyGSDLA4LxZK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Virtute the Cat Explains Her Departure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and the second was &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/1RwhqapZ0XuqDDeSY4Tzbu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heart of the Continent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/6-OFLKdUU0w' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I could feel my knees shaking, I was sure everyone could see how nervous I was. But I had rehearsed and felt my body follow muscle memory as my brain slipped into that blissful autopilot. It reminded me of speaking at a conference – something I&amp;rsquo;m pretty comfortable with at this point. But still nerve-wracking. I made a few mistakes, but I kept going. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a senior in high school, I performed in the talent show. Well, I started too. About eight bars into &amp;ldquo;American Pie&amp;rdquo; on the piano, I forgot the music. My mind blanked. I panicked and ran off stage. I was afraid I would panic again and forget the music. But even if I did, I felt safe around my colleagues. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/582iYsdMHjA' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second song went well too, though my legs were still shaking. I rushed the tempo. I always do. In retrospect, I was afraid of the mic; I need to rehearse more with one. That&amp;rsquo;s okay – those are all improvements I can make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is I had fun, and that I did it. It was hard and I did it anyway (not always easy with depression). Je pense que quelqu&amp;#39;un se mit a rire au française dans the chanson. Bienvenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time it&amp;rsquo;ll be a little easier, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be a little better. Actually, I recorded &lt;em&gt;Heart of the Continent&lt;/em&gt; a month ago, and re-listening to that recording this morning, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised by just how much I&amp;rsquo;ve improved since then.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/331082254&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  



&lt;p&gt;Thank you to my colleagues and friends for showing up for my debut, and thank you to my wife Ashley for taking some recordings. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have some artefact of my ability – a snapshot of what I could do. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 16:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/guitar-debut/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
