<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Ash Furrow</title>
    <description>Learning and teaching about interesting topics in iOS Development. Sometimes I diverge to talk about design, photography, or what-have-you.</description>
    <link>https://ashfurrow.com/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Building Compassionate Software</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/building-compassionate-software/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you make a mistake, you would want a colleague to point it out to you, right? Just like you would hope a colleague would ask a question when they don&amp;rsquo;t understand something, and just like you want everyone on your team to speak up with ideas, even if they&amp;rsquo;re unconventional. But chances are that you&amp;rsquo;ve been in the position to speak up before and haven&amp;rsquo;t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? It feels like those scenarios represent a good team dynamic, but what effect do they have on a team&amp;rsquo;s performance? And how can we begin to change a team&amp;rsquo;s dynamic to improve its performance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to take a look at &lt;em&gt;psychological safety&lt;/em&gt; and how it can help your team perform better. My goal is to give you the evidence you need to take back to your team so we can all improve our workplaces – with enough of us, we can begin to make significant change in our industry and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to take us through three main points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feelings Matter.&lt;/strong&gt; Before we talk about feelings, we should discuss why exactly they matter. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of evidence here that I&amp;rsquo;m excited to talk about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teams with Psychological Safety Perform Better.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m going to describe what psychological safety means and what it looks like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Implement Psychological Safety on Your Team.&lt;/strong&gt; After we have a firm grasp on feelings and psychological safety, I want to discuss some ways to start improving your team&amp;rsquo;s performance and dynamics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this topic on my mind for a long time, and I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to get started. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="feelings-matter"&gt;Feelings Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/empathetic-civilization/"&gt;written about this before&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ll say it again: &lt;em&gt;feelings matter&lt;/em&gt;. It might sound obvious to you – it might not – so it really does need to be repeated: feelings matter. Compassionate software can&amp;rsquo;t be built without compassion for each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feelings matter, a lot. &lt;a href="http://qz.com/622749/teens-do-better-in-science-when-they-know-einstein-and-curie-also-struggled/"&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve actually researched this&lt;/a&gt;: students who learned about the struggles that scientists went through on their way to achieving success did a lot better in science class. And students who &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; learn started doing &lt;em&gt;worse&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning how successful scientists struggle helped students when they inevitably struggled. That&amp;rsquo;s because struggling is normal, but when we neglect to mention the struggles of history&amp;rsquo;s great scientists, we present the incorrect view that they just &lt;em&gt;were great&lt;/em&gt;. And that&amp;rsquo;s not true, &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/normalizing-struggle/"&gt;everyone struggles&lt;/a&gt; sometimes. Students no longer felt like outsiders when &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; started to struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When students see themselves and their own struggles represented in the history of science, they learn to &lt;em&gt;empathize&lt;/em&gt; with scientists. Empathy, the core of emotions, is the practice of sharing another person&amp;rsquo;s point of view and feelings.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/1Evwgu369Jw' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Empathy is a choice we make. In 1996, &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1365-2648.1996.12213.x/full"&gt;Theresa Wiseman&amp;rsquo;s work&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Theresa_Wiseman/publication/227941757_A_concept_analysis_of_empathy/links/00b4951e409deac34f000000.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;) categorized four necessary components to empathy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing the world as others see it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognizing and understanding another&amp;rsquo;s feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staying non-judgemental.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicating that you understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are things we can do, things we can &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how someone empathizes, which is core to feelings, which matter. Feelings are important. Now I want to explore what it means to be a member of a team where feelings are prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="teams-with-psychological-safety-perform-better"&gt;Teams with Psychological Safety Perform Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you want to be a 10x developer, eh? You may have heard that the 10x developer is a myth, but that&amp;rsquo;s not true: a 10x developer is someone who makes the ten developers around them each twice as productive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;How to be a 10x engineer: help ten other engineers be twice as good.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Peter Seibel (@peterseibel) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/peterseibel/status/512615519934230528"&gt;September 18, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can be a 10x developer by making sure that your team has psychological safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychological safety is defined as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The belief that one will not be punished or humiliated for speaking up with ideas, questions, concerns, or mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this sounds touchy-feely, but there is data to back this up! Google spent &lt;em&gt;five years&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/28/magazine/what-google-learned-from-its-quest-to-build-the-perfect-team.html?_r=0"&gt;Project Aristotle&lt;/a&gt; searching for the answer to &lt;em&gt;what makes some teams perform really well and other teams perform poorly?&lt;/em&gt; They examined &lt;em&gt;a tonne&lt;/em&gt; of data and eventually – after extensive searching – they found psychological safety is correlated positively with team success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were other behaviors that seemed important as well — like making sure teams had clear goals and creating a culture of dependability. But Google’s data indicated that psychological safety, more than anything else, was critical to making a team work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt;. They A/B test shades of blue to use on the Gmail &amp;ldquo;Send&amp;rdquo; button. They are &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; data-driven organization, and their research came to the conclusion that teams with psychological safety were more successful than teams without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, psychological safety is the belief that you won&amp;rsquo;t be punished for saying something. That&amp;rsquo;s fairly basic, but think about it: I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ve worked in groups where this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case. Was that project a success, or a failure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-4by3'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/LhoLuui9gX8' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers – &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; – need to be able to ask questions when they don&amp;rsquo;t understand something. We need to feel free to suggest ideas or concerns, to be able to point out and admit mistakes. This is really necessary for development teams, and &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; necessary in resource-strained startups where missteps could cost the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was this one time at Artsy where I was behind schedule on a big feature, which was delaying me from starting work on &lt;a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/"&gt;something really important&lt;/a&gt;. I sat down with my team, and we had &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; started reviewing the designs for all the stuff I had to finish when a designer asked &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;hellip; we just&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t do any of it?&amp;rdquo; We hadn&amp;rsquo;t really considered whether the feature I was behind on was worth delaying the next project for. A designer from outside our team was comfortable challenging our assumptions. They were right, we dropped the delayed feature and moved directly on to what was more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the designer felt comfortable asking questions, we came to a new conclusion we hadn&amp;rsquo;t considered on our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychological safety is &lt;a href="http://qz.com/625870/after-years-of-intensive-analysis-google-discovers-the-key-to-good-teamwork-is-being-nice/"&gt;observable in teams&lt;/a&gt; in two ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversational turn-taking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average emotional sensitivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversational turn-taking is a measure of how often people in a conversation switch from talking to listening. One member of a team who dominates the conversation is risking the psychological safety of the entire team. Everyone needs to feel safe having their say, and to revisit a conversation later if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average emotional sensitivity is a bit trickier. Emotional sensitivity is basically a measure of how empathetic some is to another&amp;rsquo;s feelings. For example, how often does one colleague notice another colleague is having a difficult time? And when they notice, do they try to understand? Do they stay non-judgemental? And do they communicate that understanding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychological safety really ought to be expected at your workplace. At any workplace, really, for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes team members feel safer: everyone is welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes business sense: teams with high levels of psychological safety consistently perform better than those without.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt; at your workplace should expect these things: from contributors and leadership, C-levels and the company board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay. So feelings matter, and psychological safety is why high-performing teams do so well. But how would one go about improving their team&amp;rsquo;s dynamic? Where do we start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-implement-psychological-safety-on-your-team"&gt;How to Implement Psychological Safety on Your Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychological safety is awesome! How do we &amp;ldquo;do psychological safety&amp;rdquo; though? That&amp;rsquo;s an interesting question. First we need to talk about the two scenarios you&amp;rsquo;re likely to find yourself in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a team leader, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot you can do to improve your team&amp;rsquo;s dynamic and – as a consequence – your team&amp;rsquo;s performance. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at those steps after we discuss how individual contributors can help their teams, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a team member, then you can still help improve the levels of psychological safety in your team using the same techniques as a team lead. However, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to have the biggest impact if you approach your team lead directly, present the evidence we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed, and work on the team dynamic together. This is really their job, they just might not know it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaders and contributors can do three main things to help improve psychological safety on their team:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admit fallibility&lt;/strong&gt; and normalize struggle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frame all work as &lt;strong&gt;learning experiences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model curiosity&lt;/strong&gt; by creating a space where opinions are asked for and voices don&amp;rsquo;t need to ask permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, remember that everyone struggles and everyone makes mistakes. If you, as a team lead, make this the norm, then that sends a message to team members that it&amp;rsquo;s okay to make mistakes. Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty straightforward: you want your team to feel safe when things go wrong, so make sure to act normal when you make a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, all work your team performs should be primarily modelled as exercises in learning. Because that&amp;rsquo;s what they are; when a team build something, you&amp;rsquo;re all really just &lt;em&gt;learning how to build something&lt;/em&gt; as a team. The byproduct of this is the thing that happened to built. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product a team builds is important to the business&amp;rsquo; success, so it may seem counterintuitive to place a higher priority on the learning experience of a team than on building the product itself. But remember: by doing this, you&amp;rsquo;re helping to increase the performance of your team so – in turn – they&amp;rsquo;re able to build a better product, faster and with fewer bugs. The evidence shows it makes business sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you need to model curiosity. Ask questions, even silly ones. Ask questions you think you already know the answer to. Help model an environment where learning through curiosity is praised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This advice is really built upon empathy, which means there are a few other common sense tidbits that accompany it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch out for people getting interrupted in meetings. When you see it, say &amp;ldquo;hang on, I want to hear the rest of what they have to say.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t pressure people into providing immediate feedback. Instead of asking on the spot, give time for reflective feedback. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll type up what we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed and send it to everyone, let me know what isn&amp;rsquo;t clear.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow space for your team to revisit discussions if someone feels their voice wasn&amp;rsquo;t heard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can practice empathy, we can set a Google Calendar reminder to reflect on recent meetings, we can focus on the feelings of our peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychological safety can be a differentiator at your workplace. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to retain good developers, and it&amp;rsquo;s harder to find them in the first place. Working in a safe environment, where everyone feels like they can ask questions and where everyone is able to do their best work, well that sounds awesome, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? Implement these suggestions so that your workplace stands out to prospective developers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be a workplace differentiator, likely more attractive than free snacks or a foosball table to prospective colleagues. Show your potential hires how you structure meetings, give them examples where you made a mistake but learned something, tell them a story about how someone asked a question and it had a big impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve covered a lot today, from some initial questions to empathy, and from definition of &amp;lsquo;psychological safety&amp;rsquo; to steps on improving it in your team. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot to take in, why not set a reminder somewhere to wait a week, think things over, and revisit this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have the evidence that shows how an ideal team works, but we see our industry falling short of that ideal. But! We have the tools to improve ourselves, our teams, and our industry. I really hope that teams operating in psychological safety become the norm, something to expect at any job. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a long way to go before we reach that point, but I know we can do it if we work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I&amp;rsquo;ve had this topic on my mind for a long time, though I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the vocabulary to discuss it or the evidence to support my theories. A few months ago, I attended the &lt;a href="http://www.osfeels.com"&gt;Open Source &amp;amp; Feelings&lt;/a&gt; conference, and the talks there really helped frame a lot of my thoughts. I found the following talk particularly helpful, and led me to a lot of the points I discussed today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/OdHH5KWGTNo' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m presenting on this topic at a &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/iOSoho/events/226405664/"&gt;meetup here in New York&lt;/a&gt; in October. I&amp;rsquo;d love to see you there, hear what you think, and talk about how we can all help improve the industry together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/building-compassionate-software/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smartphones and Augmenting Humanity</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/smartphones-and-augmenting-humanity/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, shortly after Pokemon Go launched, I saw a pretty messed up image get circulated &amp;lsquo;round the internet, with comments to the effect of &amp;ldquo;haha, this is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; edgy!&amp;rdquo; But it made me pretty angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pawelkuczynski.com"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/smartphones-and-augmenting-humanity/pikachu.jpg" alt="Bad satire" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ohhhhhhh my goshhhhhh&lt;/em&gt; the pretension practically oozes off my screen. Pokemon Go became popular and despite benefits like spending more time outside, the game&amp;rsquo;s popularity demanded snarky responses. Thinkpieces had to be written! Snarky comics had to be published! Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wumo.com/wumo/2016/08/11"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/smartphones-and-augmenting-humanity/cliff.png" alt="Worse satire" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so tired of this. Pokemon Go entertains people, gets them outside, helps them make new friends, all kinds of awesome things. But it&amp;rsquo;s an app, which is technology, and technology is bad, right? So we get this faux intellectual backlash coming from people who you&amp;rsquo;d think would know better: so called &amp;ldquo;satirists.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason this has me so frustrated is something I read back in January:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not actually edgy to call folk with smart phones drones, it IS actually edgy to admit that some ppl need them to communicate w world&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sook Moon (@doloresonthedot) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/doloresonthedot/status/701369715621502980"&gt;February 21, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The internet – and technology in general – is at its best when it helps people lead fulfilling lives. By many measures, smartphones do that. All the thinkpieces criticizing people for using smartphones, all the comics mocking people for using apps, they&amp;rsquo;re all intellectually lazy, designed to satisfy one group of people by othering another. And we all act like it&amp;rsquo;s normal to mock people for relying on technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone acts like it&amp;rsquo;s acceptable to hate on people who rely on the internet, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. This is just a thing that society does in order to shame people who find communicating online easier than in person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s got to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smartphones augment human intelligence, the internet enables new kinds of friendships, and technology provides new avenues of creativity. Computers are &lt;a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2011/12/21/steve-jobs-bicycle-for-the-mind-1990/"&gt;bicycles for our minds&lt;/a&gt; and we take them for granted. As a society, we&amp;rsquo;ve accepted the idea that relying on technology is a form of weakness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No more edgy comics. No more faux-provocative thinkpieces. They&amp;rsquo;re all wrong. If we fail to challenge their message, then we are complicit in the harm they do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 20:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/smartphones-and-augmenting-humanity/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photography Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/photography-retrospective/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February of 2012, I wrote that &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/effort-to-improved-skill-ratio-and-expertise/"&gt;I would not be buying a camera&lt;/a&gt;. Two months later, &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-i-bought-a-camera/"&gt;I did buy one&lt;/a&gt;, and that decision has come to shape a lot of who I am today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how four years seems like a long time, but also feels really short, too. Photography exploded into my life, taking up all my spare time, attention, and money. I knew it would when I started. After all, I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved gadgets and gizmos, and photography is rife with things to fiddle with and obsess over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept buying nicer and nicer lenses, and nicer and nicer cameras, until I had &amp;ldquo;the setup&amp;rdquo;, what I thought would signal to other photographers (and myself) that I was serious about photography. It was never enough. I had a problem. I felt addicted to buying gear. I would feel crummy and think that buying such-and-such new photography thing would make me feel better, and it did, but that elation would quickly subside when I realized that I &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have bought that&lt;/em&gt;. So that would make me feel crummy too and the cycle would repeat. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying photography gear was an unhealthy coping mechanism that I used to deal with my &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/depression/"&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, but eventually I did manage to stop before I did unrepairable damage to my marriage and finances. When I moved to New York, I got the help I needed, and that&amp;rsquo;s made recovery from &amp;ldquo;gear acquisition syndrome&amp;rdquo; possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the dark side of my photography. But there&amp;rsquo;s a good side, too: photography is a huge, positive part of my life – in both lofty and day-to-day senses. Let me explain both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted &lt;em&gt;so much&lt;/em&gt; to feel like a &amp;ldquo;real photographer&amp;rdquo;, and I bought gear that I thought would help. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t smart, but it did lead to making making a lot of photos, and that &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; help me feel like a photographer. More than that, I eventually stopped caring about how I appear to others as a photographer; photography has become something I do &lt;em&gt;for me&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying gear didn&amp;rsquo;t help, but actually using the gear I had &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt;. And eventually, I learnt that it didn&amp;rsquo;t really matter anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, a camera accompanies me everywhere I go. Every time I leave my apartment, I have my camera in my bag, and the camera is already in my hand by the time my feet hit the sidewalk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Walk to work: 30 minutes of Spotify. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Walk to work, carrying a camera: 45 minutes of “wow, everything is amazing!” … and Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/695643794922934272"&gt;February 5, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Photography taught me to &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/developers-should-learn-photography/"&gt;learn from my mistakes&lt;/a&gt;; if a photo didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way I wanted, I figured out why. Once I found out what went wrong, I tried not to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the choices I&amp;rsquo;ve made haven&amp;rsquo;t turned out for the best, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer has actually been the first time in my life that I haven&amp;rsquo;t lived paycheque-to-paycheque. It sucks that it took until my late twenties to get my shit together, but I want to concentrate on the fact that &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m actually getting my shit together&lt;/em&gt;. And honestly, photography only exacerbated an obsession with buying things. But, it did help in unique ways that I think only art could have. It taught me lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to other parts of my life, and it now helps take my mind off things when I do feel down. It&amp;rsquo;s become a healthy coping mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could go back and explain all this to myself in 2012, when I was buying my first camera, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure my younger self would understand. It&amp;rsquo;s like &lt;a href="https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2009/01/12/abstraction-intuition-and-the-monad-tutorial-fallacy/"&gt;monads&lt;/a&gt;, you can&amp;rsquo;t explain how they work because that comprehension can only come from struggling with them. You can&amp;rsquo;t take a shortcut. With buying photography gear, I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand how I was hurting myself until I had struggled for a while. Maybe the struggle was necessary. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m glad it&amp;rsquo;s ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s my retrospective on photography, at least so far: a hobby-turned-obsession that cost a lot of money and caused a lot of stress, but also a hobby that became a healthy coping mechanism with a lot of fun. Like most everything, photography hasn&amp;rsquo;t been &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo;, but a bit of both. I can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/photography-retrospective/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh macOS Setup</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/fresh-macos-setup/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of things I do when I re-install macOS on a computer, or when I begin working on a new computer. I don&amp;rsquo;t do this often, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget the steps. So I &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/ashfurrow/3865eed417a5fbe8402708e2c706eea6"&gt;documented everything in a gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to keep these steps in Notes.app but figured they should be public anyway (open source by default, right?) so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/ashfurrow/3865eed417a5fbe8402708e2c706eea6.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve added recently, that&amp;rsquo;s super-important to me, is to untrust a certain certificate. Blue Coat is a company that creates &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Coat_Systems#Controversy"&gt;internet surveillance and censorship software&lt;/a&gt; and Semantic gave them an intermediate CA certificate. That means they can sign arbitrary certificates that you&amp;rsquo;re computer will trust (because your computer trusts Semantic, and Semantic trusts Blue Coat). &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;BlueCoat now has a CA signed by Symantec &lt;a href="https://t.co/8OXmtpT6eX"&gt;https://t.co/8OXmtpT6eX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to untrust it &lt;a href="https://t.co/NDlbqKqqld"&gt;https://t.co/NDlbqKqqld&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/mBD68nrVsD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/mBD68nrVsD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Filippo Valsorda (@FiloSottile) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FiloSottile/status/735940720931012608"&gt;May 26, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really into the idea of my computer trusting a company like Blue Coat, so I &lt;a href="https://blog.filippo.io/untrusting-an-intermediate-ca-on-os-x/"&gt;follow the instructions&lt;/a&gt; to untrust this certificate. I highly recommend you do, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I recommend you document everything you do to make your computer awesome! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 14:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/fresh-macos-setup/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Search with Middleman and lunrjs</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/static-site-search-with-middleman-and-lunrjs/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/issues/213"&gt;someone opened an issue&lt;/a&gt; asking for a site search on my blog. Neat idea, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t high on my list of priorities at the time, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;d get to it someday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, today&amp;rsquo;s the day 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: The original &amp;ldquo;the day&amp;rdquo; was two weeks ago but I had given up in frustration.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search is an interesting problem. Most search engines run on servers and not the browser client. This site, just like all static sites like those built with &lt;a href="https://middlemanapp.com"&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt;, is generated on a computer before being served statically. It&amp;rsquo;s a faster, easier, and more secure way of serving web pages that don&amp;rsquo;t need dynamism, but it does mean that you can&amp;rsquo;t run server code when a page is fetched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running search on servers makes sense for DuckDuckGo and Google because their search engines are trying to cover the whole internet. But for a site like mine, a client-side search engine written in Javascript can be a suitable solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lucene.apache.org/solr/"&gt;Solr&lt;/a&gt; is an open source search engine. &lt;a href="http://lunrjs.com"&gt;lunrjs&lt;/a&gt; is a Javascript-based search engine, which claims to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit like Solr, but much smaller and not as bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lovely. I think the sun-vs-moon metaphor for server-vs-client search engines is really apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few Middleman extensions that integrate lunrjs search into static sites, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get any to work for me because I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand how they worked. I ended up &lt;a href="https://github.com/256dpi/middleman-lunr/blob/5c49621007e003da0b748ec8bd34bfc7b11240d2/lib/middleman-lunr/indexer.rb#L23-L64"&gt;reading the source code&lt;/a&gt; of one to understand &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how it worked. Even then, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get things right. It turns out that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know enough Javascript to use a Javascript-based search engine. Not yet anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I submitted a &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/232"&gt;work-in-progress pull request&lt;/a&gt; and gave up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little break and some food, I went back and looked into a different extension. Actually it was the original extension I tried but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it working. I understood what it was doing on the Ruby side, and concentrated just on the Javascript. After looking up some jQuery syntax, I had something that worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some fiddling with CSS and lining things up, &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/233"&gt;I had a ready PR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/search"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/static-site-search-with-middleman-and-lunrjs/screenshot.jpg" alt="Screenshot of site search" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Site search stumped me for weeks. Distinct from search engines in general, server-side static site search is a very interesting problem in its own right. Ruby code uses Javascript to generate a search engine index of the content of my entire site. Then client-side Javascript downloads that index and uses lunrjs to run queries against it. It crosses the dynamic-to-static barrier, which isn&amp;rsquo;t something many other features of static sites need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After submitting the pull request, I realized I had been working into the late evening, that I&amp;rsquo;d had a beer or two, and that maybe pushing code to production wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best thing to do. I pinged Orta on the pull request and asked for a second opinion. It can never hurt to have someone double-check things for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things checked out, and &lt;a href="/search"&gt;search is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/233"&gt;The pull request is here&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to comment on anything that you&amp;rsquo;d like clarification on or that you have a suggestion about. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are ways this could be more idiomatically done. (&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/237"&gt;added documentation&lt;/a&gt; to all the code and linked to the relevant code &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog"&gt;in the readme&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing new features into software can be overwhelming, and stepping back for a break is usually the right answer. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to give up if things are getting frustrating, and it&amp;rsquo;s okay to ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;PARTY TIP: At the end of the day, just try your hardest to be nice.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ANDREW W.K. (@AndrewWK) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AndrewWK/status/722843678994219009"&gt;April 20, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all in this together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 15:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/static-site-search-with-middleman-and-lunrjs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asking for Help in Open Source</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/asking-for-help-in-open-source/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Note: this post isn&amp;rsquo;t addressed to or aimed at anyone in particular, it&amp;rsquo;s just general advice. I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="/blog/how-to-ask-for-developer-help"&gt;written about this before&lt;/a&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s time for a refresher.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m going to start by addressing the elephant in the open source room: licensing. I could quote any open source license here and point out that it says &amp;ldquo;software provided without warranty&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;software provided as-is&amp;rdquo; or whatever else that really means &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t owe you tech support.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not going to do that, because I don&amp;rsquo;t believe it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I write open source and publish it, and then you use it, I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;legally&lt;/em&gt; owe you anything, but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; owe you something. Maintainers get to benefit from developers using our code, because they&amp;rsquo;ll find bugs and recommend feature requests and we get to benefit from all that too. Maintainers benefit when our code gets used, and I think there&amp;rsquo;s a reciprocal nature to that relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of that relationship, maintainers are responsible for acknowledging bug reports and giving advice to solve problems. We don&amp;rsquo;t owe anyone technical support or bug fixes, but if we spend a few minutes to point you in the right direction for a fix, we can benefit too. We&amp;rsquo;ll ask you to submit a pull request adding a feature or fixing a bug or clarifying some documentation. That&amp;rsquo;s the sort of social contract that exists in open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is a &lt;em&gt;reciprocal&lt;/em&gt; relationship, which means you owe us too. You should be kind, provide steps to reproduce a bug, details about a feature you&amp;rsquo;ve requested, that kind of stuff. One more thing you owe us is to respect the project&amp;rsquo;s communication norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you find a bug, open an issue. If you have a feature request, open an issue. If you have a question, open an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t tweet or email contributors with this stuff. Open an issue, if they don&amp;rsquo;t answer within a reasonable amount of time, maybe send them a link to the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t just to keep my inbox manageable, you should do this for your own sake: chances are there are other people watching the issues that can help you faster than I can. Your issue will probably get answered faster than I can answer an email or tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source is big, it&amp;rsquo;s many-to-many, and when you email or tweet at me, that really limits how many people can benefit from my response. &lt;a href="https://realm.io/news/altconf-orta-therox-being-nice-in-open-source/"&gt;Being nice is nice&lt;/a&gt;, so be nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 15:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/asking-for-help-in-open-source/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
