<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Ash Furrow</title>
    <description>Learning and teaching about interesting topics in iOS Development. Sometimes I diverge to talk about design, photography, or what-have-you.</description>
    <link>https://ashfurrow.com/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Gridcoin</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/gridcoin/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve known about bitcoin since 2012 when a friend described a kind of digital currency that he purchased by meeting a guy at a subway station and exchanging an envelope of cash for an envelope of a hard drive. The whole concept felt as something not very above-board. So I decided not to learn more about it and just generally ignored it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years passed when I would catch the occasional headline describing the currency&amp;rsquo;s latest record-setting price, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay it much attention until I moved in New York. Bitcoin would come up in conversation at Artsy; people were discussing new art projects and new technologies and new startups centred around blockchains. And so, cryptocurrency reasserted itself within my bubble and I took a closer look. That was about 18 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading articles and watching videos – and listening to a great lunchtime presentation from a colleague – I now have a solid grasp on the technical underpinnings of the different technologies involved in bitcoin. I have a less solid understanding of some of the practical nuances, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got the technical stuff down. Cryptography, mining, P2P networks for blockchains, that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m reading headlines about new record-setting bitcoin prices with the perspective of the technological underpinnings. And I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed. I mean, the technology is &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;m not excited about the idea of a bunch of powerful nerds getting rich. Amazing tech, but not something I want to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then a few months ago, I noticed an uptick in media coverage about bitcoin. Articles like &lt;a href="https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/ywbbpm/bitcoin-mining-electricity-consumption-ethereum-energy-climate-change"&gt;this one exploring bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s carbon footprint&lt;/a&gt; were being discussed at the office. Bitcoin was being increasingly reported on by people who understood it, leading to more critical coverage and more reporting targeted at a non-engineering audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good! But I still kind of dismissed it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have anything to do with it, and I still don&amp;rsquo;t. Sadly, I may have thrown the proverbial baby out with the bathwater; the blockchain technology that bitcoin is built upon is &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; interesting. I learnt more about etherium and the distributed-computing infrastructure it&amp;rsquo;s built upon and – yeah I regretted not buying bitcoin when it was under $10 – I threw $150 into etherium. I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; etherium and I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m now involved with cryptocurrencies, yet here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things changed a few weeks ago when, during follow-up on their episode about citizen science, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/izqaWyZsEtY?t=784"&gt;PBS Spacetime mentions a cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; that:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; gridcoin, which you mine by devoting computing cycles to BOINC research programs. Seems a bit more useful than bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s useless cryptographic calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gridcoin.us"&gt;Gridcoin&lt;/a&gt;, eh? &lt;a href="https://boinc.berkeley.edu"&gt;BOINC&lt;/a&gt;, huh? Let&amp;rsquo;s check this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did, and through capitalizing on my newly rediscovered interesting in tinkering on things, I revived my Raspberry Pi and set off. Over the course of the past two weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about gridcoin and playing with the related technologies. And while I have a good theoretical understanding of cryptocurrency technologies, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the experience of working with cryptocurrencies in practice. The past few weeks have therefore been a lot of learning new ideas and refining new skills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/pi.png" alt="BOINC on a Raspberry Pi" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s back up and define gridcoin. Other cryptocurrencies, like bitcoin, are mined by computers that compete to solve cryptographic hash functions. That computing power is wasted, in a very real sense: solving those hashes isn&amp;rsquo;t useful &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; to mining more bitcoins. On the other hand, gridcoin is a cryptocurrency mined using calculations that contribute towards scientific research. In fact, gridcoin is really just a layer on top of BOINC, which predates bitcoin and blockchains altogether. This was something I could be interested in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BOINC is a project run out of Berkley; it administers work to a network of distributed computers owned by ordinary people, who volunteer their spare computing resources to BOINC. This is really important because many projects in science require a lot of computing power. Furthermore, many of these projects lend themselves to being solved using BOINC&amp;rsquo;s distributed batch-processing architecture. You may be familiar with its most famous project &lt;a href="http://setiathome.berkeley.edu"&gt;SETI@Home&lt;/a&gt;, the search for extraterrestrial life, but there are others. My favourites include &lt;a href="https://sech.me/boinc/Amicable/"&gt;Amicable Numbers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://milkyway.cs.rpi.edu/milkyway/"&gt;Milkyway@Home&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://asteroidsathome.net"&gt;Asteroids@Home&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So gridcoin basically piggy-backs off of the existing credit and team systems built into BOINC. A blockchain is used to keep track of transactions, like other cryptocurrencies, but new coins are staked based off your contributions to BOINC projects. I&amp;rsquo;m still learning the nuances of the somewhat confusing math, but the general idea is that the more you contribute towards a project&amp;rsquo;s work units (relative to how much others have contributed, and some other factors), the more gridcoins you stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Despite a very active community, I found the documentation to be difficult to follow and sometimes out of date. The guides and wikis I found mostly assumed you already knew what you were doing. Maybe when I have a better grasp of it all, I&amp;rsquo;ll return to update the docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve installed the BOINC client on my laptop and my pi, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around on EC2 to spin up cloud servers to crunch numbers for SETI. It&amp;rsquo;s been fun, to tinker. I eventually settled on just using my laptop because even a c4.xlarge instance (4 virtual CPUs, $0.20/hour) performs worse than my laptop in terms of BOINC stats. I looked into GPU-specific instances, but cloud-based GPU access is still new and in high-demand, so it was too expensive for me (you can add a GPU to an EC2 instance for $0.50/hour, or rent a GPU-optimized instance starting from $0.90/hour). So yeah, not my thing! That&amp;rsquo;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One stumbling block I&amp;rsquo;ve faced when starting has been that (for reasons that are still beyond me) you need to &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; gridcoins to stake them. Seems kinda scam-y, but there&amp;rsquo;s a small transaction fee to basically announce yourself on the blockchain. Okay, fine, but also: when and how often you stake gridcoins (get credit for your BOINC work) is determined in part by how many gridcoins you already have. So starting out is tricky, feels weird, and involves a lot of waiting. With a balance of 3 gridcoins (which I acquired by signing up for a newsletter, lol), my estimated time-to-stake was an estimated three thousands days.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/wallet.png" alt="Gridcoin wallet" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mmm. Mmhmmm. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To build up an initial balance, I tried using a &lt;a href="https://grcpool.com"&gt;gridcoin pool&lt;/a&gt; on an EC2 instance for a few days but wasn&amp;rsquo;t really impressed. Using a pool is like solo mining except you don&amp;rsquo;t need the upfront investment (and you don&amp;rsquo;t get to keep all your earnings). Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m impatient – the calculations take longevity of contribution into account, and I only ran this server for like two days.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/ec2.png" alt="BOINC on EC2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(Lest my command-line hacker skills be called into question, yes I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; install a desktop environment on EC2 but I didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to, it was just easier.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of paying per-second for anything. It reminded me I&amp;rsquo;m literally playing with money, and something about my upbringing makes that uncomfortable for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/pool.png" alt="EC2 gridcoin pool overview page" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I moved a bit of my etherium to my gridcoin wallet to prime the process. My time-to-stake estimate is now bouncing between 15–30 days. More reasonable I guess? I&amp;rsquo;ll learn to be patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways. Still don&amp;rsquo;t love that I&amp;rsquo;m doing this but it&amp;rsquo;s fun and I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying all the tinkering, so. Learning new things has been fun but (as usual) includes its share of frustrations too. And helping to map the galaxy just makes me feel warm and fuzzy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/gridcoin/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is Tom Scharpling?</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/who-is-tom-scharpling/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So a few weeks ago, I was listening to my new favourite Podcast &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/whatatimepod"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What a Time to Be Alive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the hosts mentioned a different show. This Tom Scharpling guy apparently has a show and they revered it a bit actually. The name sounded kinda familiar and I made a note to check him out later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well so this Tom fella is listed in the Apple Podcasts as running &lt;a href="http://thebestshow.net"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best Show&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so I checked it out. About&amp;hellip; thirty seconds into the first episode I froze. My eyes dilated and defocused. I held my breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait a minute.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I double-checked on IMDb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Scharpling is the voice actor behind my favourite character on my &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/"&gt;favourite show&lt;/a&gt;: Greg Universe. I&amp;rsquo;ve already been listening to this guy and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it! And he was a writer and producer on &lt;em&gt;Monk&lt;/em&gt;, which played a big role in my formative years. (I&amp;rsquo;d never seen a protagonist depicted with a mental illness before.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so that&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool, right? Well I kept reading up on him and he&amp;rsquo;s been involved with a bunch of musicians that I like, over many years. Very cool! I kept digging. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Best_Show_with_Tom_Scharpling"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best Show&lt;/em&gt; has been running&lt;/a&gt; for well over a decade, with many people now attributing the rise of podcasting &lt;em&gt;in general&lt;/em&gt; to this show. Some describe him as the &amp;ldquo;Godfather Of Podcasting&amp;rdquo;, according to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Scharpling"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. Very cool! I&amp;rsquo;ve run a number of podcasts over the years and they&amp;rsquo;ve all be influential on my career. My first was just with &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/my-podcast-loves-me/"&gt;some friends and colleagues in 2011&lt;/a&gt;, but I later did an &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/springboard/"&gt;interview series&lt;/a&gt; with established developers who described their origin stories – because we all start from somewhere – and finally I did &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/notification-center/"&gt;another iOS news show&lt;/a&gt;. (All the shows are defunct and offline, sorry. Welllll, one of them &lt;a href="http://notificationcenter.ashfurrow.com"&gt;is archived&lt;/a&gt; but you should absolutely not listen to it.) The point is, I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gotten into podcasting if not for the zeitgeist around the medium in 2011, which Tom Scharpling helped create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this person, who I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know about really, has been influencing my life for well over a decade. My personal life, my career, my art. Wow. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know his name. Prettttty cool!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 19:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/who-is-tom-scharpling/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The S Word</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/the-s-word/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself drawn towards some ideas to improve the living conditions of folks around the world. These are ideas like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;single-payer healthcare, including prescriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lowering income and wealth inequality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fighting climate change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognizing and fighting against racism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a higher minimum wage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ideas have fairly mainstream support, but if I presented them as &amp;ldquo;socialist&amp;rdquo; ideas, many folks would instinctively reject them. In fact, they are &lt;a href="http://ndpsocialists.ca/socialist-caucus-resolutions-2018-federal-ndp-convention/"&gt;ideas from the Canadian New Democratic Party&amp;rsquo;s Socialist Caucus&lt;/a&gt;. But we can&amp;rsquo;t discuss these ideas in that context, though, because Socialism Is Bad, or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be discussing in this post. Feel free to not @ me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I mentioned my interest in socialism on twitter, I upset a few people. I was accused of spreading communist propaganda and of disrespecting people who had died under the Soviets. Those words hurt. I&amp;rsquo;m not a socialist, or Soviet communist, and I&amp;rsquo;m capable of thinking for myself. Reducing my ideas to mindless repetition of propaganda robs me of my agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I want to talk about this, because I&amp;rsquo;m really frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go through my thought process here. I&amp;rsquo;ve scrutinized the following points for a logical misstep but if you see one, please direct your feedback directly to your drafts folder. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;capitalism causes a lot of people a lot of harm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;critiquing capitalism and capitalists is helpful in diminishing that harm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;socialists have the most experience critiquing capitalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;listening to what socialists have to say about capitalism could be worthwhile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all I&amp;rsquo;m saying. But I know I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna get angry tweets about this blog post. People are just &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; against even the patina of socialism. And I kind of get why: the harsh rule of the Soviets is very much in living memory and folks are very cautious about entertaining any of their ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s, I guess, step back for a second? Why exactly can&amp;rsquo;t we discuss ideas that come from socialists? Is it because socialism is inherently/universally bad? Why do we think that? I mean, this is a cliché but: when people suffer under socialism, it is blamed on socialism; when people suffer under capitalism, it is blamed on the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s have a discussion around why that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There appears to be a refusal to acknowledge the role that capitalism plays in contemporary world events. Let&amp;rsquo;s take climate change for example. Capitalism is responsible for our current climate change disaster: &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/exxon-knew-about-climate-change-almost-40-years-ago/"&gt;oil companies knew about CO2 emissions and their effect in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and hid that knowledge in order to protect their profits. And capitalism still contributes to climate change in many ways – for example, by convincing people that buying an electric car is a way to fight the incipient collapse of our planet&amp;rsquo;s climate. (It&amp;rsquo;s not.) We can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;shop&lt;/em&gt; our way out of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalism created a problem and is now selling us a solution to that problem that won&amp;rsquo;t actually work, thus diverting resources away form solutions that could work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can disagree with my characterization here – that&amp;rsquo;s fine – I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to advance the specific argument that capitalism caused climate change. Instead, what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to point out is that I can&amp;rsquo;t really find criticisms like this – of capitalism – anywhere in the mainstream media narrative. Capitalism is never discussed in a critical way. Ever. Whether or not you believe capitalism caused climate change, you have to admit that it&amp;rsquo;s weird how we don&amp;rsquo;t ever talk about capitalism&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;role&lt;/em&gt; in climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like it&amp;rsquo;s the very ideology of capitalism that prevents us from discussing the roles that the ideology plays in our world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That really sucks, and let me tell you why. You probably don&amp;rsquo;t think the economy is perfect, right? I mean, no one does. So let&amp;rsquo;s discuss how to improve it! Cool, except we aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed to mention Marx or any of his ideas. Why? Because Stalin or something, I guess. We&amp;rsquo;re missing out on what could turn out to be valuable ideas!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/fSQgCy_iIcc' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maybe coming from Canada colours my view of socialism. Maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t recognize the same dangers in socialism that my peers in Europe do. Maybe socialism is far too dangerous to consider at all, in any quantity or any context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what I think: history is written by the victors, and capitalism was the victor of the twentieth century. Is it not likely that capitalist ideology – that we were all born into – has a strong negative slant against socialism? Which capitalism correctly sees as an existential threat? Maybe the taboo of discussing socialist ideas has less to do with the ideas and more to do with how those ideas threaten the interests of capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe! I&amp;rsquo;d love to discuss this with people, but I can&amp;rsquo;t because then they yell at me. So I&amp;rsquo;m stuck and unable to express my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, fuck it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the dangers of considering socialist ideas (even in the abstract) are overblown by capitalists trying to protect their own profits. I believe that there are enough resources on this Earth to provide every human with a meaningful and dignified existence, but this vision is incompatible with capitalism. I believe that the broad and abstract topic of &amp;ldquo;socialism&amp;rdquo; is worth scrutinizing for any ideas that could save our species from extinction. That&amp;rsquo;s what I believe, and if you&amp;rsquo;re mad about any of this, ask yourself why that is.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/344260297&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If this resonates with you, check out the above podcast from &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/citationsneededpodcast"&gt;Citations Needed&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a great show that dissects (among other things) capitalist ideology without preaching socialism. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re a staunch anti-socialist, check it out anyway, because the discussion they present is representative of the kinds of discussions we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; having, but that we really &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 19:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/the-s-word/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So Steven Universe, eh?</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a TV show called &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; that I highly recommend, to anyone. To everyone, actually. I&amp;rsquo;m rewatching it now and I&amp;rsquo;ve got some notes on what appeals to me in the show. Maybe it would appeal to you, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;If you’re looking for a distraction from the depressing hellscape of 2017, I can’t recommend Steven Universe enough. &lt;a href="https://t.co/pymOPd086g"&gt;pic.twitter.com/pymOPd086g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ash &amp;ldquo;Thanksgiving Belongs in October&amp;rdquo; Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/925891391737143296?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;ve never watched cartoons or did but didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy them, I encourage you to set that aside and give &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; a try anyways. It&amp;rsquo;s obviously a cartoon and it&amp;rsquo;s obviously aimed at kids, but the metaphors in the show make it inclusive to folks from all kinds of different backgrounds. Even adults. It&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;em&gt;kid&amp;rsquo;s show&lt;/em&gt; as much as it is a show that is accessible &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; is an adventure dramedy that tells stories around a cast of believable characters – with hopes and flaws – centred around the titular Steven&amp;rsquo;s coming-of-age story. The show also tells a long, drawn-out sci-fi about intergalactic beings that colonize planets to mine their raw materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are a few things that really stand out in the show. Here&amp;rsquo;s a tl;dr list, continue reading for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent pacing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large stories, told with restraint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistent and cohesive lore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phenomenal music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Believable characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spectacular Art.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A non-judgemental narrative style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go into detail!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pacing"&gt;Pacing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; is a masterclass in pacing. The story takes place on a kind of slightly-alternate Earth, and it spans back thousands of years to a war. Through telling stories relating to that war, the characters are developed over the course of 11-minute episodes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no filler episodes; each episode contributes to character development in some way, and usually ties in with the broader story. There are often 3–5 episode arcs that tie together, but each episode is a self-contained story. This is a nice balance between the episodic monster-of-the-week style and the Battlestar Galactica style where only a few episodes can be watched in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="lore"&gt;Lore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lore and world-building in &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; is remarkable in its consistency and cohesion with both the art and the plot. It builds upon itself, setting up a stable foundation upon which to grow the characters and tell their stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a taste, here&amp;rsquo;s a rough overview of the world (season one/two spoilers):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gems are aliens. They are a kind of magic/technology hybrid and exist as small gemstones embedded in their &amp;ldquo;physical forms&amp;rdquo; – humanoid bodies. These bodies are &amp;ldquo;holograms but with mass&amp;rdquo; and the show has fun with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gems don&amp;rsquo;t age and they don&amp;rsquo;t change. Gems are created and used for specific purposes and there is no escape from their rigid social hierarchy. And that brings us to the war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gem War was began on Earth as a rebellion against Homeworld. Earth was being destroyed to serve the purposes of the Diamonds until Rose Quartz stopped them. Countless gems and humans were destroyed, but the resistance successfully fought off Homeworld&amp;rsquo;s forces (for now). Only a few gems survived the last assault on Earth, and they have been living in isolation for thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mid-nineties, Rose met Greg (a human). They fell in love and, eventually, decided to have a child. This was unprecedented – gems don&amp;rsquo;t have children, they are grown artificially. Steven was born and the show focuses a lot on his struggle to exist in the space between two races. Not a human, not a gem. Just Steven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="music"&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show weaves music into its narrative in a real thoughtful way. Both background music as well as music featured in the show: Steven plays a ukulele, and his dad plays a guitar. The show&amp;rsquo;s music had an impact on me: this time last year, I picked up a ukulele and have rediscovered how much I enjoy music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice actors are cast specifically with their singing voices in mind, and Rebecca Sugar (the show&amp;rsquo;s creator) really emphasizes how important the music is by playing a lot of the songs herself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/usXTGY4anrQ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the soundtrack is &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/3fNVnjSRQ3oW4PUIKvrThu"&gt;available on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="characters"&gt;Characters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so the characters! The adolescent Steven lives with the gems leftover from the war, and is also raised by his father Greg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rose and Greg wanted to have a child, but Rose understood this would require a sacrifice. She would have to permanently give up her physical form to give birth. This serves as an analogue to dying during childbirth, except that Rose &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; that the beginning of Steven&amp;rsquo;s existence would mark the end of her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So fast forward: Steven is living with the gems and spends a lot of time with his father. The two groups don&amp;rsquo;t really get along. Some of the gems blame Greg for Rose being gone, and they struggle with complicated feelings towards their roles in Steven&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each gem has their own distinct origins. Greg has a backstory too. These are all explored in really interesting and thoughtful ways. Side-characters too! You will never see a character only once, they &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; reappear. Here&amp;rsquo;s a very small (but very representative) example: in Season Two, we explore the origins of a side-character, and that origin story briefly features this gem in a flashback:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/lapis.jpg" alt="Lapis is poofed by Bismuth" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Later, in Season Three, we meet the gem again learn more about her relationship to Rose and her role in the war.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/bismuth.jpg" alt="Steven meets Bismuth" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I mean, what? I didn&amp;rsquo;t see this coming at all – and these kinds of hints are scattered throughout the show&amp;rsquo;s art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="art"&gt;Art&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art in the show is spectacular. &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; uses dedicated background artists to help create a cohesive palette of visuals that drive – and are driven by – the plot. It won&amp;rsquo;t do it just to describe, so here are some examples.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/tree.jpg" alt="A tree on a hill" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/car.jpg" alt="Stevonnie driving" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/house.jpg" alt="Steven's kitchen" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/pearl.jpg" alt="Pearl clutching a sword" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The dynamic nature of the show&amp;rsquo;s artwork isn&amp;rsquo;t really represented by still images. The distinctive animation plays a key role. I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned music already, but music+art+animation combine synergistically to convey a really compelling story. Here&amp;rsquo;s one representative example, with some cool glitchy body horror elements!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/Iqp0jlXkNQk' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 id="non-judgemental-narratives"&gt;Non-judgemental Narratives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really dig about the show is how non-judgemental it is. No story ever looks down on a character for their ability, stature, job, lifestyle, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take Greg for example. Greg is a burnt-out wannabe rockstar who lives in his van parked beside the carwash (where he works). Rather than depicting Greg as being unable to care for Steven, the relationship between the two is caring and meaningful. The show celebrates how Greg overcomes difficult challenges to support his son. Greg is probably my favourite character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve presented here a list and explanation of what appeals to me in &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to describe the show only in ways &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; show could be evaluated. This analysis misses out on discussing ways the show excels as a piece of &lt;em&gt;culture&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not well-suited to describing the show&amp;rsquo;s meaningfulness to groups of people who are underrepresented in media, but the show&amp;rsquo;s makers make efforts to tell stories that are neglected by most television media. &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; uses metaphors to tell stories that would normally be &amp;ldquo;over the heads&amp;rdquo; of children, tackling topics normally reserved for &lt;em&gt;Degrassi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metaphors, oh the metaphors!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re keen to start watching the show, there are a few places you can begin with. The first episode, &lt;em&gt;Gem Glow&lt;/em&gt; (S01E01), is a natural place to start; the show finds its footing incredibly quickly. &lt;em&gt;Space Race&lt;/em&gt; (S01E28) is a great way to dive in and get a feel for the show without getting caught up in its lore. And if you want a sneak into the where the show&amp;rsquo;s story is gonna go – while avoiding most spoilers! – try &lt;em&gt;Bismuth&lt;/em&gt; (S03E20). Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomies of Engineering Careers</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/taxonomies-of-engineering-careers/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans are ridiculous bad a taxonomy. We look for patterns to group stuff together, even though most stuff is different from most other stuff. Nature defies any classification system we humans try to create, but it is our nature to try anyway. Our classification systems can &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; be applied universally. Just look at how poorly we define &lt;em&gt;seasons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/s0oX9YJ5XLo' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Drift between theoretical classification systems and the tangible stuff they try to classify isn&amp;rsquo;t always a bad thing. Classifications are a kind of abstraction that hides &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; details in order to make &lt;em&gt;others&lt;/em&gt; easier to reason about. For example, Linnaean taxonomy is good at grouping individuals into &amp;ldquo;species&amp;rdquo; because &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; find it useful; even though nature is &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; too messy to ever be accurately represented in a general taxonomy, having a taxonomy nonetheless helps us study biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Classification systems are most useful when they &lt;em&gt;describe&lt;/em&gt; something that &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; exists. They lose much of their usefulness when we use them to &lt;em&gt;prescribe&lt;/em&gt; what we &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to discuss career ladders! If your engineering team is worth their salt, they try to help you grow as a software developer using a &amp;ldquo;ladder&amp;rdquo; of different stages of your career. I&amp;rsquo;m using my own career and &lt;a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/04/03/artsy-engineering-compensation-framework/"&gt;Artsy&amp;rsquo;s own engineering career ladder&lt;/a&gt; to illustrate shortcomings in engineering careers &lt;em&gt;in general&lt;/em&gt;. Hopefully this will resonate with your and you can help your team work around those shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two main complaints with engineering career ladders:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tacitly expect that engineers will advance up the ladder, always and forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prescribe a single path that engineers are expected to follow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Okay so let&amp;rsquo;s deal with the tacit suggestion that to grow in your career, you need to advance up the ladder. From junior to intermediate to senior and beyond. There is an expectation from businesses and peers that developers ought to seek to advance their careers, that we should always be working towards the next rung of that ladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem is exacerbated by conflation between growing one&amp;rsquo;s career and growing one&amp;rsquo;s skillset; continual learning is inherent to being an engineer, but continual progress up some arbitrary career ladder is not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been facing lately in my own career. According to Artsy, I am a &amp;ldquo;Senior Engineer&amp;rdquo; despite fulfilling many of the requirements for the next level role of &amp;ldquo;Staff Engineer.&amp;rdquo; I had convinced myself that I &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; to broaden my skills and praxis to advance to that next level, despite how it was affecting my happiness and satisfaction with my career &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at a Staff Engineer&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities at Artsy:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owns large scale and impact service or collection of services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understands the Artsy business and makes decisions based on its direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sought out by other team members for technical guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anticipates technical issues at the product level and makes architectural and design decisions to avoid them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognized as a prolific contributor to core and side projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiplies the effectiveness of others by facilitating cross-team work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has track record of creating sweeping improvements in stability, performance, and scalability across services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistently reduces the complexity of projects, services, and processes in order to get more done with less work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has made an obvious positive impact on the entire company&amp;rsquo;s technical trajectory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sets short to medium-term strategic technical direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicates the awesomeness of Artsy technology externally via talks and blog posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The requirements that I already fulfill are fulfilled because &lt;em&gt;I enjoy doing them&lt;/em&gt;. The requirements that I don&amp;rsquo;t fulfill are largely because &lt;em&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy doing them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why aren&amp;rsquo;t I happy just being a &amp;ldquo;Senior Engineer&amp;rdquo;? Probably the hedonic treadmill I guess. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize how much my pursuit of the ladder&amp;rsquo;s next rung was making me unhappy and dissatisfied with what I already have and do. I was a &lt;a href="/blog/we-are-the-coyote/"&gt;coyote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the expectation of engineers to continually advance up a career ladder is intrinsic to the &lt;em&gt;overwhelming&lt;/em&gt; breadth of the ladders themselves. These ladders attempt to describe the complete range of developer experience levels, despite that &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you grow as a junior dev is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different from how you grow as a senior dev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fault is in the ladder metaphor itself. It works well as a prescription of how to grow from novice to competency but does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; work well as a guide to growing from competency to proficiency. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When starting a software developer career, there are basics that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; needs to learn. Things like familiarity with source control, command line tools, and &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; programming language. Once you learn those basics, you can move onto more complex, but still universally applicable skills such as writing idiomatic code or contributing to open source. But beyond these fundamentals, things vary wildly based on individual engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior engineer might pursue a career in user interface systems, people management, community building, system reliability, and so on. No career &amp;ldquo;ladder&amp;rdquo; can possibly prescribe steps and goals for such a wide gamut of paths because careers defy classification. The ladder metaphor works very well for junior engineers but loses applicability the more an engineer advances. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better metaphor might be that of a tree: roots and a trunk that follow a single path upward before splitting into many branches. This provides structure for beginning engineers while still accommodating the breadth of ways individual engineers grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core problem with prescriptive, linear career ladders is that the limitations of the ladder metaphor cause them to be imbued with the biases of whoever writes it. For example, Artsy&amp;rsquo;s engineering career ladder requires public speaking and/or blog posts (which excludes developers who aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in or able to practice those activities). It&amp;rsquo;s also very oriented around &amp;ldquo;services&amp;rdquo;, which excludes developers who work primarily on apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say Artsy&amp;rsquo;s ladder isn&amp;rsquo;t useful – it is! I&amp;rsquo;m just highlighting that the experience and background of the engineers who &lt;em&gt;wrote&lt;/em&gt; Artsy&amp;rsquo;s ladder have influenced it. By extension, those biases have impacted the careers of dozens of engineers who have worked at Artsy. That impact, of biases on career ladders, is going to be present in &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; ladder, no matter who writes it and no matter how useful that ladder is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that my focus on advancing to the &amp;ldquo;next level&amp;rdquo; of Artsy&amp;rsquo;s ladder is hurting my satisfaction with what I already have. I need to learn to pursue career growth that leaves me fulfilled and not dissatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that the ladder metaphor itself is prescriptive and every ladder is imbued with the biases of its authors. Maybe I need to write my own career ladder, specific to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an industry, I hope that we move away from prescription towards description, away from linear tracks towards intertwining paths, away form the relentless pursuit of what&amp;rsquo;s next towards an appreciation for what we&amp;rsquo;ve already accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 17:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/taxonomies-of-engineering-careers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proprioception</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/proprioception/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hold your hand in front of your face. Close your eyes. Now make a fist. Do a &amp;ldquo;thumps up&amp;rdquo; or maybe the Spock sign. Even though your eyes are closed, you know where your hand is and what shape it&amp;rsquo;s in. Seems silly to even say, but this &amp;ldquo;knowing where parts of your body are without seeing them&amp;rdquo; thing is a sense called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proprioception"&gt;proprioception&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not something you&amp;rsquo;d often think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about it. When starting or stopping certain antidepressants, my sense of proprioception gets &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; messed up. You know double-vision? I get that but for proprioception. If I move suddenly, my brain gets confused about where parts of my body are and I get waves of nausea. Not fun, but it&amp;rsquo;s never been this bad. I need to be careful not to turn my head too quickly or the dizziness kicks in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not even &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. You know what other body part frequently makes sudden, jerky movements? (don&amp;rsquo;t be creepy) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your eyes. &lt;em&gt;Constantly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your eyes move, your brain edits out the &amp;ldquo;frames&amp;rdquo; blurred by the quick motion. When you look from the left to the right, your brain sees the left image, then the right image, but not the blurry bits in between. Same with me. I see the new image on the right, but my proprioception is still telling my brain that I&amp;rsquo;m still looking to the left. The cognitive dissonance causes a sort of jolt, almost like electricity. It sweeps across my head without warning, leaving ripples of nausea in its wake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had these side-effects before when starting or stopping an SSRI or SNRI, but never to this degree. Everyday activities are really difficult and laborious. I climb stairs so slowly that my iPhone and Apple Watch don&amp;rsquo;t give me credit towards the &amp;ldquo;flights climbed&amp;rdquo; activity metric (which really pisses me off).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is the worst of it appears to be over, but the bad news is it&amp;rsquo;s still pretty bad. Last week was &lt;em&gt;basically&lt;/em&gt; a write-off. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an appointment tomorrow with my psychiatrist  to follow-up about progress on the new med, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be up to a therapeutic dose within another week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 23:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/proprioception/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
