<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Ash Furrow</title>
    <description>Learning and teaching about interesting topics in iOS Development. Sometimes I diverge to talk about design, photography, or what-have-you.</description>
    <link>https://ashfurrow.com/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Ideology</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/open-source-ideology/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh hey look, my employer &lt;a href="https://artsy.net"&gt;Artsy&lt;/a&gt; is in the news! We got a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/18/15983712/artsy-fine-art-galleries-online-auction-sales"&gt;great write-up in &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and our recent fundraising was reported on in &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/18/online-art-marketplace-artsy-raises-50m-plans-to-double-down-on-auctions"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tech Crunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Very cool! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of my work at Artsy, and I admire the company and its leadership. I especially like a few things, that I would 
argue have a huge positive impact on our business success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there&amp;rsquo;s our &lt;a href="http://code.dblock.org/2015/02/09/becoming-open-source-by-default.html"&gt;Open Source by Default&lt;/a&gt; policy. We &lt;a href="http://artsy.github.io/open-source/"&gt;generate a lot of open source&lt;/a&gt;: code, tools, frameworks. We create projects for – and contributing back to – the Ruby, Node, iOS, and DevOps open source communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, there is our adherence to collaboration over disruption. The term &amp;ldquo;disruption&amp;rdquo; is such a cliché of Silicon Valley, and I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to focus more on collaborating with existing art market players than &amp;ldquo;disrupting&amp;rdquo; them. As time goes on, folks in the valley are starting to realize that disruption may not be the guaranteed path to business success they thought it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This really gets to what I like about the company and it’s culture. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iWC7mMp3wr"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iWC7mMp3wr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; the nokogiri lover (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/887313271518375936"&gt;July 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think these two paradigms – open source and collaboration – complement each other really nicely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;gently&lt;/em&gt; corrected me :) &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But the sentiment of collaboration in lieu of disruption has stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; the nokogiri lover (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/887315061680766976"&gt;July 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artsy&amp;rsquo;s success has always been intrinsically aligned with the company values and open source software. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t build Artsy without open source, especially with such a small team, and we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be as successful as a business without contributing back to that community. Collaboration is intrinsically connected to that open source software as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something so foundational to Artsy&amp;rsquo;s engineering culture that it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to describe. What I&amp;rsquo;ll call our &lt;em&gt;open source ideology&lt;/em&gt; imbues every conversation I have with one of my engineering colleagues. It&amp;rsquo;s contagious. Engineers are drawn to it, they join the company, they drink the Kool-Aid. &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine working any other way&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;ll hear them say. I nod. &amp;ldquo;Neither could I.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is it? Artsy&amp;rsquo;s open source ideology is defined by &amp;ldquo;open source by default&amp;rdquo;, and there are a lot of implications carried in that phrase. To borrow a phrase, open source by default is a &lt;em&gt;mindset&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s the ability for engineers to ask the community for help on a pull request they&amp;rsquo;re having a hard time with. It&amp;rsquo;s taking pride in their work, knowing they can use it and showcase it even after they (eventually) leave the company. It&amp;rsquo;s a sense of ownership, as open source projects created by Artsy engineers are done on their own GitHub accounts – our engineers &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; the open source projects they build. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all our software is open, but even our closed source software still has open source components that we contribute back to. And that closed source software is often modularized and open sourced piecemeal anyway. We aim for a sort of&amp;hellip; minimum viable closed source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is this open source ideology so important to Artsy&amp;rsquo;s business success? Let&amp;rsquo;s frame the impact in business terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low turnover&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s rare for an engineer to leave Artsy. Turnover, especially in specialized fields like software engineering, is a huge cost for businesses. Replacing engineers is expensive, and we don&amp;rsquo;t often have to do it. That&amp;rsquo;s because we&amp;rsquo;ve got&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engaged engineers&lt;/strong&gt;. Our engineering team is really engaged with their work; our internal anonymous surveys back this up. I doubt we could accomplish as much as we do with only 25 engineers if we weren&amp;rsquo;t highly engaged with our jobs. You can read more about the impact of employee engagement on businesses &lt;a href="http://hello.cultureamp.com/hubfs/Impact_of_engagement-whitepaper.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reputation&lt;/strong&gt;. Smart businesses know that you can never have too much reputation. Artsy is well-known among developers in the open source community. That helps us attract talent, making hiring engineers a lot easier for us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Familiarity with tools&lt;/strong&gt;. Every business relies on open source software, at some level, and our team is familiar with a lot of that tooling. There are teammates available to pair with you on whatever compiler/language/tool issue you&amp;rsquo;re having to find the problem, document a fix, and hopefully submit a pull request back to the project. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are a lot of business upsides to working in the open. The risks are pretty minimal too. People tend to overestimate the risks anyway, since the unfamiliar is always scarier than the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ideology is a feedback loop – a sort of flywheel that keeps gaining momentum. The more we contribute to open source, the more we benefit as a business, allowing us to contribute more back, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-cards="hidden" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The team &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/artsy"&gt;@artsy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ArtsyOpenSource"&gt;@ArtsyOpenSource&lt;/a&gt; is committed to spending a lot of our $50MM Series D on writing open source code. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Fb4GxMisrT"&gt;https://t.co/Fb4GxMisrT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Artsy Open Source (@ArtsyOpenSource) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ArtsyOpenSource/status/887358284553912321"&gt;July 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/artsy/meta/blob/master/meta/what_is_artsy.md"&gt;Our values&lt;/a&gt; are open source. They all contribute to our success. But openness, particularly in software, will always be close to my heart, and I&amp;rsquo;ll see it reflected in our success all the time. I believe that this is how the whole software industry will work, eventually, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud to be ahead of the curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would encourage you to experiment with open source by default at your own workplace. Remember, it&amp;rsquo;s open source &lt;em&gt;by default&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;by demand&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to have closed source! The steps to start open source by default, more rationale behind the idea, and tales of our own progress towards this goal are &lt;a href="https://artsy.github.io/series/open-source-by-default/"&gt;all documented&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out, get in touch if you have questions. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 16:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/open-source-ideology/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contemporaneous Blogging</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/contemporaneous-blogging/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/sharing-is-selfish/"&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; – and &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/sharing-is-selfish/"&gt;spoken&lt;/a&gt; – about how we should all be blogging as we learn things. It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea for many reasons, some selfish and some altruistic. But I&amp;rsquo;ve always said: you really should try and write &lt;em&gt;as&lt;/em&gt; you learn something. It&amp;rsquo;s when you&amp;rsquo;re best able to describe and bridge the gap between ignorance and understanding. &lt;em&gt;As&lt;/em&gt; you experience the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are other reasons to blog &lt;em&gt;as&lt;/em&gt; you learn something – contemporaneously with the learning process. For example, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to write about a topic when it&amp;rsquo;s fresh in your mind. Also, even if you &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; to write about something later, it can easily become an item on a todo list that you&amp;rsquo;re likely to put off and &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/issues/188#issuecomment-315918906"&gt;not get to&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But another reason to blog contemporaneously is that you may just not be able to write about something in the future. A friend recently was laid off and now a blog post they had written contemporaneously – but not published – is out of context and needs to be changed. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re able to fit writing into your schedule – please try to. You never know when life circumstances – job, family, housing – could change. Writing about things &lt;em&gt;as&lt;/em&gt; you learn them is the best way to capture that knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you keep it private, writing is a wonderful way to document knowledge and gain a deeper understanding of the subject. I encourage you to try it out, even if writing hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a strength for you. I have faith you&amp;rsquo;ll produce something of value.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/contemporaneous-blogging/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Left Media and Performative Podcasting</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/left-media-and-performative-podcasting/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s the podcast, right? It&amp;rsquo;s by a bunch of hard left folks and they discuss really interesting topics like labour organizing, they provide radical feminist criticisms of popular culture, and they have interesting guests on to discuss their own interesting work. I really enjoy listening to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: they&amp;rsquo;re a bit problematic. They don&amp;rsquo;t adhere to the usual political correctness typical of the left. The language they use – calling people &amp;ldquo;retarded&amp;rdquo; for example – makes me uncomfortable. They walk a fine line between critique of sexism and sexist critique. Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m talking about &lt;a href="https://thetrap.fm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chapo Traphouse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;when the new &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CHAPOTRAPHOUSE"&gt;@CHAPOTRAPHOUSE&lt;/a&gt; drops &lt;a href="https://t.co/o1yB9XAUSo"&gt;pic.twitter.com/o1yB9XAUSo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; 🌴 illy bocean™ 🌴 (@IllyBocean) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IllyBocean/status/851320439896850432"&gt;April 10, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the show gains popularity as a tentpole of radical left culture, it&amp;rsquo;s come under increasing scrutiny (largely from liberals). And while I agree with some of the criticisms lobbed at the show, hating it has become a sort of signifier among liberals that &lt;em&gt;yes, I too think Chapo is problematic&lt;/em&gt;. The liberals that somehow managed to lose to Donald Trump(!) think it in vogue to hate &lt;em&gt;Chapo Traphouse&lt;/em&gt; and its fans, and to consider the show to be the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; enemy of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Instead of organizing against Trump or his awful policies, they criticize a left-wing podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our capitalist society is so completely imbued with the ideology that &lt;em&gt;you are what you consume&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve been hesitant to even admit that I listen to the show (lest I get called out as &lt;em&gt;problematic&lt;/em&gt;). But I am not the podcasts I listen to, and I can enjoy media while being critical of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as the hosts of &lt;em&gt;Chapo Traphouse&lt;/em&gt; themselves point out: the show is not politics, it is entertainment. Listening to &lt;em&gt;Chapo Traphouse&lt;/em&gt; is about as effective at fighting fascism as watching Stephen Colbert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m clearly not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t criticize Chapo. I pretty strongly disagree with a lot of the language they use.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Donald (@Boringstein) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Boringstein/status/885845764655763456"&gt;July 14, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacLean&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; had what is probably the most &lt;a href="http://www.macleans.ca/society/the-rise-of-the-internets-dirtbag-left/"&gt;level-headed analysis of the show&lt;/a&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s emerging popularity. It kind of examines the origins of the show in a roundabout but thoughtful way, interviewing show guest and author Angela Nagle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in dipping your toes in, I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to check out this episode that discusses a popular concept among the left: universal basic income.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/332459247&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But just listening to a podcast doesn&amp;rsquo;t really help anything. And I want to help. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading books they mention, researching the topics they discuss, and have started getting involved in real-world organization in the socialist left. This action, too, comes from the show. From the &lt;em&gt;MacLean&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; article:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chapo’s Frost sees it, the end goal of Left Twitter and catalyzing podcasts like hers is to help the left regain its footing, to organize—and ultimately unplug. &amp;ldquo;The most important thing social media can do politically has always been to get people off the internet,&amp;rdquo; she says. &amp;ldquo;People need to get offline and plug into organizing and campaigns in the real world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The past few months of listening to the show, and the resulting challenges to my existing ideologies, have been tectonic shifts for my politics and even my sense of self (and I was already fairly left-leaning before). I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure where I&amp;rsquo;m going, and I&amp;rsquo;m a bit scared. That&amp;rsquo;s okay – change is always scary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 16:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/left-media-and-performative-podcasting/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon Interview</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-interview/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://joinmastodon.org"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;: still a thing. And &lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology"&gt;my instance&lt;/a&gt;, also still a thing! Recently, one of the users on mastodon.technology sat down and &lt;a href="http://www.smays.com/2017/06/ash-furrow/"&gt;interviewed me&lt;/a&gt; about the platform and the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/x3FEs8sgXjE' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My participation in Mastodon hasn&amp;rsquo;t been steady, but neither was my participation in Twitter at first. I&amp;rsquo;m still finding my feet and my voice there. I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what the future holds; this is still an experiment, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see where we end up together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-interview/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why My Eyes Gently Roll</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/why-my-eyes-gently-roll/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, an article from the Washington Post titled &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2017/lifestyle/the-slow-secret-death-of-the-electric-guitar/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why my guitar gently weeps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; made its way around the internet&amp;rsquo;s various music circles. The article makes some noise about falling guitar sales and draws conclusions from interviews that the author conducted with various captains of industry; its thesis is that sales are trending down, the industry is shrinking, and a lack of &amp;ldquo;guitar heroes&amp;rdquo; is to blame. Young people – apparently – just don&amp;rsquo;t have enough rock stars to look up to and emulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to read the post (it&amp;rsquo;s not long) prepare yourself for some extreme eye-rolling. Also, the article uses some weird JavaScript scroll hijacking, so have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost as an aside, the article mentions a shift towards more women and girls learning guitar, but brushes their increased interest aside as trivial – or based purely in aesthetics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Mooney, the Fender CEO, calls [Taylor] Swift “the most influential guitarist of recent years.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think that young girls looked at Taylor and said, ‘I’m really impressed by the way she plays G major arpeggios.’ ” Mooney says. “They liked how she looked, and they wanted to emulate her.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds dismissive. After all, young folks of the past were focused &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; on the sounds of musicians and not their looks (for example, this is why KISS is known for wearing only dull boring outfits during performances). Girls don&amp;rsquo;t care about music, just about looks. Uh huh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a writing perspective, the biggest weakness of the article is that the author neglected to include perspectives from actual &lt;em&gt;guitarists&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, Geoff Edgars tacitly implies that falling guitar sales = declining industry = declining guitar popularity. A lot of folks around guitar forums and YouTube have pointed out this fallacy, and they further refute the claim that there are no &amp;ldquo;guitar heroes&amp;rdquo; by offering their own list of popular players. Usually men. Actually, all men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think that just maybe our society has some kind of problem with attitudes towards women.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with the musicians&amp;rsquo; rebuttal, that there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; still &amp;ldquo;guitar heroes&amp;rdquo; (gosh I dislike that term). I can name a few bands that really influenced my decision to pick up the guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, there&amp;rsquo;s such an abundance of educational resources on learning guitar that, since starting in December, I&amp;rsquo;ve at times felt overwhelmed by just how much there is to learn, and just how many ways there are to learn it all. I would be interested in reading an article discussing these resources, the rising popularity of YouTube as a music education platform, and hearing from a variety of musicians (of all genders) about their perspectives on the guitar industry&amp;rsquo;s decline. But that would require the Washington Post to investigate – which is apparently too much to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 18:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/why-my-eyes-gently-roll/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feelings are Hard</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/feelings-are-hard/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Things have been getting to me lately. Big things, little things, all kinds of things. The result is: I get upset. Angry even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aaaaaand because I insist on spending so much of my life on Twitter (I need to stop that&amp;hellip;) everyone gets to see me get upset at things. The latest problems in my life are bringing the wrong computer cable and the LEGO store being sold out of something I want. Pretty childish stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hey Ash, sounds like you’re not having the best day. Here’s a box of fucking adorable goddamn kittens. It’ll help you on your way. &lt;a href="https://t.co/92nzKdfbFB"&gt;pic.twitter.com/92nzKdfbFB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Aaron Vegh 📎 (@aaronvegh) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aaronvegh/status/875051392515403784"&gt;June 14, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, things were going great until about six weeks ago when my doctor suggested going off one of my medications. I&amp;rsquo;m on a very small dose, and we wanted to see if I needed it. Turns out I desperately do. Within a week I was miserable, flat, depressed. I finally got back on the medication, and as soon as it kicked in, I caught a cold. So I&amp;rsquo;m back to feeling miserable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing guitar can help, except my wrists hurt too much to play. So I get a little more sad. Sleeping helps, I feel better in the mornings. Doing things helps, so I feel better when I make it to the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the sort of back drop for this emotional rollercoaster is the political landscape of 2017. What a shitty year it&amp;rsquo;s been and promises to continue to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be okay – I have a supportive partner, and a therapist, and a psychiatrist. And I&amp;rsquo;m making progress all the time. I&amp;rsquo;ve just had such a hard time over the past month or so. This summer was supposed to be refreshing and exciting, but instead it&amp;rsquo;s began with familiar ennui. Things are looking up, I guess, but I can&amp;rsquo;t help feel like I&amp;rsquo;m going to be stuck here forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/feelings-are-hard/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
