<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Ash Furrow</title>
    <description>Learning and teaching about interesting topics in iOS Development. Sometimes I diverge to talk about design, photography, or what-have-you.</description>
    <link>https://ashfurrow.com/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Photography Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/photography-retrospective/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February of 2012, I wrote that &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/effort-to-improved-skill-ratio-and-expertise/"&gt;I would not be buying a camera&lt;/a&gt;. Two months later, &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-i-bought-a-camera/"&gt;I did buy one&lt;/a&gt;, and that decision has come to shape a lot of who I am today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how four years seems like a long time, but also feels really short, too. Photography exploded into my life, taking up all my spare time, attention, and money. I knew it would when I started. After all, I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved gadgets and gizmos, and photography is rife with things to fiddle with and obsess over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept buying nicer and nicer lenses, and nicer and nicer cameras, until I had &amp;ldquo;the setup&amp;rdquo;, what I thought would signal to other photographers (and myself) that I was serious about photography. It was never enough. I had a problem. I felt addicted to buying gear. I would feel crummy and think that buying such-and-such new photography thing would make me feel better, and it did, but that elation would quickly subside when I realized that I &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have bought that&lt;/em&gt;. So that would make me feel crummy too and the cycle would repeat. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying photography gear was an unhealthy coping mechanism that I used to deal with my &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/depression/"&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, but eventually I did manage to stop before I did unrepairable damage to my marriage and finances. When I moved to New York, I got the help I needed, and that&amp;rsquo;s made recovery from &amp;ldquo;gear acquisition syndrome&amp;rdquo; possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the dark side of my photography. But there&amp;rsquo;s a good side, too: photography is a huge, positive part of my life – in both lofty and day-to-day senses. Let me explain both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted &lt;em&gt;so much&lt;/em&gt; to feel like a &amp;ldquo;real photographer&amp;rdquo;, and I bought gear that I thought would help. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t smart, but it did lead to making making a lot of photos, and that &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; help me feel like a photographer. More than that, I eventually stopped caring about how I appear to others as a photographer; photography has become something I do &lt;em&gt;for me&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying gear didn&amp;rsquo;t help, but actually using the gear I had &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt;. And eventually, I learnt that it didn&amp;rsquo;t really matter anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, a camera accompanies me everywhere I go. Every time I leave my apartment, I have my camera in my bag, and the camera is already in my hand by the time my feet hit the sidewalk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Walk to work: 30 minutes of Spotify. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Walk to work, carrying a camera: 45 minutes of “wow, everything is amazing!” … and Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/695643794922934272"&gt;February 5, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Photography taught me to &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/developers-should-learn-photography/"&gt;learn from my mistakes&lt;/a&gt;; if a photo didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way I wanted, I figured out why. Once I found out what went wrong, I tried not to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the choices I&amp;rsquo;ve made haven&amp;rsquo;t turned out for the best, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer has actually been the first time in my life that I haven&amp;rsquo;t lived paycheque-to-paycheque. It sucks that it took until my late twenties to get my shit together, but I want to concentrate on the fact that &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m actually getting my shit together&lt;/em&gt;. And honestly, photography only exacerbated an obsession with buying things. But, it did help in unique ways that I think only art could have. It taught me lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to other parts of my life, and it now helps take my mind off things when I do feel down. It&amp;rsquo;s become a healthy coping mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could go back and explain all this to myself in 2012, when I was buying my first camera, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure my younger self would understand. It&amp;rsquo;s like &lt;a href="https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2009/01/12/abstraction-intuition-and-the-monad-tutorial-fallacy/"&gt;monads&lt;/a&gt;, you can&amp;rsquo;t explain how they work because that comprehension can only come from struggling with them. You can&amp;rsquo;t take a shortcut. With buying photography gear, I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand how I was hurting myself until I had struggled for a while. Maybe the struggle was necessary. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m glad it&amp;rsquo;s ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s my retrospective on photography, at least so far: a hobby-turned-obsession that cost a lot of money and caused a lot of stress, but also a hobby that became a healthy coping mechanism with a lot of fun. Like most everything, photography hasn&amp;rsquo;t been &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo;, but a bit of both. I can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/photography-retrospective/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh macOS Setup</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/fresh-macos-setup/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of things I do when I re-install macOS on a computer, or when I begin working on a new computer. I don&amp;rsquo;t do this often, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget the steps. So I &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/ashfurrow/3865eed417a5fbe8402708e2c706eea6"&gt;documented everything in a gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to keep these steps in Notes.app but figured they should be public anyway (open source by default, right?) so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/ashfurrow/3865eed417a5fbe8402708e2c706eea6.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve added recently, that&amp;rsquo;s super-important to me, is to untrust a certain certificate. Blue Coat is a company that creates &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Coat_Systems#Controversy"&gt;internet surveillance and censorship software&lt;/a&gt; and Semantic gave them an intermediate CA certificate. That means they can sign arbitrary certificates that you&amp;rsquo;re computer will trust (because your computer trusts Semantic, and Semantic trusts Blue Coat). &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;BlueCoat now has a CA signed by Symantec &lt;a href="https://t.co/8OXmtpT6eX"&gt;https://t.co/8OXmtpT6eX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to untrust it &lt;a href="https://t.co/NDlbqKqqld"&gt;https://t.co/NDlbqKqqld&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/mBD68nrVsD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/mBD68nrVsD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Filippo Valsorda (@FiloSottile) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FiloSottile/status/735940720931012608"&gt;May 26, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really into the idea of my computer trusting a company like Blue Coat, so I &lt;a href="https://blog.filippo.io/untrusting-an-intermediate-ca-on-os-x/"&gt;follow the instructions&lt;/a&gt; to untrust this certificate. I highly recommend you do, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I recommend you document everything you do to make your computer awesome! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 14:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/fresh-macos-setup/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Search with Middleman and lunrjs</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/static-site-search-with-middleman-and-lunrjs/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/issues/213"&gt;someone opened an issue&lt;/a&gt; asking for a site search on my blog. Neat idea, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t high on my list of priorities at the time, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;d get to it someday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, today&amp;rsquo;s the day 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: The original &amp;ldquo;the day&amp;rdquo; was two weeks ago but I had given up in frustration.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search is an interesting problem. Most search engines run on servers and not the browser client. This site, just like all static sites like those built with &lt;a href="https://middlemanapp.com"&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt;, is generated on a computer before being served statically. It&amp;rsquo;s a faster, easier, and more secure way of serving web pages that don&amp;rsquo;t need dynamism, but it does mean that you can&amp;rsquo;t run server code when a page is fetched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running search on servers makes sense for DuckDuckGo and Google because their search engines are trying to cover the whole internet. But for a site like mine, a client-side search engine written in Javascript can be a suitable solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lucene.apache.org/solr/"&gt;Solr&lt;/a&gt; is an open source search engine. &lt;a href="http://lunrjs.com"&gt;lunrjs&lt;/a&gt; is a Javascript-based search engine, which claims to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit like Solr, but much smaller and not as bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lovely. I think the sun-vs-moon metaphor for server-vs-client search engines is really apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few Middleman extensions that integrate lunrjs search into static sites, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get any to work for me because I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand how they worked. I ended up &lt;a href="https://github.com/256dpi/middleman-lunr/blob/5c49621007e003da0b748ec8bd34bfc7b11240d2/lib/middleman-lunr/indexer.rb#L23-L64"&gt;reading the source code&lt;/a&gt; of one to understand &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how it worked. Even then, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get things right. It turns out that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know enough Javascript to use a Javascript-based search engine. Not yet anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I submitted a &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/232"&gt;work-in-progress pull request&lt;/a&gt; and gave up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little break and some food, I went back and looked into a different extension. Actually it was the original extension I tried but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it working. I understood what it was doing on the Ruby side, and concentrated just on the Javascript. After looking up some jQuery syntax, I had something that worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some fiddling with CSS and lining things up, &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/233"&gt;I had a ready PR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/search"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/static-site-search-with-middleman-and-lunrjs/screenshot.jpg" alt="Screenshot of site search" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Site search stumped me for weeks. Distinct from search engines in general, server-side static site search is a very interesting problem in its own right. Ruby code uses Javascript to generate a search engine index of the content of my entire site. Then client-side Javascript downloads that index and uses lunrjs to run queries against it. It crosses the dynamic-to-static barrier, which isn&amp;rsquo;t something many other features of static sites need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After submitting the pull request, I realized I had been working into the late evening, that I&amp;rsquo;d had a beer or two, and that maybe pushing code to production wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best thing to do. I pinged Orta on the pull request and asked for a second opinion. It can never hurt to have someone double-check things for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things checked out, and &lt;a href="/search"&gt;search is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/233"&gt;The pull request is here&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to comment on anything that you&amp;rsquo;d like clarification on or that you have a suggestion about. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are ways this could be more idiomatically done. (&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog/pull/237"&gt;added documentation&lt;/a&gt; to all the code and linked to the relevant code &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/blog"&gt;in the readme&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing new features into software can be overwhelming, and stepping back for a break is usually the right answer. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to give up if things are getting frustrating, and it&amp;rsquo;s okay to ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;PARTY TIP: At the end of the day, just try your hardest to be nice.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ANDREW W.K. (@AndrewWK) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AndrewWK/status/722843678994219009"&gt;April 20, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all in this together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 15:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/static-site-search-with-middleman-and-lunrjs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asking for Help in Open Source</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/asking-for-help-in-open-source/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Note: this post isn&amp;rsquo;t addressed to or aimed at anyone in particular, it&amp;rsquo;s just general advice. I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="/blog/how-to-ask-for-developer-help"&gt;written about this before&lt;/a&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s time for a refresher.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m going to start by addressing the elephant in the open source room: licensing. I could quote any open source license here and point out that it says &amp;ldquo;software provided without warranty&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;software provided as-is&amp;rdquo; or whatever else that really means &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t owe you tech support.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not going to do that, because I don&amp;rsquo;t believe it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I write open source and publish it, and then you use it, I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;legally&lt;/em&gt; owe you anything, but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; owe you something. Maintainers get to benefit from developers using our code, because they&amp;rsquo;ll find bugs and recommend feature requests and we get to benefit from all that too. Maintainers benefit when our code gets used, and I think there&amp;rsquo;s a reciprocal nature to that relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of that relationship, maintainers are responsible for acknowledging bug reports and giving advice to solve problems. We don&amp;rsquo;t owe anyone technical support or bug fixes, but if we spend a few minutes to point you in the right direction for a fix, we can benefit too. We&amp;rsquo;ll ask you to submit a pull request adding a feature or fixing a bug or clarifying some documentation. That&amp;rsquo;s the sort of social contract that exists in open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is a &lt;em&gt;reciprocal&lt;/em&gt; relationship, which means you owe us too. You should be kind, provide steps to reproduce a bug, details about a feature you&amp;rsquo;ve requested, that kind of stuff. One more thing you owe us is to respect the project&amp;rsquo;s communication norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you find a bug, open an issue. If you have a feature request, open an issue. If you have a question, open an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t tweet or email contributors with this stuff. Open an issue, if they don&amp;rsquo;t answer within a reasonable amount of time, maybe send them a link to the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t just to keep my inbox manageable, you should do this for your own sake: chances are there are other people watching the issues that can help you faster than I can. Your issue will probably get answered faster than I can answer an email or tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source is big, it&amp;rsquo;s many-to-many, and when you email or tweet at me, that really limits how many people can benefit from my response. &lt;a href="https://realm.io/news/altconf-orta-therox-being-nice-in-open-source/"&gt;Being nice is nice&lt;/a&gt;, so be nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 15:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/asking-for-help-in-open-source/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Workshop Notes</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/blogging-workshop-notes/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, at Artsy&amp;rsquo;s offsite, Orta and I are leading a workshop named &amp;ldquo;Bootstrap your Blog!&amp;rdquo; where we&amp;rsquo;ll try to get participants most of the way towards their first blog post. This advice is widely applicable, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the introductory email we sent participants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello team! Orta and I are super-excited you&amp;rsquo;re coming to our &amp;ldquo;Bootstrap your Blog&amp;rdquo; workshop at Artsy&amp;rsquo;s offsite! Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief intro describing the workshop and a small bit of necessary preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our workshop&amp;rsquo;s goal is to get you most of the way towards writing your first blog post. We&amp;rsquo;ll be describing what a good blog post is, how to write one, and most importantly: how to recognize when to write a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to bring an idea to blog about. This idea should be something you care about – the more you care, the easier it&amp;rsquo;ll be to blog. It can be related to Artsy, or not, as long as you care about it. Try to think of something you&amp;rsquo;ve recently learned, or were surprised by, and bring that idea with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re recommending you use pencil and paper, which suits the offsite a little better than computers. We&amp;rsquo;ll have materials, but you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to use a laptop or tablet if that&amp;rsquo;s more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re really looking forward to this because we both believe in a world where everyone benefits when we all share our experiences. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting and rewarding to be there as you take your first steps into that world, but remember that the most important thing is that you enjoy yourself. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The email is meant to be encouraging without applying too much pressure. People get caught up in the details of writing and that can be discouraging. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to frame our introduction as a learning exercise so that making mistakes, or not completing a blog post, are totally acceptable. I write half blog posts all the time and they never get published, and that&amp;rsquo;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the main points we&amp;rsquo;re going to cover in the actual workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-recognize-when-to-blog"&gt;How to recognize when to blog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogging is easiest and most effective when the blogger &lt;em&gt;cares&lt;/em&gt; about the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more you care about the subject, the more you should blog about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you learn something, if something wasn&amp;rsquo;t immediately obvious to you, if something surprised you, write down a few notes. You probably won&amp;rsquo;t remember this later, but these little things can turn out to be the most important part of your post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-is-a-good-blog-post"&gt;What is a good blog post?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good blog post is usually short, even a few paragraphs can be effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good blog post usually tells a story. The better storytelling, the better the blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog posts, like all stories, usually follow the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hero%27s_journey"&gt;Hero&amp;rsquo;s Journey&lt;/a&gt; (and you&amp;rsquo;re the hero!). Here are 5 good steps for a blog post:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Ordinary World&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Call to Adventure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Ordeal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Reward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Return&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The story your blog posts should tell is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; story. Since &lt;em&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re&lt;/em&gt; the best person to tell your story, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about blogging something that another blogger has already discussed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-start-writing-a-post"&gt;How to start writing a post?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with a stream of consciousness process. Either:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stream an outline of the story and fill in details later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stream a story and organize it later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting is the hardest part.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="miscellaneous-advice"&gt;Miscellaneous advice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worry about where to put it, formatting, etc &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a medium, blogs are not printed on paper. They exist on the web, and can be corrected. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about publishing something less than perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orta and I can help you get set up putting your blog post online when we get back to New York. Just worry about the content :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it! Remember to relax, take it easy, and remember: your blog doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be perfect, it just needs to be yours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 18:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/blogging-workshop-notes/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stargate SG-1 in 50 Hours</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/stargate-sg-1-in-50-hours/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about one of my favourite science fiction shows, &lt;a href="/blog/star-trek-voyager-in-40-hours/"&gt;Star Trek Voyager&lt;/a&gt;. I really liked the format of that post, where I break the show down into bitesized chunks, so I decided to do it again with &lt;em&gt;Stargate SG-1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I love about &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; is that the characters aren&amp;rsquo;t from the 23rd century, and they&amp;rsquo;re not from Kobol and the Twelve Colonies, and they&amp;rsquo;re not from a galaxy far, far away. They&amp;rsquo;re people &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; with the strengths and flaws of &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt; as we exist &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;. Well technically as we existed in the late 90s, but still. It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to relate to the characters because they&amp;rsquo;re so much closer to us as an audience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the largest villains in the first season is a goddamn &lt;em&gt;US Senator&lt;/em&gt; who thinks the whole Stargate program is too expensive and wants to shut it down to save money. That would totally happen! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What damaged &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s reputation more than anything was its timing. &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/make-sci-fi-great-again/"&gt;Sci-fi isn&amp;rsquo;t fun anymore&lt;/a&gt;, and Stargate happened just as sci-fi was transitioning to the dystopian stories we have today. If Stargate had been a few years earlier, or Battlestar: Galactica had been a few years later, I think &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; would enjoy a much nicer reputation than it does today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; has arcs that span many seasons, intertwined with episodic stories. It&amp;rsquo;s a really great balance and is written well enough that you can watch an episode without any background knowledge and still really enjoy it. Generally, &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; can be divided into three parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seasons 1–5&lt;/strong&gt; A fun adventure with scrappy humans barely holding their own against far more powerful foes. Episodes focus on finding new allies and applying newly discovered technology to defend Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seasons 6–8&lt;/strong&gt; Earth is a little more advanced; we have managed to build a space ship all by ourselves but things are still rocky. Episodes focus on developing deeper friendships with allies, international- and interplanetary-politics, and using Earth&amp;rsquo;s new capabilities as plot devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seasons 9 &amp;amp; 10&lt;/strong&gt; The main foe of the series has been defeated, Earth is the badass rockstar of the Milky Way. Too bad another galaxy invades because we accidentally make ourselves known to them. Episodes are still fun, with darker elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-1"&gt;Season 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first season begins with a strong pilot written by Jonathan Glassner and Brad Wright, the two people responsible for adapting the Stargate feature film to television. &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; quickly establishes the tone of the show: they know the kinds of stories they want to tell and how they want to tell them. Here are my favourite episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 1 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2amFtVN"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S01E01&lt;/strong&gt;: Children of the Gods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S01E10&lt;/strong&gt;: Thor&amp;rsquo;s Hammer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S01E15&lt;/strong&gt;: Singularity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S01E18&lt;/strong&gt;: Solitudes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S01E20&lt;/strong&gt;: There But for the Grace of God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-2"&gt;Season 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show expands on the mythology established from the first season. Concepts and storylines are revisited, and you see more and more character development. By the end of Season 2, Teal&amp;#39;c has really opened up to bonding with the rest of the team beyond a warrior&amp;rsquo;s role. From what I gather, Christopher Judge wanted more creative input on the show and started taking his portrayal of Teal&amp;#39;c a lot more seriously later in season two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 2 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2aB121A"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S02E02&lt;/strong&gt;: In the Line of Duty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S02E03&lt;/strong&gt;: Prisoners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S02E11&lt;/strong&gt;: The Tok’ra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S02E14&lt;/strong&gt;: Touchstone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S02E16&lt;/strong&gt;: A Matter of Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S02E19&lt;/strong&gt;: One False Step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S02E21&lt;/strong&gt;: 1969&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-3"&gt;Season 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next season really works on crafting the storytelling techniques, but episodes are still a bit hammy. This fades over the course of this season, but the show stays as fun. &lt;em&gt;Foothold&lt;/em&gt; is one of my favourite episodes, and &lt;em&gt;Urgo&lt;/em&gt; features Dom DeLuise playing opposite roles as a funny and serious character. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 3 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2adWnjB"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E02&lt;/strong&gt;: Seth &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E04&lt;/strong&gt;: Legacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E06&lt;/strong&gt;: Point of View&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E09&lt;/strong&gt;: Rules of Engagement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E11&lt;/strong&gt;: Past and Present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E14&lt;/strong&gt;: Foothold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E15&lt;/strong&gt;: Pretense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E16&lt;/strong&gt;: Urgo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S03E18&lt;/strong&gt;: Shades of Grey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-4"&gt;Season 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth season is my favourite. For a show with such a strong start, you can really tell when it hits its stride. The show continues themes and storylines established in the previous seasons, while exploring the relationship with the Tok&amp;#39;Ra, the Aschen, and the Russians. Quite a ride!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 4 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2amXNb0"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E01&lt;/strong&gt;: Small Victories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E03&lt;/strong&gt;: Upgrades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E05&lt;/strong&gt;: Divide and Conquer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E06&lt;/strong&gt;: Window of Opportunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E07&lt;/strong&gt;: Watergate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E10&lt;/strong&gt;: Beneath the Surface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E12&lt;/strong&gt;: Tangent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E15&lt;/strong&gt;: Chain Reaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E16&lt;/strong&gt;: 2010&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E20&lt;/strong&gt;: Entity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S04E22&lt;/strong&gt;: Exodus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-5"&gt;Season 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the season the show started to feel a little stale, and afterward the show actually moved from Showtime to the SciFi channel for season six. There are still some great episodes: &lt;em&gt;2001&lt;/em&gt; is the perfect follow-up from last season&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;2010&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;48 Hours&lt;/em&gt; introduces a new recurring frenemy: Dr Rodney McKay portrayed by David Hewlett. Oh, and Daniel dies in &lt;em&gt;Meridian&lt;/em&gt;, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry he&amp;rsquo;ll show up in the next season a few times before returning permanently in season seven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 5 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2a9KMGQ"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S05E03&lt;/strong&gt;: Ascension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S05E10&lt;/strong&gt;: 2001&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S05E11&lt;/strong&gt;: Desperate Measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S05E14&lt;/strong&gt;: 48 Hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S05E21&lt;/strong&gt;: Meridian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-6"&gt;Season 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so season six isn&amp;rsquo;t too popular with &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; fans, probably because Daniel&amp;rsquo;s gone and there&amp;rsquo;s this new character. But it&amp;rsquo;s a great season! The switch to the SciFi channel included a switch to HD widescreen format and better lighting/production. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this season is actually really good. &lt;em&gt;Redemption&lt;/em&gt; features Dr Rodney McKay, and you start to see him and Samantha become better frenemies. &lt;em&gt;Nightwalkers&lt;/em&gt; is a fantastic piece of storytelling and a strong Jonas episode, and &lt;em&gt;Abyss&lt;/em&gt; features a masterful performance by Richard Dean Anderson while introducing a great new villain: Ba&amp;#39;al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 6 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2aJ0tma"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S06E01&lt;/strong&gt;: Redemption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S06E05&lt;/strong&gt;: Nightwalkers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S06E06&lt;/strong&gt;: Abyss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S06E11&lt;/strong&gt;: Prometheus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S06E22&lt;/strong&gt;: Full Circle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-7"&gt;Season 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Jackson returns in &lt;em&gt;Fallen&lt;/em&gt; following the events of &lt;em&gt;Full Circle&lt;/em&gt;, the previous season&amp;rsquo;s finale. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot we have to skip over here, but &lt;em&gt;Grace&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Heroes&lt;/em&gt; are two of the best episodes of the whole show. At the end of the season, Jack gets promoted to General and returns in season eight as the SGC commanding officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 7 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2anXPCM"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S07E01&lt;/strong&gt;: Fallen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S07E09&lt;/strong&gt;: Avenger 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S07E13&lt;/strong&gt;: Grace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S07E17&lt;/strong&gt;: Heroes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-8"&gt;Season 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season eight is a bit weird, since Jack isn&amp;rsquo;t on the SG-1 team anymore, which fundamentally changes his relationship with the other characters. They portray this shift really well, and have a lot of fun with it, but Richard Dean Anderson does leave the show after this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However! This is still a great season. &lt;em&gt;Threads&lt;/em&gt; ties up a lot of loose ends and &lt;em&gt;Moebius&lt;/em&gt; would have been a fantastic series finale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 8 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2amFEjW"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S08E03&lt;/strong&gt;: Lockdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S08E04&lt;/strong&gt;: Zero Hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S08E10&lt;/strong&gt;: Endgame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S08E12&lt;/strong&gt;: Prometheus Unbound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S08E18&lt;/strong&gt;: Threads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S08E19&lt;/strong&gt;: Moebius&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-9"&gt;Season 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season nine introduces a brand new main character and a brand new enemy. The galaxy has an enormous power vacuum left by the Goa&amp;#39;uld, and it gets filled with Jaffa politics and the Ori. The Ori are an interesting villain, because unlike the previous Goa&amp;#39;uld, they arguably &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the gods they claim to be. It&amp;rsquo;s a great take on the show&amp;rsquo;s origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduced in Avalon, the Ori storyline sets up the rest of the season and introduces Valla as a recurring character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 9 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2a9KJuo"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S09E01&lt;/strong&gt;: Avalon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S09E19&lt;/strong&gt;: Crusade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S09E20&lt;/strong&gt;: Camelot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="season-10"&gt;Season 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final season of the show is actually pretty good. The show hit its new groove and the characters show meaningful, believable friendships. &lt;em&gt;The Pegasus Project&lt;/em&gt; is a crossover with &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s spinoff, &lt;em&gt;Stargate Atlantis&lt;/em&gt;, which deserves its own blog post. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the &lt;em&gt;funniest&lt;/em&gt; season of &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;200&lt;/em&gt; is the two hundredth episode of the show, and calls back to &lt;em&gt;Wormhole X-treme!&lt;/em&gt;, while &lt;em&gt;The Road Not Taken&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bad Guys&lt;/em&gt; both take an existing concept from the franchise and turn the idea on its head. &lt;em&gt;Unending&lt;/em&gt; is an&amp;hellip; Interesting way to end a show. But they get away with it because there are two &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; straight-to-television movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Season 10 on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2amXRaG"&gt;Amazon Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S10E01&lt;/strong&gt;: Flesh and Blood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S10E03&lt;/strong&gt;: The Pegasus Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S10E06&lt;/strong&gt;: 200&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S10E13&lt;/strong&gt;: The Road Not Taken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S10E16&lt;/strong&gt;: Bad Guys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S10E20&lt;/strong&gt;: Unending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2amG2P4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ark of Truth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2aB1D3a"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Continuum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are the two made-for-TV movies from the SciFi channel. They&amp;rsquo;re pretty great, I enjoyed them each. &lt;em&gt;Ark of Truth&lt;/em&gt; wraps up the Ori storyline with a visit &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; the Ori galaxy through the supergate. &lt;em&gt;Contiuum&lt;/em&gt; is a masterpiece of time-travel storytelling, featuring Ba&amp;#39;al, the series&amp;rsquo; best villain. The film wraps up his I-have-a-hundred-clones storyline by killing the last of them. It&amp;rsquo;s a romp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, &lt;em&gt;SG-1&lt;/em&gt; has a spinoff. Actually, it has two! Actually there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stargate_Infinity"&gt;also a terrible cartoon&lt;/a&gt;, but don&amp;rsquo;t want it. Seriously don&amp;rsquo;t watch it. But &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; go ahead and watch &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2ae1W1r"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stargate Atlantis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea, but there&amp;rsquo;s just something about an international team of scrappy humans barely surviving in another galaxy that works for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a scrappy bunch of barely surviving people is not sufficient to drive a plot. And unfortunately, the writers thought they could replace actual character development with sex appeal, and we got &lt;em&gt;Stargate 90210&lt;/em&gt;. Er, &lt;em&gt;Stargate Universe&lt;/em&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t watch it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like what you watched in this guide, it’s worth going back to watch some of the episodes you skipped. I had a really hard time trimming this down to only 50 hours of television and had to leave out some great episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/stargate-sg-1-in-50-hours/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
