<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>Ash Furrow</title>
    <description>Learning and teaching about interesting topics in iOS Development. Sometimes I diverge to talk about design, photography, or what-have-you.</description>
    <link>https://ashfurrow.com/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Update on Medication Changes</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/update-on-medication-changes/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been open about my &lt;a href="/blog/good-bad-days/"&gt;recent changes to antidepressant medications&lt;/a&gt; and I wanted to provide an update about how things are going. In a word: well. Things are going well. A lot better than they&amp;rsquo;ve gone in a long time, in fact. I attribute this improvement to a recent change in medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depression saps energy from me. There are days I can&amp;rsquo;t even get out of bed because it takes too much energy. What I miss most about &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; having depression is the abundance of things to do. There were days in university where I would stay up all night configuring drivers for a hackintosh because I was just &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; excited to do it. Or times in Toronto when I&amp;rsquo;d walk myself to exhaustion taking photos all day, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss feeling &lt;em&gt;compelled&lt;/em&gt; to do something: the ecstasy of borderline mania that accompanies me when I&amp;rsquo;m accomplishing something I have my heart set on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling a trickle of that energy. Not a lot, but more than, you know, none. I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the projects I get to work on at Artsy, I&amp;rsquo;m writing on this blog more I&amp;rsquo;m taking guitar lessons, I&amp;rsquo;m hosting an &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon/"&gt;OSS social network&lt;/a&gt; for crying out loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time in a while, the things I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;excited&lt;/em&gt; to do exceed the number of hours I have to spend on them. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to play guitar, but also excited to write this blog post. I have to pick one, and here we are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, it&amp;rsquo;s introducing some FOMO and I&amp;rsquo;m having a hard time dealing with that kind of anxiety. This is progress. Recovery isn&amp;rsquo;t a straight line, and if my recouped energy leads me to a little anxiety around what to spend my time on, well then I&amp;rsquo;ll have to deal with that. No problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/update-on-medication-changes/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon Administration</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-administration/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I &lt;a href="/blog/mastodon/"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about starting my own Mastodon instance. It&amp;rsquo;s like a federated Twitter, and it&amp;rsquo;s really fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a place for tech folks to hang out, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of experience with server administration. So I chose Heroku. Things have gone&amp;hellip; okay. Mostly good, even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve run into a number of scaling issues, 500 errors, questions I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to, yikes. So I&amp;rsquo;ve spent time searching for answers, scaling up Heroku Dynos, configuring DNS settings, and upgrading Postgres databases. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mastodon-administration/resources.png" alt="Resources" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My hope is that these resources will be sufficient for some time while the community scales. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on starting a Patreon to help cover the hosting costs, and maybe even a little of my time. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to start asking for help unless I&amp;rsquo;m certain that this is something I want to build in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this has taken time away from the rest of my life. If that cost is largely upfront, with ongoing costs not taking up a lot of time, then that&amp;rsquo;s great. But I can&amp;rsquo;t afford to give dozens of hours a month to this project. If things start looking dire, at least I know who to ask for help 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, here are the metrics for the Heroku app. The red numbers worry me. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how things go. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of migrating the whole instance over to a Digital Ocean instance, which would bring the costs down considerably, but the limiting factor is my time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mastodon-administration/metrics.png" alt="Metrics" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At first I was really overwhelmed because things weren&amp;rsquo;t always running perfectly. Then I realized that this is just a process, an experiment, and I should relax. People have been thanking me for setting up the instance, which has felt really nice. Even if this space turns out to be ephemeral, it&amp;rsquo;s still its own community, and creating that community is really rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I accepted that the instance won&amp;rsquo;t be around forever, that at some point in the future it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; shut down (all websites will eventually), once I accepted that fact, things became a lot less stressful. So what if GIF uploads aren&amp;rsquo;t work, or 2FA is broken? I&amp;rsquo;m opening GitHub issues to ask for help, and I&amp;rsquo;m getting helped. I&amp;rsquo;m contributing back documentation improvements. I&amp;rsquo;m learning a &lt;em&gt;tonne&lt;/em&gt; about how to administer websites through firsthand experience and experimentation. And I&amp;rsquo;m helping contribute to an entire community of online communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology"&gt;join&lt;/a&gt;, if you like, in a social media experiment and experience. It might not last – but nothing does – and in the mean time, you can have fun and meet new friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re keen, I&amp;rsquo;m going to need help. Things on my agenda are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define a code of conduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help to establish community norms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;respond to reported abuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in helping, let&amp;rsquo;s chat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 22:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-administration/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Twitter. I have a community there of people I talk with, learn from, it&amp;rsquo;s great. But Twitter also has serious problems that stop everyone from being able to participate in that community. That sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was keen on App.net, when it was around. It never really had the chance to get off the ground, I feel, since they tried a pay model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, a free-and-open-source distributed microblogging service. Sarah Jeong has great things to say in her article &lt;a href="https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/mastodon-is-like-twitter-without-nazis-so-why-are-we-not-using-it"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mastodon Is Like Twitter Without Nazis, So Why Are We Not Using It?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I was intrigued and signed up to one of the more popular instances that Jeong mentioned in her article. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t around too long in &lt;a href="https://awoo.space"&gt;Awoo&lt;/a&gt; before noticing that the existing community was starting to feel uncomfortable with the influx of outsiders. One of the posts said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While queer furries are the &amp;lsquo;old guard&amp;rsquo; of mastodon.social&amp;hellip; here we run the joint. You are in our house, and we expect safety and calm to be the order of the day here. If you want something more lively or tech-y, find another instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still wanna stay? If you behave and respect us, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am 100% on board with respecting people, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want my presence to make anyone feel like their space is not theirs. So I decided I&amp;rsquo;d try to run my own instance for tech folks like me. If you&amp;rsquo;re keen, head over to &lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology"&gt;mastodon.technology&lt;/a&gt; and sign up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the instance took a few hours of configuration (I&amp;rsquo;m not that great at this) and some email providers aren&amp;rsquo;t letting the confirmation emails through (if you don&amp;rsquo;t get an email, &lt;a href="mailto:ash@ashfurrow.com"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ll get you confirmed). I put it on a Heroku hobby plan, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how things go. If costs become a burden, I&amp;rsquo;ll throw up a Patreon or something. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t promise that this instance will be around forever, or ever around next week, but I think that Mastodon&amp;rsquo;s distributed nature makes it a great bet for the future of microblogging (&lt;a href="http://micro.blog"&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; looks promising too). Come hang out, help me build an inclusive community, and have fun. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 01:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RxSwift Book Announcement</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/rxswift-book-announcement/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well well well, look what we have here. After months of toiling in secret, I can finally announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve helped the &lt;a href="https://raywenderlich.com"&gt;Ray Wenderlich team&lt;/a&gt; complete a brand new RxSwift book! &lt;a href="https://store.raywenderlich.com/products/rxswift"&gt;RxSwift: Reactive Programming in Swift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.raywenderlich.com/products/rxswift"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/rxswift-book-announcement/cover.png" alt="Book cover" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been serving as a technical editor to help make sure the book is correct, awesome, and cohesive. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a blast working with Florent Pillet, Junior Bontognali, Marin Todorov, Scott Gardner, and Chris Belanger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been really hard to keep this under wraps, partially because I&amp;rsquo;m so excited about it and partially because people keep asking me for a Swift version of my existing &lt;a href="https://leanpub.com/iosfrp"&gt;Functional Reactive Programming on iOS book&lt;/a&gt;. Well it&amp;rsquo;s finally here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is much more than I could have accomplished on my own, from a team that&amp;rsquo;s used to writing top-notch tutorials. I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of what we accomplished, and I hope you enjoy reading it as much as we enjoyed making it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/rxswift-book-announcement/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Playground Books</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/swift-playground-books/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I wrote about &lt;a href="/blog/building-swift-playground-books/"&gt;Swift Playground Books&lt;/a&gt; and introduced &lt;a href="https://github.com/playgroundbooks/playgroundbook"&gt;a tool&lt;/a&gt; to create them from a regular Xcode playground. There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of work done to the tool by our wonderful contributors, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for an update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a quick overview of &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/swift/playgrounds/"&gt;Swift Playground Books&lt;/a&gt; (for iPad), let&amp;rsquo;s explore what they look like on the file system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/swift-playground-books/structure.png" alt="Structure of a playground book source" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This structure (documented &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/content/documentation/Xcode/Conceptual/swift_playgrounds_doc_format/index.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40017343-CH47-SW4"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) must be strictly adhered to or else the playground book won&amp;rsquo;t work on the iPad. Creating this directory structure and the corresponding manifest plists is tedious, which is why I originally created the tool. Now, compared to the original post, things are much easier to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original format had users writing triple-slash &lt;code&gt;///&lt;/code&gt; comments to delineate playground book pages. Now, chapters are divided into individual Xcode playgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/swift-playground-books/new_structure.png" alt="Structure of a rendered playground book" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual pages within a chapter are represented by Playground pages within Xcode. Use the File -&amp;gt; New menu to add pages. Make sure that the page names are lexicographically ordered in the way you want them to appear in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/swift-playground-books/new_page.png" alt="Adding a new page" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also some cool things you can do with special comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//#-hidden-code&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"This code gets executed but isn't visible in the book."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//#-end-hidden-code&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="kd"&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cm"&gt;/*#-editable-code*/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;funcName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cm"&gt;/*#-end-editable-code*/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"The user will be prompted to edit &amp;lt;#funcName#&amp;gt;"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"This yields a compiler warning in Xcode ¯&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;_(ツ)_/¯"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Play around and see what you think! For more info, check out &lt;a href="https://github.com/playgroundbooks/example"&gt;the example repository&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are bugs in the tool, so if you run into problems please &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/playgroundbook/issues/new"&gt;open an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love open source, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I built this tool (even if I never did end up using it myself). Several students have contacted me for assistance when using it to apply for WWDC scholarships, and it makes my heart swell knowing that people are using my software to advance their own careers. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with the small community that&amp;rsquo;s growing around the tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 15:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/swift-playground-books/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pocket Cruelty</title>
      <link>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/pocket-cruelty/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year when Pokémon Go came out, cultural critic Jonathan McIntosh did what cultural critics do: he pointed out an uncomfortable truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Surprisingly unpopular opinion of the day: I find it unsettling that the ultimate goal of Pokémon Go is to train your cute pets to fight.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jonathan McIntosh (@radicalbytes) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/radicalbytes/status/754147540149219329"&gt;July 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pokémon was a huge part of my childhood – augmented by the nominal determinism of being named &amp;ldquo;Ash&amp;rdquo; – but I don&amp;rsquo;t deny that it&amp;rsquo;s cruel to capture animals and force them to fight. I mean, come on people. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit obvious, if (as McIntosh points out) surprisingly unpopular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the internet being what it is, McIntosh got a bunch of harsh blowback because people are uncomfortable with the idea that something they like could be problematic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s take a detour and talk about my new favourite show: Rick and Morty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricky is a drunk genius who takes his adolescent grandson Morty on adventures through the multiverse. There are actually an infinite amount of Ricks and Mortys, since there are an infinite number of dimensions to exist in. They interact with these alternate versions of themselves and get up to hijinks and in to trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the show, during a hiatus between seasons, released a game that parodied Pokémon: &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/rick-and-morty-pocket-mortys/id992640880?mt=8"&gt;Pocket Mortys&lt;/a&gt;. You play as Rick to collect, train, and fight Mortys. Say again: the game is cockfighting, but with your grandson. And it&amp;rsquo;s super fun.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/pocket-cruelty/pm.png" alt="Pocket Morty's Screenshot" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No one on the Internet seems to have a problem with this uncomfortable truth, even though the game explicitly highlights the same truth that McIntosh did. During fights, Mortys will scream in pain, they&amp;rsquo;ll whimper &amp;ldquo;this just seems really cruel&amp;rdquo;, and they&amp;rsquo;ll exclaim &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do this any more!&amp;rdquo; And it&amp;rsquo;s all part of the fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why does this game get critically reviewed as &amp;ldquo;hilarious&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;quirky&amp;rdquo; while McIntosh gets threatened on twitter – even when both point out the same reality? &lt;a href="http://www.ign.com/articles/2016/01/12/rick-and-morty-pocket-mortys-review"&gt;Pocket Mortys even gets compared directly to Pokémon&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its best moments, Pocket Mortys has a similar feel and tone to its source material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no one seems to care that it&amp;rsquo;s pointing out the cruelty. The game is an explicit parody of Pokémon, and readily points out how cruel it is to fight Mortys. By extension, the game highlights how cruel it is to fight Pokémon. Yet there has been no pushback against the creators of Pocket Mortys, while McIntosh gets threatened on twitter for essentially saying the same thing. What&amp;rsquo;s the difference here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are uncomfortable when something they like gets criticized as problematic. Well&amp;hellip; tough. Your &lt;a href="https://medium.com/matter/admit-it-your-fave-is-problematic-2dfa692f557b"&gt;favs are problematic&lt;/a&gt;. Your favourite game? Problematic. Your favourite book? Problematic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deal. With. It. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m problematic, you&amp;rsquo;re problematic. Everyone is. We all have blind spots – that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make us bad people, it just makes us human. What makes us good or bad people is how we respond to uncomfortable realizations. What do you do when it&amp;rsquo;s pointed out that your favourite game or show or author is problematic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I learned from &lt;a href="https://feministfrequency.com"&gt;Feminist Frequency&lt;/a&gt; is to be critical of the media I love. Pocket Mortys is a fun game, and the show is funny as hell, but in some ways it&amp;rsquo;s suuuuuuper problematic. I can enjoy both the game and the show while being critical of them. I swear, it might be uncomfortable at first, but after a while you get used to liking something while recognizing its flaws. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of critical thinking is useful beyond just media, I would argue it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to be a well-rounded member of society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 14:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/pocket-cruelty/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
