<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Ash Furrow</title>
  <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog</id>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/"/>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-11-11T14:51:29+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ash Furrow</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>It Was Only a Matter of Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/</id>
    <published>2017-11-11T14:51:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-11T14:51:29+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh hey remember that time that I went to a doctor for wrist pain, and they diagnosed me with Carpal Tunnel Syndrome?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Saw a doctor yesterday and they confirmed: carpal tunnel syndrome 😩 Got some physical therapy lined up.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ashley Alonzo Hale Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/778229355956822016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 20, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well. Artsy changed insurance at the end of August, so I had to find a new physiotherapist. I made an appointment with a new clinic because, while I made some progress, my wrists still hurt. I saw a doctor for an exam and they were&amp;hellip; dubious of my diagnosis. They were especially surprised at how long I&amp;rsquo;d been on a physiotherapy regimen without feeling totally better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay nerds: there&amp;rsquo;re two nerves that control the hands and relay sensory information back to the brain: the median nerve and the ulnar nerve. The median nerve goes through your carpal bones in your hand and when those bones compress the nerve, that&amp;rsquo;s carpal tunnel syndrome. This nerve connects to your thumb and your index, middle, and ring fingers. The ulnar nerve is the one exposed in your elbow as your &amp;ldquo;funny bone&amp;rdquo; and connects to your pinky and half your ring finger (the other half is the median nerve).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So they did an EMG to see what was up with my nerves. See, my symptoms are wrist pain and numbness in my pinky/ring fingers, so Carpal Tunnel Syndrome is kind of a weird diagnosis. The EMG confirmed that my nerve responses are fine, which is good news! I don&amp;rsquo;t actually have Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s going on then? Turns out that, in concert with how all office furniture is too short for my 188cm stature, my bad posture was causing me to lean forward and apply pressure on the underside of my forearms. That&amp;rsquo;s where my ulnar nerve is. I&amp;rsquo;ve since noticed that I do this a lot, especially while typing. There is also some shoulder pain that is being referred down my nerve, so I feel wrist pain but the source of the pain is in my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I&amp;rsquo;d sought a second opinion earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since starting physiotherapy four weeks ago, the pain is gone from both wrists and the numbness is gone from my right hand (still working on the left, but it&amp;rsquo;s improving). The therapy has mostly concentrated on strengthening scapular muscles to help my posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyways. I was chatting with Orta on the walk home about all this, and how I&amp;rsquo;d felt left out of the Apple Watch hoorah since watches aggravate my wrist pain (and have for years). But since I&amp;rsquo;m making such great progress, maybe I&amp;rsquo;d look into getting an Apple Watch. He mentions that Artsy still has a first-generation test device, it&amp;rsquo;s at his apartment, and why don&amp;rsquo;t I come fetch it and say hello to his new puppy?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Ba_1zPNDXn_/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by Murphy (@murphys&lt;em&gt;paw&lt;/em&gt;nyc)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-11-02T15:14:46+00:00"&gt;Nov 2, 2017 at 8:14am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obviously I said yes; the puppy alone makes it worth climbing three flights of stairs. But the point is, I tried out the Apple Watch for a while and I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you might remember that when the watch was first announced, I was&amp;hellip; &lt;a href="/blog/crestfallen/"&gt;less than enthused&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty skeptical, but whatever. It was no risk to me to try it out. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it, or if it started hurting my wrists, no problem: I give it back to Artsy to sit in a drawer forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after upgrading the device to watchOS 4 (which was it&amp;rsquo;s own thing) I started wearing it. Not many of the apps I used have watchOS extensions, but I found the built-in support for Activity and stuff pretty cool! I like getting more in-depth data about myself and the gentle encouragement throughout the day was really nice. I also re-enabled some iOS push notifications so I&amp;rsquo;d have an excuse to use it more, to give it a fair chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy with the first-gen watch but I could definitely see it strain under the weight of, well, of anything.  And I discovered that I need to wear it on my right wrist, at least for now, because my left one is still recovering and the watch irritated it. I also discovered I&amp;rsquo;d been wearing wristwatches wrong my whole life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;[poll] So I may have been wearing wristwatches wrong my whole life. They apparently go above the wrist bone and not on top of this wrist where it flexes? Sound of in the comments hey&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ashley Alonzo Hale Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/928283229068644353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks on Twitter told me to get a contemporary model but I wanted to get a feel for it first. Well I finally did get one of my own, a Series 3 (without cellular, you monsters), and it&amp;rsquo;s great! A &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2hlM5Do"&gt;knockoff watchband from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; helped it look snazzy and provide more granular adjustments, which I really like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upgrade from first-gen to Series 3 is&amp;hellip; well it&amp;rsquo;s quite a leap. UI transitions that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think were animated on the old device were actually just really, really laggy. So the new one is a big improvement! I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only problem has been the dearth of apps for the Apple Watch, even a few years on. The apps that &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have watchOS extensions are hit-or-miss. &lt;em&gt;OmniFocus&lt;/em&gt; is probably a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; example of an extension done well: a thoughtful subset of functionality with an easy UI. Other apps, like &lt;em&gt;Airmail&lt;/em&gt;, go all-in on feature parity with their iOS apps, which is a bit excessive in my opinion. And some apps, like &lt;em&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/em&gt;, offer a kind of in-between where the functionality is limited but in ways I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with. So who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some games even designed specifically with the watch in mind, like &lt;em&gt;Pocket Bandit&lt;/em&gt; where you use the digital crown and haptic feedback to crack open locked safes. And there are some that take advantage of how infrequently/briefly users check their watches, like &lt;em&gt;Lifeline&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m on the lookout for more of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting a watch has also stirred within me something I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt towards native apps for a long time: a desire to build something new and the resulting search for a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I wanna make an apple watch app that uses the accelerator etc to do like an exercise monitor but for petting cats 😹&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ashley Alonzo Hale Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/929340577291923458?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it may have been premature for me to dump on the watch (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/st607cjBit/"&gt;oops&lt;/a&gt;). But I get the impression that the hardware and software are still not really reaching their full potential. I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s similar to the iPhone 3GS in that regard: getting closer, but still a ways off from what it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be. What it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing how the device and ecosystem evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>So I Have Been Struggling</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-i-have-been-struggling/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-i-have-been-struggling/</id>
    <published>2017-11-04T15:02:21+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-04T15:02:21+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; update time I guess. I&amp;rsquo;m kind of writing this for me to help me work through some stuff, and it&amp;rsquo;s probably not that interesting. But I&amp;rsquo;m putting it on my blog so that others can see that &lt;a href="/blog/normalizing-struggle/"&gt;struggle is normal&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully realize that they are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past August had me feeling happier than I&amp;rsquo;ve been since roughly 2011, when I graduated university, got married, and moved to Toronto. In university, I had struggled with depression but I had overcome it with talk therapy. I felt great in 2011, and I think I felt that great in August. I even got to enjoy a vacation back home to see my family before things changed suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was taking two medications: an SNRI and another &amp;ldquo;booster&amp;rdquo; drug that augments the SNRI. It was the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; combination for me, it worked &lt;em&gt;so well&lt;/em&gt;. I had even &lt;a href="/blog/therapys-end/"&gt;stopped going to therapy&lt;/a&gt; because I had worked through what I needed to work through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well see the problem is that the booster I was on has an uncommon complication. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly rare, and I was on a very low dose, but I had been told to watch out for certain signs of this complication. This neurological complication. This complication that often is permanent and persists for the rest of one&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped taking the booster at the very end of August. I knew what withdrawal from this drug would feel like, I&amp;rsquo;d been through it a few times. It starts out seeming like it won&amp;rsquo;t be so bad: a few weeks of no change at all, but then a sudden and steep drop in my mood. Drop in my appetite. Drop in hobbies. In motivation to work. Motivation to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke with my psychiatrist and the next step we&amp;rsquo;d settled on was to use a different booster, one that I had used before and had seen &lt;em&gt;partial&lt;/em&gt; improvement with. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly conventional approach and I wanted to pursue this before trying something more radical: a change to my main anti-depressant. From an SNRI to, something else. I&amp;rsquo;m nervous about this option.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BbEu3vmA3DM/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-11-04T12:50:25+00:00"&gt;Nov 4, 2017 at 5:50am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Artsy changed insurance providers at the end of August and my old therapist was no longer in my health insurance network. And he&amp;rsquo;s more of a psychoanalyst than someone who could help me with coping strategies in the moments when I&amp;rsquo;m feeling hopeless. What I need is a Cognitive Behavioural Therapist. My psychiatrist had offered to help me find someone specializing in CBT. I was secretly resistant to this idea for, I don&amp;rsquo;t know, really dumb reasons. Rationales that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t shared with my psychiatrist or my wife, Ashley. After talking it through with Ashley, I decided to find a new therapist. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s kind of where I am right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to my psychiatrist for a checkup to see how I was feeling on the alternate booster (these drugs take weeks-to-months to &amp;ldquo;kick in&amp;rdquo;). I told her: I&amp;rsquo;m feeling better, I guess. I can concentrate more easily, I manage to get showered and leave the house every day, which is a big improvement from when I crashed mid-September. But I still felt totally flat, &lt;a href="/blog/depression-graphed/"&gt;unable to experience any emotion&lt;/a&gt;. She was getting concerned that the conventional booster wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be effective and started discussing an aggressive change in my primary anti-depressant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See&amp;hellip; psychiatrists all have these little questionnaires that measures changes in different symptoms of depression. Things like mood, appetite, sleeping patterns, interest in activities, and of course, thoughts of suicide. I took the usual questionnaire and my results were only a &lt;em&gt;slight&lt;/em&gt; improvement from September. Not promising. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My psychiatrist noticed that one score on one questionnaire had significantly worsened, a really important question. And so I got to have &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; conversation. You know the one, right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;And how often would you say that you think about ending your life?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s quite a lot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you have access to any firearms?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you think you would do if you decided to act on these thoughts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always hate this conversation. I feel so ashamed of myself. I know I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t but I do. I feel like a dog getting its nose rubbed into a mess it&amp;rsquo;s made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation continues. I answer a question with vague euphemisms. They re-ask the question, reworded so I can&amp;rsquo;t wiggle out of it with an &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; and a hapless shrug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I don&amp;rsquo;t even why I&amp;rsquo;m afraid of switching medications. It just seems scary. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;ll get worse I guess. But I&amp;rsquo;ve kind of realized that though it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; make things worse in the near-term, my current prescription isn&amp;rsquo;t healthy or sustainable. I have an appointment next week where I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss crossfading between prescriptions and the associated blood work (ugh).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird, but, I&amp;rsquo;m kind in better spirits now that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to be more aggressive with medication. I guess I was kind of ashamed, but talking through things Ashley and another friend helped me realize that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to feel that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking helped improve my mood in the short term and I hope or believe I guess that it&amp;rsquo;ll improve things in the long term too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend and yours, Orta, had spoken highly of &lt;a href="https://www.blueapron.com"&gt;Blue Apron&lt;/a&gt; on several occasions. I was really interested but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t pursued it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, my appetite is pretty low right now. I have to remind myself to eat and if I forget, my mood drops significant. And my motivation to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; things was &lt;em&gt;verrrrrrry&lt;/em&gt; limited. So I was eating pretty poorly because it is &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; easier to microwave another frozen dinner or order food using the internet than it is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan what to eat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of things I need to buy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go outside and buy them (or, more likely, order them using the internet).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare the food in the tiny kitchen that I share with my roommates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is a real fucking shame because I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; to cook. I used to anyways. Here&amp;rsquo;s me in university 2010 cooking for a community breakfast that I&amp;rsquo;d organized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-i-have-been-struggling/pancakes.jpg" alt="Me making pancakes" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to Toronto was like, the peak of my enjoyment of cooking. Actually, it was and remains the most joyous part of my life. I had a &lt;em&gt;kickass&lt;/em&gt; kitchen and bought all kinds of doodads to make all kinds of food. I started experimenting with baking, even making goddamn &lt;em&gt;macarons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to Amsterdam put up a lot of barriers to me enjoying cooking. Barriers like a totally different grocery store where everything is in a totally different language and cashiers assume you speak Dutch, and folks interact according to very different customs. Barriers like this weren&amp;rsquo;t by themselves a problem but after moving to Amsterdam I ran out of anti-depressants and struggled to find reliable medical help. I didn&amp;rsquo;t cook anymore, my appetite was gone, I was feeling suicidal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Footnote: the time I was feeling the lowest coincided with my first few months with Artsy, and I was really worried that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t performing adequately enough. Artsy colleagues, and Orta in particular, were a reliable source of validation. It got me through some tough times.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to New York reduced a lot of the barriers to cooking I&amp;rsquo;d had in Amsterdam, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really in the habit anymore. Plus there are &lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt; cool takeout places around the city to try out. Well, to order over the internet. Anyway, the point is I haven&amp;rsquo;t really cooked since Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve come to rely upon in New York while I&amp;rsquo;ve been depressed in the past few years are, like, &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; bougie. The part of me that wants to buy off-brand Kraft Dinner to save thirty cents is in utter conflict with the part of me that is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; into doing my laundry online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt ashamed of paying extra for convenience. Ashley had explained that, logistically, it makes more sense to pay a little extra for conveniences than to languish without the basics of living. That made sense, and was the kind of justification that I&amp;rsquo;d used when I felt bad about things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Blue Apron. It was something that I had felt ashamed of even considering. But after Orta helped connect the dots for me that Blue Apron could &lt;em&gt;remove the barriers to cooking&lt;/em&gt;, I brought it up with Ashley. She&amp;rsquo;s handled everything to get us set up (aside from carrying the heavy box up four flights of stairs).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BbDyar7BFhp/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by Ashley Furrow (@ashleyfurrow)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-11-04T04:02:10+00:00"&gt;Nov 3, 2017 at 9:02pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been three weeks now and I. Am. Loving. It. Blue Apron has brought some joy back into my life while I struggle through all the shit I&amp;rsquo;m going through right now. It reminded me that &lt;em&gt;I like to cook&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that hard stuff? The planning and grocery lists and going to store and cleaning the kitchen? Well I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten, but I like that too. Yesterday, I noticed an &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; grocery store literally on my walk home. It excited me. I went in, planned not one, but two meals! I had a goddamn &lt;em&gt;conversation&lt;/em&gt; with the cashier about what I was planning to cook and &lt;em&gt;I enjoyed it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not completely at ease with my feelings about the modern conveniences of New York and the internet. Maybe parts of me will always be at odds: a struggle between rigid parsimony and practical indulgence. But embracing convenience and starting Blue Apron sparked something with me. It re-ignited a source of joy for me, and is responsible for a much-needed reprieve from the things I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have realized that the most effective solutions to my problems &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; involve talking it through with someone. It&amp;rsquo;s a mix of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rubber_duck_debugging"&gt;Rubber Duck debugging&lt;/a&gt; but for emotions, and advice from trusted friends. It came down to talking, but I had to be honest and I usually had to start the conversation. That was really hard. Like, &lt;em&gt;the hardest thing&lt;/em&gt;. But I did it. I worked up the courage for days and finally sprung a conversation about suicidal ideation on my unsuspecting wife while seated in a bustling café. But it worked, and I felt &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with the kinds of problems I&amp;rsquo;m having, I want you to try talking to someone you trust about how you&amp;rsquo;re feeling. Please. I promise that you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; worth the struggle it will be to ask: &amp;ldquo;can we talk?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Perspective of the Polyglot</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/perspective-of-the-polyglot/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/perspective-of-the-polyglot/</id>
    <published>2017-10-14T02:09:25+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-14T02:09:25+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2015, &lt;a href="/blog/building-my-career/"&gt;I wrote&lt;/a&gt; about my next steps in &lt;a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/04/03/artsy-engineering-compensation-framework/"&gt;Artsy&amp;rsquo;s engineering career ladder&lt;/a&gt;. I laid out the steps that I would be focusing on, like multiplying effectiveness of cross-team work and having an obvious technical impact on the team&amp;rsquo;s strategic trajectory. I&amp;rsquo;ve made progress on these points, to varying degrees, but that&amp;rsquo;s not what I want to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then, after listing all the things I wanted to focus on, I casually mention some other items that I&amp;rsquo;d skipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other, more technical things like &amp;ldquo;own a large scale and impact service&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I maybe treated these &amp;ldquo;technical things&amp;rdquo; as though they were inevitable and would just happen on their own. But just like the community-oriented qualifications, technical skills are things that I need to consciously practice to improve at. To some extent, I might have neglected them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I made occasional contributions (mostly in Ruby), I built new open source tools (mostly in Ruby), I even rewrote my website (in Ruby). I stayed in my comfort zone – heck, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even learn Rails!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That changed about a year ago, when I talked to my manager about breaking outside of the iOS developer box. I told him that I wanted to contribute to mission-critical backend systems, to help build web frontends written in new languages, to experiment with unproven technologies and evaluate their applications at Artsy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a slow process. I haven&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; been learning new things, I&amp;rsquo;ve also been helping other team members contribute to Artsy&amp;rsquo;s iOS code. I can&amp;rsquo;t just leave the iOS codebases – I have responsibilities. I was doing things like pairing on our Scala codebase, which was totally new to me, while also pairing on our iOS codebases, which I helped write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My progress was stunted at times by setbacks in my depression treatment. Sometimes I would take one step forward and two steps back. That sucked. I made progress where I could and tried to accept that developing new skills takes time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributions to non-iOS codebases were minor at first: arduous pull requests that changed some button&amp;rsquo;s text or added some field to a model object. Simple stuff. I was making contributions, but each one was a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, things have been different. I started making contributions to a few distinct projects a week. Then a few distinct projects a day. I sought out exposure to building new-to-me kinds of software, with new-to-me practices and new-to-me conventions. It was hard. It sucked. It ruled. I doubted myself a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the upside, learning language after framework after methodology helped develop my intuition and pattern-recognition. I can more quickly recognize the similarities and differences between different types of software. Now, I can jump into a new project and pretty quickly make meaningful contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It. Feels. Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take this week: I released a new version of Artsy&amp;rsquo;s main iOS app, helped profile and limit GraphQL request complexity, tuned server logging, worked on a new feature in a Rails app, undertook a refactor in a Scala backend – all while keeping on top of my responsibilities in the open source community. Cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what? Well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s perspective that comes with experience in different programming languages. Not just languages: systems, communities, and contexts. For example, when I step into another programming community, I have the opportunity to look back and see the iOS developer community from a distance. Sometimes I really like what I see. Sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t. I try to &lt;a href="/blog/apple-releases-jive/"&gt;bring that perspective back&lt;/a&gt; with me and improve things. Perspective makes you do that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://science.nasa.gov/science-news/science-at-nasa/2013/23jul_palebluedot"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/perspective-of-the-polyglot/bluedot.jpg" alt="Bluedot" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The more I learn, the more I realize I have to learn. I make progress only to learn that the goal – my vision of an idealized developer – is even further away than I thought. Like Zeno, I&amp;rsquo;ll never make it to a finish line. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that feeling will ever change, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning to accept the fact that the finish line doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist: &lt;a href="/blog/the-journey-is-the-reward/"&gt;the journey is the reward&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Due Diligence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/due-diligence/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/due-diligence/</id>
    <published>2017-10-08T16:04:31+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-08T16:04:31+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay so yesterday I wrote a &lt;a href="/blog/apple-releases-jive/"&gt;hypothetical blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a new testing framework that Apple made. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of feedback – more than I expected, honestly. Developers really care about their tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One piece of criticism I received is that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t filed any bug reports with Apple asking for these features. I did include a link to &lt;a href="http://bugreport.apple.com"&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s bug reporter&lt;/a&gt; and asked people to file radars, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t provide any radars to duplicate. That was an oversight on my part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s some due diligence: I have filed eleven radars with Apple asking for individual features that would each enhance the developer experience. They have all been cross-posted to &lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/"&gt;Open Radar&lt;/a&gt;, so please feel free to duplicate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=4928269132496896"&gt;34875844 Xcode&amp;rsquo;s unit testing framework should include a mocking library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=5060966442074112"&gt;34875826 Hot Module Reloading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=4970395111260160"&gt;34875798 Open source Xcode, or make a new OSS Xcode Lite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=5011363730554880"&gt;34875762 Run unit tests in parallel processes/simulators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=5055377615880192"&gt;34875753 Xcode unit testing should support Behaviour-Driven Development workflows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=6135499479580672"&gt;34875723 Matchers that ship with Xcode&amp;rsquo;s testing framework could be improved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=5025044409352192"&gt;34875713 Xcode should schedule failing tests to run first&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=4959620246274048"&gt;34873674 Xcode should only run tests related to files changed since the last commit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=6063405903380480"&gt;34873507 Add a test-on-save feature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=4937505996537856"&gt;34873492 Unit tests always run in the same order, but should be randomized&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=5001137547640832"&gt;34876469 Isolate global state between tests by isolating tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; feature requests that I&amp;rsquo;m bringing from other communities – mainly Ruby and JavaScript. I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LtrzZb5Jw0g"&gt;asking developers to bring ideas from other communities since Swift was in beta&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to ask me to follow my own advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What features would make your day-to-day life as a developer easier, or more joyful?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Releases Jive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/apple-releases-jive/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/apple-releases-jive/</id>
    <published>2017-10-07T14:55:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-07T14:55:08+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following is a hypothetical blog post, written by a version of me in a parallel universe. In this fictional world, Apple cares very much about software quality (ensured by unit testing), as well as the developer experience of building software for its platforms. The features I describe of Apple&amp;rsquo;s new fictional test runner are all real features in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/facebook/jest"&gt;Jest project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, what a WWDC! Lots of stuff to get excited about, but what&amp;rsquo;s got me most pumped up is the release of Apple&amp;rsquo;s new unit testing tool: Jive. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what Jive is, how it makes your life as an iOS developer easier, and how it helps you write better software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First some theory. Unit testing generally has three components: a test runner, which runs your tests; a test framework, which is how you structure your tests; and a matcher library, which helps you write test assertions. Jive provides the whole package: it&amp;rsquo;s a test runner, a test framework, and a matcher library. Let&amp;rsquo;s go through each component in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="test-runner"&gt;Test Runner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jive&amp;rsquo;s test runner is seriously impressive. Apple has examined the workflow that developers – inside Apple and within the community – and has optimized Jive for common workflows. The top priority of Jive is to give accurate test results as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s say you check out a new branch to work on a feature. Jive is going to use git to determine which Swift files and which tests have changed since the last commit. Running fewer tests will speed up the test suite run time. And whenever you save a file, Jive examines the dependency graph and re-runs all related tests, giving you near instant feedback in your red/green/refactor cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jive prioritizes running tests that failed the last time it ran because it assumes that you&amp;rsquo;re trying to fix those tests first. It also keeps track of how long each test takes to run, in order to prioritize long-running tests &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt;. This reduces overall test time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/apple-releases-jive/length.png" alt="Before and after running long tests first" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the improved scheduling of long-running tests improved full test suite run times by 20% – wow! And because it can run tests in parallel simulator processes (from Xcode 9), parallelism is constrained only by the number of cores in your CPU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Jive provides a fast testing experience, using advanced dependency resolution techniques and aggressive caching so that incremental changes take less than a second to test. This near-instant feedback is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; change in how we can write code. Since tests take a very short time to run, developers run them more often (on file saves, in a pre-commit hook, etc). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On full test runs, Jive is still stunningly fast, reducing test suite run times with XCTest to about 15% of their original run times. Very impressive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="test-framework"&gt;Test Framework&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XCTest provided a very bare-bones approach to testing, something reminiscent of JUnit circa 1999. In contrast, Jive provides a modern RSpec-like interface for behaviour-driven development. Let&amp;rsquo;s compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;MyTests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;XCTestCase&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;override&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;setUp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;setUp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;override&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;tearDown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;tearDown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kd"&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;testExample&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="c1"&gt;// TODO&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay now let see an equivalent Jive test suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;beforeEach&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;afterEach&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nf"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"behaves a certain way"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="c1"&gt;// TODO&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What may not be obvious about RSpec-style tests is the possibility of &lt;em&gt;nesting contexts&lt;/em&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at a more practical example to see the power of nesting test contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;db&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;DataBase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;beforeEach&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;db&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;DataBase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;testDataBase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;afterEach&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;db&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;destroy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nf"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"adds new rows to the db"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nf"&gt;describe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"prepopulated"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;beforeEach&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;db&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;populateWithFakeData&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"can fetch rows from the db"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of nested contexts was impossible to build in XCTest (at least, without a lot of work and/or repeated code). Finally Apple has recognized that a test suite needs more than just two &lt;code&gt;setup()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tearDown()&lt;/code&gt; methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jive leverages its new runner with the RSpec-style tests to run each test in an independent process. This means that state leftover from one test can&amp;rsquo;t affect the outcome of another test. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Jest provides an interface for testing that lends itself to writing more expressive tests. It reminds me of &lt;a href="https://github.com/Quick/Quick"&gt;Quick&lt;/a&gt;, the Swift test framework that&amp;rsquo;s now been sherlocked by Jive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="matchers"&gt;Matchers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XCTest matchers were&amp;hellip; not optimal. Matchers are used by the assertions of a test, so making them concise and expressive is really important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;XCTAssertEqual&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;objectA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;objectB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s compare with the new Jive matchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;objectA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;equal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;objectB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// or&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;objectA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;objectB&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jive uses operator overloading to help write more expressive tests. I really dig this – it lets developers choose whatever level of verbosity they feel is right for their project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at a few more examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;~=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;beNil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can write your own matchers, too, and leverage the power of the Swift type system. For example, it&amp;rsquo;d be pretty easy to write a custom matcher to check that collections are of a certain size. I&amp;rsquo;ll likely port my &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/Nimble-Snapshots"&gt;Nimble-Snapshots&lt;/a&gt; library over to Jive within the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course Jive ships with a comprehensive mocking library. This makes mocking dependencies and injecting them into a subject under test &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; easy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"invokes the callback"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;Jive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;testSubject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;method&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;haveBeenCalledWith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nf"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"calls the network"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;Jive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;Alamofire&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;testSubject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;networkModel&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;testSubject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;fetch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nf"&gt;expect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;mock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;haveBeenCalledWith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"https://example.com"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very cool, and all out of the box! Mocking is a testing strategy that Objective-C and Swift developers aren&amp;rsquo;t too familiar with, but it &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/3623574/516359"&gt;solves a lot of problems&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this powerful testing technique become more popular within our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="wrap-up"&gt;Wrap up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has released Jive as an open source Xcode extension, written in Swift. This means that any Swift developer can contribute back to the project, helping to improve everyone&amp;rsquo;s developer experience. After releasing the &lt;a href="https://swift.org/blog/swift-local-refactoring/"&gt;Swift refactoring tools&lt;/a&gt; as open source last year, it&amp;rsquo;s exciting to see Apple continue this trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Xcode ships with everything an iOS developer needs to write comprehensive unit tests. Apple really put a concerted effort into making Jive an industry-leading test runner, and I thank them for recognizing how important unit testing is to making quality software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Jive doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. It&amp;rsquo;s up to iOS developers to seek out better testing tools than the ones we&amp;rsquo;re given by Apple, and most folks don&amp;rsquo;t bother. And because Xcode is &lt;a href="http://isxcodeopensourceyet.github.io"&gt;closed source&lt;/a&gt;, the community can&amp;rsquo;t contribute back to improve their own tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why haven&amp;rsquo;t Apple done this? Priorities. Apple has the engineering talent to make this a reality, but they have other priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to suggest that making Jive would be easy. Imagine: you hit &amp;ldquo;save&amp;rdquo; and Xcode has to determine which files have changed, recompile them, load them into a runtime, and execute them. That alone would take a lot of engineering effort, and only a few companies exist that could invest the time. And only Apple can contribute to Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Apple cares more about writing modern unit tests, or until they get tired of us &lt;a href="/blog/due-diligence/"&gt;filing radars&lt;/a&gt; asking for better tools, we&amp;rsquo;ll likely never see Jive come to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekend Hack Project: Twelease</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/node-express-typescript/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/node-express-typescript/</id>
    <published>2017-10-01T19:28:28+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-01T19:28:28+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using technologies like &lt;a href="http://nodejs.org"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://expressjs.com"&gt;Express&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org"&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; at Artsy for a while now, contributing new features or fixing bugs to various codebases. But I haven&amp;rsquo;t ever gone through the full process of having an idea, starting a new project, building a minimum-deployable-product, and shipping it off to a server. I was less prepared for this than I&amp;rsquo;d thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I give an overview of steps I followed, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a tutorial. It is a reflection on the contrasts between the iOS developer experience and the JavaScript developer experience. All the code is &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/twelease"&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like using small projects to learn new things. Limited-scope projects are great to build without getting too overwhelmed by complexity. An open source project &lt;a href="https://github.com/danger/danger-js/issues/332"&gt;wanted to tweet when they pushed a new GitHub tag&lt;/a&gt;; only slightly more complicated than an IFTTT rule, perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where to start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, after opening Xcode and selecting a project template, you have an entire app. You can compile and run it as-is and there&amp;rsquo;s tonnes of helpful comments about where to add certain pieces of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no Xcode for JavaScript, so how you decide to build your app is &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; up to you. It can be difficult to choose a methodology because there is an entire community of strong opinions about how to build software. And while projects like &lt;a href="https://github.com/react-community/create-react-native-app"&gt;Create React Native App&lt;/a&gt; offer an equivalent experience of a new project template, what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is that the frameworks you use in JavaScript are only the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m using Express, but I prefer using a strong type system. No problem, I&amp;rsquo;ll use TypeScript! Okay, so now I have to integrate an entire build system into my workflows for developing, testing, and deploying, and holy shit I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used Express before, but I copy/pasted a basic Hello, World project anyway. Then I found &lt;a href="https://github.com/Gisonrg/express-github-webhook"&gt;a library&lt;/a&gt; that provides middleware to process and verify GitHub webhook events. Great! Let&amp;rsquo;s smash the two together, LHC-style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I work, I&amp;rsquo;m getting tired of building, then running, my code. So I add &lt;a href="https://gulpjs.com"&gt;Gulp&lt;/a&gt; to watch the filesystem and re-run the TypeScript compiler whenever I change &lt;code&gt;.ts&lt;/code&gt; files. I also specify an output directory of &lt;code&gt;dist&lt;/code&gt; because that seems to be what everyone else does. (&lt;code&gt;dist&lt;/code&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t checked in to git, it&amp;rsquo;s basically like your Xcode app archives.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gulp is configured via execution of &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/twelease/blob/master/gulpfile.js"&gt;&lt;code&gt;gulpfile.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - like a Gemfile or Podfile, while TypeScript is configured through &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/twelease/blob/master/tsconfig.json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Quirky difference – but it makes sense. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how flexible all the tools are – you can configure tools on the command line, through config files, or through environment variables. The easiest is through the config files, but they all need to be strictly valid JSON. The strictness of JSON was a bit frustrating, to be honest, especially the lack of comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also needed to get fancy about how Heroku gets deployed by adding &lt;code&gt;[&amp;quot;types&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;node&amp;quot;]]&lt;/code&gt; to my TypeScript config. Oh, and also a &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/twelease/blob/1f233ba4aa8004958379e073232cc9b72b395c47/package.json#L41"&gt;&lt;code&gt;postinstall&lt;/code&gt; script&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, the TypeScript compilation would fail on Heroku. And I wanted to compile the TypeScript &lt;em&gt;on deploy&lt;/em&gt; and not as part of the server startup. Oh, and I made sure Heroku&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Procfile&lt;/code&gt; points to the &lt;code&gt;dist&lt;/code&gt; directory&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;index.js&lt;/code&gt; (which is the compiled version of &lt;code&gt;src/index.ts&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your background, these details might seem either so trivial as to be hardly worth mentioning, or so complex that you might feel overwhelmed. And with no community authority like Apple providing a clear path for beginners, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to get stuck on random configuration problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I also happen to disagree with a lot of Apple&amp;rsquo;s vision for how to develop software. Not just methodology, like MVC, but also build tools. For instance, Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://isxcodeopensourceyet.github.io"&gt;Xcode IDE is closed source&lt;/a&gt;, and has very minimal support for extensions. Many community projects, like &lt;a href="https://github.com/realm/SwiftLint"&gt;swiftlint&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/jpsim/SourceKitten"&gt;sourcekitten&lt;/a&gt;, do help improve the iOS development experience, but iOS developers tend to rely exclusively on Apple tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the JS tooling ecosystem is alive with a variety of linters, type-checkers, formatters, file watchers, test runners, and more. Yes, it is a little overwhelming, and yes, your initial project setup is a lot harder than a new project template from Xcode, but the JS community seems to believe that a little extra upfront work is well worth improving the development experience long term. Having worked in both the iOS and JS ecosystems, I&amp;rsquo;m inclined to agree with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than just a variety of tools is the size of the community that builds them. Because JavaScript developers mainly use tools written &lt;em&gt;in JavaScript&lt;/em&gt;, the initial barrier of contributing to those tools is enormously lowered. The community empowers its members to improve the shared tooling, and the results are spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Let’s flip the tables: how empowering would it feel if your app’s API was written in Swift? You’d be able to fix your own bugs, add features&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Pablo Picasghost👻 (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/914247587984687104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 30, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cycle of compiling Swift/Objective-C to run unit tests adds a lot of time to my iOS development process. It takes time to compile, install, and run tests. If you have to wait fifteen seconds to see if your code works, you won&amp;rsquo;t check as often. In contrast, &lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com"&gt;VSCode&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://facebook.github.io/jest/"&gt;Jest&lt;/a&gt; make testing &lt;em&gt;unbelievably fast&lt;/em&gt;. Using Jest to test fundamentally changed how I write code, and I miss the near-instant feedback cycle when I return to iOS native development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JavaScript community moves at a blistering pace. That means I can&amp;rsquo;t just learn the current JS syntax because most tutorials, StackOverflow answers, and blog posts use older syntaxes that I also need to learn. For example, dependencies used to be loaded into a file with &lt;code&gt;require()&lt;/code&gt; but now most folks seem to use &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt;. But &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t work for me in the Node REPL, I had to still use &lt;code&gt;require&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I really dig about JavaScript is how you import all your dependencies explicitly; you import specifically &amp;ldquo;exported&amp;rdquo; functions and such from modules. Some modules export named functions, while other modules export a &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; function. Some do both. Here are a few examples of how to import stuff in JS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight javascript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;info&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;error&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'./lib/loggers'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kr"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;auth&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'auth'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kr"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;tweet&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'./twitter'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all makes sense to read, but I still don&amp;rsquo;t have the mechanics internalized enough to write the syntax right on the first try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One neat thing I like about working in Artsy&amp;rsquo;s JS codebases is their use of git pre-commit hooks. Often, these hooks will lint and reformat your code for you to adhere to the repo&amp;rsquo;s standard. Or maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll run any tests related to your staged changes. Very handy stuff for catching mistakes earlier in the development process. For whatever reason, automatic code formatters just haven&amp;rsquo;t been popular among iOS developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I have my app set up and working, but with all the experimentation with tools and frameworks, I&amp;rsquo;m certain that I&amp;rsquo;ve left in some orphaned configuration or dependencies that I no longer need. Or maybe I have some developer dependencies in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/twelease/blob/master/package.json"&gt;&lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt;. Or some leftover &lt;code&gt;scripts&lt;/code&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to accumulate all this stuff. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll go shake it out. If you see anything funky &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/twelease"&gt;in the repo&lt;/a&gt;, let me know in an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have a few mysteries I&amp;rsquo;m looking to solve, like precisely how &lt;code&gt;es-lint&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ts-lint&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;prettier&lt;/code&gt; relate to one another. Stuff like that, quirks I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed or other common knowledge that people don&amp;rsquo;t tend to write blog posts about. I&amp;rsquo;ve still got a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JavaScript and iOS developer communities are very different places. iOS developers have Apple setting the vision for how to build apps, whereas JS developers have an &lt;em&gt;overwhelming&lt;/em&gt; number of options. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I can work in both communities – I like and dislike things about each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial setup of the project, toolchain, and workflows was difficult enough to frustrate me a few times. It will be a lot easier next time. But the improved development workflow makes writing software way easier, way faster, and way more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of this has resonated with you, Mozilla has some &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/Server-side/Express_Nodejs"&gt;comprehensive documentation&lt;/a&gt; around setting up a development environment to write a &lt;code&gt;Hello, World&lt;/code&gt; app in Express. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about TypeScript for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of something you&amp;rsquo;d like to build, and try to build it. Make sure your idea is really easy, because building it will probably actually be hard, and you might not finish, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay because you&amp;rsquo;ll have learned a lot. Hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll have some fun. I sure did.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
