<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Ash Furrow</title>
  <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog</id>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/"/>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-03-09T22:39:02+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ash Furrow</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Mood Improvements</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mood-improvements/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mood-improvements/</id>
    <published>2018-03-09T22:39:02+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-09T22:39:02+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay so it&amp;rsquo;s been over a month since I &lt;a href="/blog/progress-and-pianos/"&gt;last checked in&lt;/a&gt; about how my mood was doing. It&amp;rsquo;s better! But I have this habit of believing that everything is improving because I feel good &lt;em&gt;at the moment&lt;/em&gt;, despite continued problems in my mood. So I&amp;rsquo;ll go to my psychiatrist and she&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rsquo;ve you been this week?&amp;rdquo; and I&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;great!&amp;rdquo; because I feel good &lt;em&gt;at that moment&lt;/em&gt;, and it prevents me from acknowledging the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this time, I have data! My friend Felix wrote a &lt;a href="https://github.com/KrauseFx/mood"&gt;small Telegram app&lt;/a&gt; that texts you three times a day to ask how you&amp;rsquo;re feeling. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mood-improvements/screenshot.png" alt="A screenshot of the app I'm using to track my mood" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been particularly keen to see the data over the past week, since I just today have my second weekly session with a new therapist. Last Friday, she gave me some exercises to practice my observation skills, and encouraged me to begin meditating again. With the help of &lt;a href="https://www.headspace.com"&gt;Headspace&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meditating twice a day: once in the morning and once in mid-afternoon in Artsy&amp;rsquo;s meditation room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so on to the data. I started collecting it just over a month ago, so I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few weeks before starting therapy and meditation, and a week afterwards. I&amp;rsquo;ve marked on the image below when I started, and the data is available in plaintext format &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/ashfurrow/752aab4da069076ad893a88cc2a983a0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for people with visual impairments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mood-improvements/mood.png" alt="A graph of my mood over the past month" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Okay, nice. So things were pretty turbulent there before begining therapy. Mostly bouncing around 3 (good, alright) and (down, worried). There are three dips down to 0 (miserable, nervous), which represent, uh, very very bad moods where I felt at my lowest. With all that is implied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hey look! For the past week, my mood has been almost entirely 3 (good, alright) or 4 (happy, excited)! Awesome news. I finally feel like things might be improving &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; I have the data to back up that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to track your mood with software, you have a few options. There&amp;rsquo;s the app I&amp;rsquo;m using that I linked to earlier, as well as &lt;a href="https://expo.io/@kkemple/hwyd"&gt;HWYD&lt;/a&gt;, detailed in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@kurtiskemple/introducing-hwyd-an-app-for-graphing-depression-442a508c2016"&gt;this awesome blog post&lt;/a&gt; and is &lt;a href="https://github.com/kkemple/hwyd"&gt;also open source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Progress and Pianos</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/progress-and-pianos/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/progress-and-pianos/</id>
    <published>2018-01-29T00:59:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-29T00:59:07+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For over a year now, I have been &lt;a href="/blog/learning-guitar/"&gt;learning guitar&lt;/a&gt;. And it&amp;rsquo;s been going great, but also not great. I enjoy guitar, but I am still very much &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt; guitar. I&amp;rsquo;m not proficient in the styles I want to be. And, I have plateaued. There are songs I listen to, &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to learn, but can&amp;rsquo;t. Not because the songs are too advanced, but because of &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href="/blog/proprioception/"&gt;struggling&lt;/a&gt; with depression since September, which contributes to the rut I find myself in on guitar. Depression has a way of magnifying challenges, and so the challenges of mastering the skills necessary to learn new songs are magnified. Moreover, the &lt;em&gt;joy&lt;/em&gt; of learning is mostly lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I&amp;rsquo;m improving! I really am, things are better and still improving – but after a few months of this kind of avoidance, one naturally develops habits. I got in the &lt;em&gt;habit&lt;/em&gt; of avoiding guitar, which is now something I need to break. But, once again, that&amp;rsquo;s a challenge that is being magnified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as the Artsy Auctions team has existed, we have talked about getting a piano for the office. Not a &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; piano of course, a digital one. One with nice weighted keys. We could pool our money and spend – maybe $500? – on a piano, connect some headphones so only the player will hear it, and put it somewhere in the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How nice would it be to have a piano just &lt;em&gt;available&lt;/em&gt; at the office? Stuck on a problem? Frustrated with something? Bored at lunch? Step away for a few minutes&amp;hellip; 𝓉𝑜 𝓉𝒽𝑒 𝓅𝒾𝒶𝓃𝑜.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about it for well over a year, when last fall I finally took action on it. Pooling money and buying the piano is the easy part; the biggest dependency of my &lt;em&gt;Office Piano&lt;/em&gt; OmniFocus project was &lt;em&gt;Get Permission from Ops&lt;/em&gt;. Does Artsy have enough space in the office? Will we &lt;em&gt;continue&lt;/em&gt; to have enough space? Where will it go? Will it be disruptive to Artsy colleagues? I scouted out some prospective locations for the piano, considered logistics, and sent a proposal to Artsy&amp;rsquo;s Ops team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some time to get a response, but eventually they gave us tentative permission! Ops were very open to the idea in principle, but naturally had some questions. We went back and forth over Slack for weeks before I happened to bump into a colleague on the Ops team. I asked about the state of their team&amp;rsquo;s discussion about the piano and, turns out, the Ops team was busy opening Artsy&amp;rsquo;s new London office, so (duh!) they were pretty busy. The piano just hadn&amp;rsquo;t been top-of-discussion while the team was split across continents. Even still, by talking with my colleague for two minutes we clarified all of the outstanding details. Face-to-face had accomplished in minutes what weeks of Slack could not in weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 ended with a note from the colleague I&amp;rsquo;d briefly chatted with. Ops had officially given the thumbs-up on our office piano plan! The rest was up to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably don&amp;rsquo;t know this about me because it&amp;rsquo;s never been a part of my adult life, but I played piano &lt;em&gt;daily&lt;/em&gt; from ages 11 to 18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to ask my parents, repeatedly and for what felt like forever, to get a piano. Piano&amp;rsquo;s aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly cheap, or even easy to actually buy. And so, I was given a&amp;hellip; well, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what they were called but I thought of them as tests. These were characteristic of my childhood: demonstrate the responsibility necessary to earn a privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids in the fifth grade of my elementary school all learn the recorder together, and my parents bought me lessons from a good family friend and neighbour, &lt;a href="http://thedowntownbluesband.com/bios/index.html#lloydbragdon"&gt;Lloyd&lt;/a&gt;. He ran a music store out of his garage across the road and he was my first formal music teacher. Lloyd was key to my entire musical education, but especially so in grade five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the school year, I &lt;em&gt;excelled&lt;/em&gt; at playing recorder. I mean, today at the age of 29 I have some doubts about my memories of being a child who was &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; at recorder. But importantly, I had rapidly developed an understanding of music&amp;rsquo;s most important fundamentals: notation, basic theory, rhythm, sub-dividing measures. I could sight-read. And I utterly &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; playing recorder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents were convinced. Lloyd helped them buy an affordable upright piano. Then he tuned it for us and put me in touch with his relative, Marie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie quickly became a mentor and friend. A talented musician and gentle teacher, she played organ at a church down the road and taught piano lessons after school. She emphasized form, technique, feeling. She demanded proper posture and wrist position (and keeping fingernails short). She lent me sci-fi novels like &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt;. When I was thirteen and terrified in the weeks following 9/11, Marie was the one I turned to for help dealing with my anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under her guidance, I prepared for the town&amp;rsquo;s annual music festival. I swept up in every category I competed in. Not really fair, an eleven year-old competing against six year-olds. (We had all been playing for less than a year, but still. The rules were changed the next year to adjudicate participants against a &lt;em&gt;rubric&lt;/em&gt; instead of against &lt;em&gt;each other&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was invited to play in the festival&amp;rsquo;s closing concert, on both piano and alto saxophone (I had joined the school band to learn it and had taken supplementary lessons from Lloyd).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year, I looked forward to the music festival. My parents still boast that they never had to tell me to practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating, I left my home town to go to university. I lost my musical support network. I lost my routine. I lost my free time. I stopped playing music. For a decade, until 2017 when I bought a ukulele, and then guitar, and now&amp;hellip; the office piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees would start trickling in soon. I had less than a half hour before &lt;a href="http://peerlab.community"&gt;peer lab&lt;/a&gt; started, so I had to hurry getting set up. I&amp;rsquo;d already printed off &lt;a href="https://musescore.com/user/3471/scores/1352881"&gt;sheet music&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;The Entertainer&lt;/em&gt;, a ragtime jazz song I had memorized in grade 8. I wanted my re-introduction to piano to be gentle. I was nervous, but excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sit down. I begin, slow at first. Then faster. Then I blink. I look down at my watch: a half hour had passed. How could a half hour had already passed? I had to stop, it was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I was there for peer lab this morning and snuck away for about a half hour of piano. Had some trouble remembering the bass clef notation, but it came back to me pretty quickly! I am excited.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; The SI Unit Respecter (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/954809752239865858?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 20, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week went by. I got three more, quick sessions in on the piano and I was amazed by how much I remembered. I had bought some sheet music books of popular songs for the office. I picked &lt;em&gt;The Piano Man&lt;/em&gt; by Billy Joel and started sight-reading it – slow at first, then fster. I felt exhilarated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Other things they’ve helped:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- staying off twitter at work, unless it’s to complain about work&lt;br&gt;- getting to the office by 9:00, and forcing myself to leave at 5:00&lt;br&gt;- motivation: I’m leading a well-defined and interesting project, an internal tool to help out my colleagues&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; The SI Unit Respecter (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/956666738933936128?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 25, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to have a better work/life balance in 2018, and part of that is getting to and leaving the office at strict times. That goal is orthogonal to my desire to immerse myself in playing piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see where this is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apartments in Manhattan&amp;rsquo;s East Village are tiny. So, a piano. How does that even fit? I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any space in our room (singular). I talked to Ashley and told her how important this was to me, and she wasted no time helping me figure out where a piano could go in our apartment. We spent the weekend rearranging and doing some general spring-cleaning to cut-down on stuff. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad I have a supportive partner. She&amp;rsquo;s excited to get to know this part of me for the first time. Our piano arrives on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen, but for the first time since August, I feel like things are about to &lt;em&gt;improve&lt;/em&gt;. Like, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve felt &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; was going to improve; best-case scenario was things only stayed as bad as they are. And today, something is changed. I feel optimistic again. And I intend to capitalize on that optimism: through therapy, I have learned to fold improvements in my mood back in on themselves. Feedback loops. The virtuous complement to the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtuous_circle_and_vicious_circle"&gt;vicious circles&lt;/a&gt; I had experienced with depression. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medication changes I started two months ago have finally stabilized, and have brought me back to the frame of mind I had in August: ready to turn the page on this depressive chapter of my life and move forward. It&amp;rsquo;s ironic that I&amp;rsquo;m looking to something from my past, music, in order to move forward. But we live in ironic times!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Earth: Final Conflict</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/earth-final-conflict/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/earth-final-conflict/</id>
    <published>2018-01-17T20:13:46+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-17T20:13:46+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What I love about art, and mass media in particular, is how it is shaped by the time and place it was created. Looking at a movie or TV show from 20 years ago, you can get a glimpse into how the world was back then, and reflect on how things have changed. In my opinion, there is no genre better-suited than science fiction for this lens because sci-fi itself is all about asking &amp;ldquo;what if?&amp;rdquo;, and the questions a society asks are as revealing as the answers they come up with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was on a roll the other morning, talking about old sci-fi shows I&amp;rsquo;d watched. I mentioned one that I&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss today: &lt;em&gt;Gene Roddenberry&amp;rsquo;s Earth: Final Conflict&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Earth: Final Conflict is really good at examining the implications of radical technological advancement, the secondary implications, the tertiary ones, etc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Like how does FTL travel affect your commute to work? That kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Person who tells you to write more blog posts (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/952949071911800837?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 15, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earth: Final Conflict&lt;/em&gt; hit TV in the late nineties, and I watched it via Canadian TV syndication during my early teenage years. The show tells the story of humanity, set roughly in the 2020&amp;rsquo;s, who are visited by ostensibly peaceful aliens (called &amp;ldquo;companions&amp;rdquo;, the show is full of poignant euphemisms). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show has lots of great storylines like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would humans graft alien tech onto our own tech? How would that affect our day-to-day lives?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who would resist the companions? Why? How?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if a companion, too evolved to normally interact in the corporeal realm, developed a drug addiction?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t pretend the show is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;, but I enjoy how it answers these questions. We&amp;rsquo;re not here to discuss the show, though, but rather what it reveals to us about the time it was created. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, the late nineties. Computers were cool, and obviously important, but the general population didn&amp;rsquo;t understand computers or the internet in the way they do today. So, the show gets some things right (everyone on the show has a &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://earthfinalconflict.wikia.com/wiki/Global"&gt;global&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, which is a video-conferencing device, but it&amp;rsquo;s also on the internet, has a camera, and is basically a contemporary smartphone).  But the show also gets some things wrong (like any time they actually &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; a computer, it&amp;rsquo;s farcical).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/earth-final-conflict/global.jpg" alt="A global, a communication device on the show" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to draw your attention to S04E05, &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0568689/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motherlode&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, released October 2000. The plot of the episode, like most episodes of &lt;em&gt;Earth: Final Conflict&lt;/em&gt;, is not its strong suit. Rather, it&amp;rsquo;s the questions it asks and how it answers them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, the companions (officially) arrived on Earth at the end of a brutal world conflict, which nearly ended in a nuclear holocaust. Mediated by the newfound companions, a peace armistice was negotiated to end the Sino-Indian War. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motherlode&lt;/em&gt; asks the question: what if a black ops organization took advantage of everyone being distracted by the arrival of the companions, and worked in secret to massively expand its sphere of influence via the Sino-Indian War Measures Act?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The episode begins with two hooded, chained figures being escorted by armed guards. It&amp;rsquo;s dark. A man in a suit tells them to listen up: by the powers granted by the SI War Measures Act, his company was suspending their civil rights. They are to be detained, indefinitely, in his sensory deprivation prison. Submerged in breathable, body-temperature water, they will be deprived of all sensory stimulation. Forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/earth-final-conflict/sendep.jpg" alt="A character we know about to be lowered into a sensory deprivation prison tank" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a fucking &lt;em&gt;mad&lt;/em&gt; premise. Like, fuuuuuuuuck. That&amp;rsquo;s dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole show makes a point of exploring why the SI War Measures Act wasn&amp;rsquo;t repealed with the armistice, what factors are stopping it from being repealed now, and most importantly, the episode makes the following point: the evil of the secret sensory deprivation prison system is something that humans are inflicting on &lt;em&gt;themselves&lt;/em&gt;. Usually in the show, it&amp;rsquo;s the companions who hurt humanity, but this episode is different. It depicts the (wildly fictional) idea of a society run by a government that doesn&amp;rsquo;t respect its citizens rights, one who is unaccountable to its citizens. There are several instances of psychological torture. It&amp;rsquo;s not an easy episode to watch. And as I said, this episode aired eleven months before the attacks of 9/11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question &amp;ldquo;what if black ops sendep prisons?&amp;rdquo; is answered by &amp;ldquo;humanity would torture each other, vindictively and relentlessly&amp;rdquo;, which is a pretty chilling-but-accurate answer. It shocked me how much our perception of the United Stats has changed in just seventeen years. In 2000, the idea that the US intelligence community would be running secret torture prisons without any oversight was a chilling sci-fi &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo;, but in 2018 it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; reality? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, I know I know, the US has a much longer history of fucking with people and trampling their rights domestically and abroad, &lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt;. The difference is: everyone I know today accepts this as reality, but in 2000, abuse of a war measures act seemed purely hypothetical. &lt;em&gt;How we perceive&lt;/em&gt; the world has shifted so much, so quickly. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s always been the case, maybe things always move this fast. But re-watching this episode, it disturbed me deeply to be reminded of what the world felt like when I watched as a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I look at the new &lt;em&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/em&gt; and I feel like a really strong 2003-era fascist vibe. Pro-government, mindlessly pro-war and pro-aggression. Humanity at its worst. Art, and specifically mass media, are a reflection of our hopes and fears. What does the media that&amp;rsquo;s being produced today say about us? Nothing good.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gridcoin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/gridcoin/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/gridcoin/</id>
    <published>2017-12-19T18:52:06+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-19T18:52:06+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve known about bitcoin since 2012 when a friend described a kind of digital currency that he purchased by meeting a guy at a subway station and exchanging an envelope of cash for an envelope of a hard drive. The whole concept felt as something not very above-board. So I decided not to learn more about it and just generally ignored it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years passed when I would catch the occasional headline describing the currency&amp;rsquo;s latest record-setting price, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay it much attention until I moved in New York. Bitcoin would come up in conversation at Artsy; people were discussing new art projects and new technologies and new startups centred around blockchains. And so, cryptocurrency reasserted itself within my bubble and I took a closer look. That was about 18 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading articles and watching videos – and listening to a great lunchtime presentation from a colleague – I now have a solid grasp on the technical underpinnings of the different technologies involved in bitcoin. I have a less solid understanding of some of the practical nuances, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got the technical stuff down. Cryptography, mining, P2P networks for blockchains, that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m reading headlines about new record-setting bitcoin prices with the perspective of the technological underpinnings. And I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed. I mean, the technology is &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;m not excited about the idea of a bunch of powerful nerds getting rich. Amazing tech, but not something I want to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then a few months ago, I noticed an uptick in media coverage about bitcoin. Articles like &lt;a href="https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/ywbbpm/bitcoin-mining-electricity-consumption-ethereum-energy-climate-change"&gt;this one exploring bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s carbon footprint&lt;/a&gt; were being discussed at the office. Bitcoin was being increasingly reported on by people who understood it, leading to more critical coverage and more reporting targeted at a non-engineering audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good! But I still kind of dismissed it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have anything to do with it, and I still don&amp;rsquo;t. Sadly, I may have thrown the proverbial baby out with the bathwater; the blockchain technology that bitcoin is built upon is &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; interesting. I learnt more about etherium and the distributed-computing infrastructure it&amp;rsquo;s built upon and – yeah I regretted not buying bitcoin when it was under $10 – I threw $150 into etherium. I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; etherium and I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m now involved with cryptocurrencies, yet here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things changed a few weeks ago when, during follow-up on their episode about citizen science, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/izqaWyZsEtY?t=784"&gt;PBS Spacetime mentions a cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; that:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; gridcoin, which you mine by devoting computing cycles to BOINC research programs. Seems a bit more useful than bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s useless cryptographic calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gridcoin.us"&gt;Gridcoin&lt;/a&gt;, eh? &lt;a href="https://boinc.berkeley.edu"&gt;BOINC&lt;/a&gt;, huh? Let&amp;rsquo;s check this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did, and through capitalizing on my newly rediscovered interesting in tinkering on things, I revived my Raspberry Pi and set off. Over the course of the past two weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about gridcoin and playing with the related technologies. And while I have a good theoretical understanding of cryptocurrency technologies, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the experience of working with cryptocurrencies in practice. The past few weeks have therefore been a lot of learning new ideas and refining new skills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/pi.png" alt="BOINC on a Raspberry Pi" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s back up and define gridcoin. Other cryptocurrencies, like bitcoin, are mined by computers that compete to solve cryptographic hash functions. That computing power is wasted, in a very real sense: solving those hashes isn&amp;rsquo;t useful &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; to mining more bitcoins. On the other hand, gridcoin is a cryptocurrency mined using calculations that contribute towards scientific research. In fact, gridcoin is really just a layer on top of BOINC, which predates bitcoin and blockchains altogether. This was something I could be interested in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BOINC is a project run out of Berkley; it administers work to a network of distributed computers owned by ordinary people, who volunteer their spare computing resources to BOINC. This is really important because many projects in science require a lot of computing power. Furthermore, many of these projects lend themselves to being solved using BOINC&amp;rsquo;s distributed batch-processing architecture. You may be familiar with its most famous project &lt;a href="http://setiathome.berkeley.edu"&gt;SETI@Home&lt;/a&gt;, the search for extraterrestrial life, but there are others. My favourites include &lt;a href="https://sech.me/boinc/Amicable/"&gt;Amicable Numbers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://milkyway.cs.rpi.edu/milkyway/"&gt;Milkyway@Home&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://asteroidsathome.net"&gt;Asteroids@Home&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So gridcoin basically piggy-backs off of the existing credit and team systems built into BOINC. A blockchain is used to keep track of transactions, like other cryptocurrencies, but new coins are staked based off your contributions to BOINC projects. I&amp;rsquo;m still learning the nuances of the somewhat confusing math, but the general idea is that the more you contribute towards a project&amp;rsquo;s work units (relative to how much others have contributed, and some other factors), the more gridcoins you stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Despite a very active community, I found the documentation to be difficult to follow and sometimes out of date. The guides and wikis I found mostly assumed you already knew what you were doing. Maybe when I have a better grasp of it all, I&amp;rsquo;ll return to update the docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve installed the BOINC client on my laptop and my pi, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around on EC2 to spin up cloud servers to crunch numbers for SETI. It&amp;rsquo;s been fun, to tinker. I eventually settled on just using my laptop because even a c4.xlarge instance (4 virtual CPUs, $0.20/hour) performs worse than my laptop in terms of BOINC stats. I looked into GPU-specific instances, but cloud-based GPU access is still new and in high-demand, so it was too expensive for me (you can add a GPU to an EC2 instance for $0.50/hour, or rent a GPU-optimized instance starting from $0.90/hour). So yeah, not my thing! That&amp;rsquo;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One stumbling block I&amp;rsquo;ve faced when starting has been that (for reasons that are still beyond me) you need to &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; gridcoins to stake them. Seems kinda scam-y, but there&amp;rsquo;s a small transaction fee to basically announce yourself on the blockchain. Okay, fine, but also: when and how often you stake gridcoins (get credit for your BOINC work) is determined in part by how many gridcoins you already have. So starting out is tricky, feels weird, and involves a lot of waiting. With a balance of 3 gridcoins (which I acquired by signing up for a newsletter, lol), my estimated time-to-stake was an estimated three thousands days.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/wallet.png" alt="Gridcoin wallet" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mmm. Mmhmmm. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To build up an initial balance, I tried using a &lt;a href="https://grcpool.com"&gt;gridcoin pool&lt;/a&gt; on an EC2 instance for a few days but wasn&amp;rsquo;t really impressed. Using a pool is like solo mining except you don&amp;rsquo;t need the upfront investment (and you don&amp;rsquo;t get to keep all your earnings). Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m impatient – the calculations take longevity of contribution into account, and I only ran this server for like two days.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/ec2.png" alt="BOINC on EC2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(Lest my command-line hacker skills be called into question, yes I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; install a desktop environment on EC2 but I didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to, it was just easier.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of paying per-second for anything. It reminded me I&amp;rsquo;m literally playing with money, and something about my upbringing makes that uncomfortable for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/gridcoin/pool.png" alt="EC2 gridcoin pool overview page" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I moved a bit of my etherium to my gridcoin wallet to prime the process. My time-to-stake estimate is now bouncing between 15–30 days. More reasonable I guess? I&amp;rsquo;ll learn to be patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways. Still don&amp;rsquo;t love that I&amp;rsquo;m doing this but it&amp;rsquo;s fun and I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying all the tinkering, so. Learning new things has been fun but (as usual) includes its share of frustrations too. And helping to map the galaxy just makes me feel warm and fuzzy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Who is Tom Scharpling?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/who-is-tom-scharpling/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/who-is-tom-scharpling/</id>
    <published>2017-12-13T19:29:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-13T19:29:42+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So a few weeks ago, I was listening to my new favourite Podcast &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/whatatimepod"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What a Time to Be Alive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the hosts mentioned a different show. This Tom Scharpling guy apparently has a show and they revered it a bit actually. The name sounded kinda familiar and I made a note to check him out later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well so this Tom fella is listed in the Apple Podcasts as running &lt;a href="http://thebestshow.net"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best Show&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so I checked it out. About&amp;hellip; thirty seconds into the first episode I froze. My eyes dilated and defocused. I held my breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait a minute.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I double-checked on IMDb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Scharpling is the voice actor behind my favourite character on my &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/"&gt;favourite show&lt;/a&gt;: Greg Universe. I&amp;rsquo;ve already been listening to this guy and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it! And he was a writer and producer on &lt;em&gt;Monk&lt;/em&gt;, which played a big role in my formative years. (I&amp;rsquo;d never seen a protagonist depicted with a mental illness before.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so that&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool, right? Well I kept reading up on him and he&amp;rsquo;s been involved with a bunch of musicians that I like, over many years. Very cool! I kept digging. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Best_Show_with_Tom_Scharpling"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best Show&lt;/em&gt; has been running&lt;/a&gt; for well over a decade, with many people now attributing the rise of podcasting &lt;em&gt;in general&lt;/em&gt; to this show. Some describe him as the &amp;ldquo;Godfather Of Podcasting&amp;rdquo;, according to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Scharpling"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. Very cool! I&amp;rsquo;ve run a number of podcasts over the years and they&amp;rsquo;ve all be influential on my career. My first was just with &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/my-podcast-loves-me/"&gt;some friends and colleagues in 2011&lt;/a&gt;, but I later did an &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/springboard/"&gt;interview series&lt;/a&gt; with established developers who described their origin stories – because we all start from somewhere – and finally I did &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/notification-center/"&gt;another iOS news show&lt;/a&gt;. (All the shows are defunct and offline, sorry. Welllll, one of them &lt;a href="http://notificationcenter.ashfurrow.com"&gt;is archived&lt;/a&gt; but you should absolutely not listen to it.) The point is, I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gotten into podcasting if not for the zeitgeist around the medium in 2011, which Tom Scharpling helped create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this person, who I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know about really, has been influencing my life for well over a decade. My personal life, my career, my art. Wow. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know his name. Prettttty cool!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The S Word</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/the-s-word/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/the-s-word/</id>
    <published>2017-12-06T19:52:16+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-06T19:52:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself drawn towards some ideas to improve the living conditions of folks around the world. These are ideas like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;single-payer healthcare, including prescriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lowering income and wealth inequality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fighting climate change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognizing and fighting against racism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a higher minimum wage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ideas have fairly mainstream support, but if I presented them as &amp;ldquo;socialist&amp;rdquo; ideas, many folks would instinctively reject them. In fact, they are &lt;a href="http://ndpsocialists.ca/socialist-caucus-resolutions-2018-federal-ndp-convention/"&gt;ideas from the Canadian New Democratic Party&amp;rsquo;s Socialist Caucus&lt;/a&gt;. But we can&amp;rsquo;t discuss these ideas in that context, though, because Socialism Is Bad, or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be discussing in this post. Feel free to not @ me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I mentioned my interest in socialism on twitter, I upset a few people. I was accused of spreading communist propaganda and of disrespecting people who had died under the Soviets. Those words hurt. I&amp;rsquo;m not a socialist, or Soviet communist, and I&amp;rsquo;m capable of thinking for myself. Reducing my ideas to mindless repetition of propaganda robs me of my agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I want to talk about this, because I&amp;rsquo;m really frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go through my thought process here. I&amp;rsquo;ve scrutinized the following points for a logical misstep but if you see one, please direct your feedback directly to your drafts folder. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;capitalism causes a lot of people a lot of harm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;critiquing capitalism and capitalists is helpful in diminishing that harm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;socialists have the most experience critiquing capitalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;listening to what socialists have to say about capitalism could be worthwhile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all I&amp;rsquo;m saying. But I know I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna get angry tweets about this blog post. People are just &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; against even the patina of socialism. And I kind of get why: the harsh rule of the Soviets is very much in living memory and folks are very cautious about entertaining any of their ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s, I guess, step back for a second? Why exactly can&amp;rsquo;t we discuss ideas that come from socialists? Is it because socialism is inherently/universally bad? Why do we think that? I mean, this is a cliché but: when people suffer under socialism, it is blamed on socialism; when people suffer under capitalism, it is blamed on the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s have a discussion around why that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There appears to be a refusal to acknowledge the role that capitalism plays in contemporary world events. Let&amp;rsquo;s take climate change for example. Capitalism is responsible for our current climate change disaster: &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/exxon-knew-about-climate-change-almost-40-years-ago/"&gt;oil companies knew about CO2 emissions and their effect in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and hid that knowledge in order to protect their profits. And capitalism still contributes to climate change in many ways – for example, by convincing people that buying an electric car is a way to fight the incipient collapse of our planet&amp;rsquo;s climate. (It&amp;rsquo;s not.) We can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;shop&lt;/em&gt; our way out of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalism created a problem and is now selling us a solution to that problem that won&amp;rsquo;t actually work, thus diverting resources away form solutions that could work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can disagree with my characterization here – that&amp;rsquo;s fine – I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to advance the specific argument that capitalism caused climate change. Instead, what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to point out is that I can&amp;rsquo;t really find criticisms like this – of capitalism – anywhere in the mainstream media narrative. Capitalism is never discussed in a critical way. Ever. Whether or not you believe capitalism caused climate change, you have to admit that it&amp;rsquo;s weird how we don&amp;rsquo;t ever talk about capitalism&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;role&lt;/em&gt; in climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like it&amp;rsquo;s the very ideology of capitalism that prevents us from discussing the roles that the ideology plays in our world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That really sucks, and let me tell you why. You probably don&amp;rsquo;t think the economy is perfect, right? I mean, no one does. So let&amp;rsquo;s discuss how to improve it! Cool, except we aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed to mention Marx or any of his ideas. Why? Because Stalin or something, I guess. We&amp;rsquo;re missing out on what could turn out to be valuable ideas!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/fSQgCy_iIcc' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maybe coming from Canada colours my view of socialism. Maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t recognize the same dangers in socialism that my peers in Europe do. Maybe socialism is far too dangerous to consider at all, in any quantity or any context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what I think: history is written by the victors, and capitalism was the victor of the twentieth century. Is it not likely that capitalist ideology – that we were all born into – has a strong negative slant against socialism? Which capitalism correctly sees as an existential threat? Maybe the taboo of discussing socialist ideas has less to do with the ideas and more to do with how those ideas threaten the interests of capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe! I&amp;rsquo;d love to discuss this with people, but I can&amp;rsquo;t because then they yell at me. So I&amp;rsquo;m stuck and unable to express my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, fuck it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the dangers of considering socialist ideas (even in the abstract) are overblown by capitalists trying to protect their own profits. I believe that there are enough resources on this Earth to provide every human with a meaningful and dignified existence, but this vision is incompatible with capitalism. I believe that the broad and abstract topic of &amp;ldquo;socialism&amp;rdquo; is worth scrutinizing for any ideas that could save our species from extinction. That&amp;rsquo;s what I believe, and if you&amp;rsquo;re mad about any of this, ask yourself why that is.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/344260297&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If this resonates with you, check out the above podcast from &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/citationsneededpodcast"&gt;Citations Needed&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a great show that dissects (among other things) capitalist ideology without preaching socialism. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re a staunch anti-socialist, check it out anyway, because the discussion they present is representative of the kinds of discussions we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; having, but that we really &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to have.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
