<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Ash Furrow</title>
  <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog</id>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/"/>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-11-28T00:00:01+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ash Furrow</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>So Steven Universe eh?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/</id>
    <published>2017-11-28T00:00:01+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-28T00:00:01+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a TV show called &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; that I highly recommend, to anyone. To everyone, actually. I&amp;rsquo;m rewatching it now and I&amp;rsquo;ve got some notes on what appeals to me in the show. Maybe it would appeal to you, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;If you’re looking for a distraction from the depressing hellscape of 2017, I can’t recommend Steven Universe enough. &lt;a href="https://t.co/pymOPd086g"&gt;pic.twitter.com/pymOPd086g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ash &amp;ldquo;Thanksgiving Belongs in October&amp;rdquo; Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/925891391737143296?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;ve never watched cartoons or did but didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy them, I encourage you to set that aside and give &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; a try anyways. It&amp;rsquo;s obviously a cartoon and it&amp;rsquo;s obviously aimed at kids, but the metaphors in the show make it inclusive to folks from all kinds of different backgrounds. Even adults. It&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;em&gt;kid&amp;rsquo;s show&lt;/em&gt; as much as it is a show that is accessible &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; is an adventure dramedy that tells stories around a cast of believable characters – with hopes and flaws – centred around the titular Steven&amp;rsquo;s coming-of-age story. The show also tells a long, drawn-out sci-fi about intergalactic beings that colonize planets to mine their raw materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are a few things that really stand out in the show. Here&amp;rsquo;s a tl;dr list, continue reading for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent pacing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large stories, told with restraint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistent and cohesive lore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phenomenal music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Believable characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spectacular Art.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A non-judgemental narrative style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go into detail!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pacing"&gt;Pacing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; is a masterclass in pacing. The story takes place on a kind of slightly-alternate Earth, and it spans back thousands of years to a war. Through telling stories relating to that war, the characters are developed over the course of 11-minute episodes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no filler episodes; each episode contributes to character development in some way, and usually ties in with the broader story. There are often 3–5 episode arcs that tie together, but each episode is a self-contained story. This is a nice balance between the episodic monster-of-the-week style and the Battlestar Galactica style where only a few episodes can be watched in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="lore"&gt;Lore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lore and world-building in &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; is remarkable in its consistency and cohesion with both the art and the plot. It builds upon itself, setting up a stable foundation upon which to grow the characters and tell their stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a taste, here&amp;rsquo;s a rough overview of the world (season one/two spoilers):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gems are aliens. They are a kind of magic/technology hybrid and exist as small gemstones embedded in their &amp;ldquo;physical forms&amp;rdquo; – humanoid bodies. These bodies are &amp;ldquo;holograms but with mass&amp;rdquo; and the show has fun with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gems don&amp;rsquo;t age and they don&amp;rsquo;t change. Gems are created and used for specific purposes and there is no escape from their rigid social hierarchy. And that brings us to the war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gem War was began on Earth as a rebellion against Homeworld. Earth was being destroyed to serve the purposes of the Diamonds until Rose Quartz stopped them. Countless gems and humans were destroyed, but the resistance successfully fought off Homeworld&amp;rsquo;s forces (for now). Only a few gems survived the last assault on Earth, and they have been living in isolation for thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mid-nineties, Rose met Greg (a human). They fell in love and, eventually, decided to have a child. This was unprecedented – gems don&amp;rsquo;t have children, they are grown artificially. Steven was born and the show focuses a lot on his struggle to exist in the space between two races. Not a human, not a gem. Just Steven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="music"&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show weaves music into its narrative in a real thoughtful way. Both background music as well as music featured in the show: Steven plays a ukulele, and his dad plays a guitar. The show&amp;rsquo;s music had an impact on me: this time last year, I picked up a ukulele and have rediscovered how much I enjoy music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice actors are cast specifically with their singing voices in mind, and Rebecca Sugar (the show&amp;rsquo;s creator) really emphasizes how important the music is by playing a lot of the songs herself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/usXTGY4anrQ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the soundtrack is &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/3fNVnjSRQ3oW4PUIKvrThu"&gt;available on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="characters"&gt;Characters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so the characters! The adolescent Steven lives with the gems leftover from the war, and is also raised by his father Greg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rose and Greg wanted to have a child, but Rose understood this would require a sacrifice. She would have to permanently give up her physical form to give birth. This serves as an analogue to dying during childbirth, except that Rose &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; that the beginning of Steven&amp;rsquo;s existence would mark the end of her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So fast forward: Steven is living with the gems and spends a lot of time with his father. The two groups don&amp;rsquo;t really get along. Some of the gems blame Greg for Rose being gone, and they struggle with complicated feelings towards their roles in Steven&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each gem has their own distinct origins. Greg has a backstory too. These are all explored in really interesting and thoughtful ways. Side-characters too! You will never see a character only once, they &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; reappear. Here&amp;rsquo;s a very small (but very representative) example: in Season Two, we explore the origins of a side-character, and that origin story briefly features this gem in a flashback:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/lapis.jpg" alt="Lapis is poofed by Bismuth" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Later, in Season Three, we meet the gem again learn more about her relationship to Rose and her role in the war.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/bismuth.jpg" alt="Steven meets Bismuth" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I mean, what? I didn&amp;rsquo;t see this coming at all – and these kinds of hints are scattered throughout the show&amp;rsquo;s art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="art"&gt;Art&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art in the show is spectacular. &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; uses dedicated background artists to help create a cohesive palette of visuals that drive – and are driven by – the plot. It won&amp;rsquo;t do it just to describe, so here are some examples.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/tree.jpg" alt="A tree on a hill" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/car.jpg" alt="Stevonnie driving" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/house.jpg" alt="Steven's kitchen" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-steven-universe-eh/pearl.jpg" alt="Pearl clutching a sword" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The dynamic nature of the show&amp;rsquo;s artwork isn&amp;rsquo;t really represented by still images. The distinctive animation plays a key role. I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned music already, but music+art+animation combine synergistically to convey a really compelling story. Here&amp;rsquo;s one representative example, with some cool glitchy body horror elements!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/Iqp0jlXkNQk' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 id="non-judgemental-narratives"&gt;Non-judgemental Narratives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really dig about the show is how non-judgemental it is. No story ever looks down on a character for their ability, stature, job, lifestyle, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take Greg for example. Greg is a burnt-out wannabe rockstar who lives in his van parked beside the carwash (where he works). Rather than depicting Greg as being unable to care for Steven, the relationship between the two is caring and meaningful. The show celebrates how Greg overcomes difficult challenges to support his son. Greg is probably my favourite character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve presented here a list and explanation of what appeals to me in &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to describe the show only in ways &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; show could be evaluated. This analysis misses out on discussing ways the show excels as a piece of &lt;em&gt;culture&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not well-suited to describing the show&amp;rsquo;s meaningfulness to groups of people who are underrepresented in media, but the show&amp;rsquo;s makers make efforts to tell stories that are neglected by most television media. &lt;em&gt;Steven Universe&lt;/em&gt; uses metaphors to tell stories that would normally be &amp;ldquo;over the heads&amp;rdquo; of children, tackling topics normally reserved for &lt;em&gt;Degrassi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metaphors, oh the metaphors!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re keen to start watching the show, there are a few places you can begin with. The first episode, &lt;em&gt;Gem Glow&lt;/em&gt; (S01E01), is a natural place to start; the show finds its footing incredibly quickly. &lt;em&gt;Space Race&lt;/em&gt; (S01E28) is a great way to dive in and get a feel for the show without getting caught up in its lore. And if you want a sneak into the where the show&amp;rsquo;s story is gonna go – while avoiding most spoilers! – try &lt;em&gt;Bismuth&lt;/em&gt; (S03E20). Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Taxonomies of Engineering Careers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/taxonomies-of-engineering-careers/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/taxonomies-of-engineering-careers/</id>
    <published>2017-11-22T17:49:14+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-22T17:49:14+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Humans are ridiculous bad a taxonomy. We look for patterns to group stuff together, even though most stuff is different from most other stuff. Nature defies any classification system we humans try to create, but it is our nature to try anyway. Our classification systems can &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; be applied universally. Just look at how poorly we define &lt;em&gt;seasons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class='embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9'&gt;&lt;iframe src='//www.youtube.com/embed/s0oX9YJ5XLo' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Drift between theoretical classification systems and the tangible stuff they try to classify isn&amp;rsquo;t always a bad thing. Classifications are a kind of abstraction that hides &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; details in order to make &lt;em&gt;others&lt;/em&gt; easier to reason about. For example, Linnaean taxonomy is good at grouping individuals into &amp;ldquo;species&amp;rdquo; because &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; find it useful; even though nature is &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; too messy to ever be accurately represented in a general taxonomy, having a taxonomy nonetheless helps us study biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Classification systems are most useful when they &lt;em&gt;describe&lt;/em&gt; something that &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; exists. They lose much of their usefulness when we use them to &lt;em&gt;prescribe&lt;/em&gt; what we &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to discuss career ladders! If your engineering team is worth their salt, they try to help you grow as a software developer using a &amp;ldquo;ladder&amp;rdquo; of different stages of your career. I&amp;rsquo;m using my own career and &lt;a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/04/03/artsy-engineering-compensation-framework/"&gt;Artsy&amp;rsquo;s own engineering career ladder&lt;/a&gt; to illustrate shortcomings in engineering careers &lt;em&gt;in general&lt;/em&gt;. Hopefully this will resonate with your and you can help your team work around those shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two main complaints with engineering career ladders:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tacitly expect that engineers will advance up the ladder, always and forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prescribe a single path that engineers are expected to follow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Okay so let&amp;rsquo;s deal with the tacit suggestion that to grow in your career, you need to advance up the ladder. From junior to intermediate to senior and beyond. There is an expectation from businesses and peers that developers ought to seek to advance their careers, that we should always be working towards the next rung of that ladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem is exacerbated by conflation between growing one&amp;rsquo;s career and growing one&amp;rsquo;s skillset; continual learning is inherent to being an engineer, but continual progress up some arbitrary career ladder is not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been facing lately in my own career. According to Artsy, I am a &amp;ldquo;Senior Engineer&amp;rdquo; despite fulfilling many of the requirements for the next level role of &amp;ldquo;Staff Engineer.&amp;rdquo; I had convinced myself that I &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; to broaden my skills and praxis to advance to that next level, despite how it was affecting my happiness and satisfaction with my career &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at a Staff Engineer&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities at Artsy:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owns large scale and impact service or collection of services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understands the Artsy business and makes decisions based on its direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sought out by other team members for technical guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anticipates technical issues at the product level and makes architectural and design decisions to avoid them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognized as a prolific contributor to core and side projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiplies the effectiveness of others by facilitating cross-team work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has track record of creating sweeping improvements in stability, performance, and scalability across services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistently reduces the complexity of projects, services, and processes in order to get more done with less work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has made an obvious positive impact on the entire company&amp;rsquo;s technical trajectory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sets short to medium-term strategic technical direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicates the awesomeness of Artsy technology externally via talks and blog posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The requirements that I already fulfill are fulfilled because &lt;em&gt;I enjoy doing them&lt;/em&gt;. The requirements that I don&amp;rsquo;t fulfill are largely because &lt;em&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy doing them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why aren&amp;rsquo;t I happy just being a &amp;ldquo;Senior Engineer&amp;rdquo;? Probably the hedonic treadmill I guess. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize how much my pursuit of the ladder&amp;rsquo;s next rung was making me unhappy and dissatisfied with what I already have and do. I was a &lt;a href="/blog/we-are-the-coyote/"&gt;coyote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the expectation of engineers to continually advance up a career ladder is intrinsic to the &lt;em&gt;overwhelming&lt;/em&gt; breadth of the ladders themselves. These ladders attempt to describe the complete range of developer experience levels, despite that &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you grow as a junior dev is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different from how you grow as a senior dev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fault is in the ladder metaphor itself. It works well as a prescription of how to grow from novice to competency but does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; work well as a guide to growing from competency to proficiency. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When starting a software developer career, there are basics that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; needs to learn. Things like familiarity with source control, command line tools, and &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; programming language. Once you learn those basics, you can move onto more complex, but still universally applicable skills such as writing idiomatic code or contributing to open source. But beyond these fundamentals, things vary wildly based on individual engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior engineer might pursue a career in user interface systems, people management, community building, system reliability, and so on. No career &amp;ldquo;ladder&amp;rdquo; can possibly prescribe steps and goals for such a wide gamut of paths because careers defy classification. The ladder metaphor works very well for junior engineers but loses applicability the more an engineer advances. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better metaphor might be that of a tree: roots and a trunk that follow a single path upward before splitting into many branches. This provides structure for beginning engineers while still accommodating the breadth of ways individual engineers grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core problem with prescriptive, linear career ladders is that the limitations of the ladder metaphor cause them to be imbued with the biases of whoever writes it. For example, Artsy&amp;rsquo;s engineering career ladder requires public speaking and/or blog posts (which excludes developers who aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in or able to practice those activities). It&amp;rsquo;s also very oriented around &amp;ldquo;services&amp;rdquo;, which excludes developers who work primarily on apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say Artsy&amp;rsquo;s ladder isn&amp;rsquo;t useful – it is! I&amp;rsquo;m just highlighting that the experience and background of the engineers who &lt;em&gt;wrote&lt;/em&gt; Artsy&amp;rsquo;s ladder have influenced it. By extension, those biases have impacted the careers of dozens of engineers who have worked at Artsy. That impact, of biases on career ladders, is going to be present in &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; ladder, no matter who writes it and no matter how useful that ladder is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that my focus on advancing to the &amp;ldquo;next level&amp;rdquo; of Artsy&amp;rsquo;s ladder is hurting my satisfaction with what I already have. I need to learn to pursue career growth that leaves me fulfilled and not dissatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that the ladder metaphor itself is prescriptive and every ladder is imbued with the biases of its authors. Maybe I need to write my own career ladder, specific to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an industry, I hope that we move away from prescription towards description, away from linear tracks towards intertwining paths, away form the relentless pursuit of what&amp;rsquo;s next towards an appreciation for what we&amp;rsquo;ve already accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Proprioception</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/proprioception/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/proprioception/</id>
    <published>2017-11-19T23:30:50+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-19T23:30:50+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hold your hand in front of your face. Close your eyes. Now make a fist. Do a &amp;ldquo;thumps up&amp;rdquo; or maybe the Spock sign. Even though your eyes are closed, you know where your hand is and what shape it&amp;rsquo;s in. Seems silly to even say, but this &amp;ldquo;knowing where parts of your body are without seeing them&amp;rdquo; thing is a sense called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proprioception"&gt;proprioception&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not something you&amp;rsquo;d often think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about it. When starting or stopping certain antidepressants, my sense of proprioception gets &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; messed up. You know double-vision? I get that but for proprioception. If I move suddenly, my brain gets confused about where parts of my body are and I get waves of nausea. Not fun, but it&amp;rsquo;s never been this bad. I need to be careful not to turn my head too quickly or the dizziness kicks in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not even &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. You know what other body part frequently makes sudden, jerky movements? (don&amp;rsquo;t be creepy) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your eyes. &lt;em&gt;Constantly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your eyes move, your brain edits out the &amp;ldquo;frames&amp;rdquo; blurred by the quick motion. When you look from the left to the right, your brain sees the left image, then the right image, but not the blurry bits in between. Same with me. I see the new image on the right, but my proprioception is still telling my brain that I&amp;rsquo;m still looking to the left. The cognitive dissonance causes a sort of jolt, almost like electricity. It sweeps across my head without warning, leaving ripples of nausea in its wake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had these side-effects before when starting or stopping an SSRI or SNRI, but never to this degree. Everyday activities are really difficult and laborious. I climb stairs so slowly that my iPhone and Apple Watch don&amp;rsquo;t give me credit towards the &amp;ldquo;flights climbed&amp;rdquo; activity metric (which really pisses me off).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is the worst of it appears to be over, but the bad news is it&amp;rsquo;s still pretty bad. Last week was &lt;em&gt;basically&lt;/em&gt; a write-off. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an appointment tomorrow with my psychiatrist  to follow-up about progress on the new med, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be up to a therapeutic dose within another week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Not Immediately Obvious</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/not-immediately-obvious/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/not-immediately-obvious/</id>
    <published>2017-11-13T00:00:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-13T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s been about a week since I &lt;a href="/blog/so-i-have-been-struggling/"&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; about how I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling and about some of the ways I&amp;rsquo;m coping with it. I discussed cooking a bit, but I wanted to explore that a little more and I want to share some thing that were not immediately obvious to me: things I had to learn (or re-learn).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, cooking has been a good coping mechanism for three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives me something to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps me feel accomplished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It helps me eat nutritious food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also something that I get to do with my wife, which is always fun. I also get to wear a cool apron, so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course the cool thing is with Blue Apron is that I&amp;rsquo;m able to take lessons I learn from their meals and apply them in other circumstances. For example, if I learn how to make a specific kind of salad, I can make that salad again with a different meal. Sounds basic, and it is, but fundamentals are important. Other skills I already had are starting to come back to me. The excitement of trying something new is coming back to me.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Bbaa7xPgjGE/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank"&gt;I made something! Not according to a recipe either, just whipped up some fried chicken, slaw, and mashed potatoes – with gravy!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;A post shared by Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow) on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-11-12T22:59:30+00:00"&gt;Nov 12, 2017 at 2:59pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently taking parts from different recipes and combining them to make remixes. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to get, like, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good at it or anything; I&amp;rsquo;m already enjoying it. But I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that more experimentation progresses me towards being a better cook. This is a pretty nice and quite needed boost to my self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyway, here are some lessons that I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up on. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any vegetable can – apparently – be cut, drizzled with olive oil, tossed with salt and pepper, then roasted in the oven for a while and it will always taste amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, vegetables like kale, sliced cabbage, and thinly sliced radishes can be left to marinate, raw, in a little vinegar and will taste good somehow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I never liked black pepper, but it apparently tastes amazing when put on food &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Season with salt and pepper&amp;rdquo; is basically implied at the end of every step of every recipe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Okay so the stuff left in / stuck to a pan after cooking meat is called &amp;ldquo;fond&amp;rdquo; and with nearly no effort can be made into a sauce. Praise to the sauce, protect the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related to using fond to make sauces, the way to use spices (chilli pepper flakes, sage, rosemary, etc) is to simmer with some kind of fat, maybe oil or butter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many kinds of vinegar and they&amp;rsquo;re all great for different things and experimenting is fun. Do not settle for off-brand Heinz white vinegar!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharp knives make things easier, safer, and more fun. I was using the knives my old roommate didn&amp;rsquo;t bother taking with him, but splurged on &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2ie9tDH"&gt;this knife&lt;/a&gt; and it is so. much. fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really really need to learn how to use my roommates&amp;rsquo; rice cooker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having little dishes around is really helpful. A friend recommended it to me but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really get how useful it is, especially in prep work, until I got a few little dishes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of fun to be had in plating food to look pretty. I started doing this in Toronto and it&amp;rsquo;s still really fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So scallions (&amp;ldquo;green onions&amp;rdquo;) have two distinct parts: the white stem and the green stalk. &lt;em&gt;Separate these parts&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;use them both omg&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow"&gt;@ me&lt;/a&gt; with your favourite cooking thing that wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It Was Only a Matter of Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/it-was-only-a-matter-of-time/</id>
    <published>2017-11-11T14:51:29+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-11T14:51:29+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh hey remember that time that I went to a doctor for wrist pain, and they diagnosed me with Carpal Tunnel Syndrome?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Saw a doctor yesterday and they confirmed: carpal tunnel syndrome 😩 Got some physical therapy lined up.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ashley Alonzo Hale Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/778229355956822016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 20, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well. Artsy changed insurance at the end of August, so I had to find a new physiotherapist. I made an appointment with a new clinic because, while I made some progress, my wrists still hurt. I saw a doctor for an exam and they were&amp;hellip; dubious of my diagnosis. They were especially surprised at how long I&amp;rsquo;d been on a physiotherapy regimen without feeling totally better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay nerds: there&amp;rsquo;re two nerves that control the hands and relay sensory information back to the brain: the median nerve and the ulnar nerve. The median nerve goes through your carpal bones in your hand and when those bones compress the nerve, that&amp;rsquo;s carpal tunnel syndrome. This nerve connects to your thumb and your index, middle, and ring fingers. The ulnar nerve is the one exposed in your elbow as your &amp;ldquo;funny bone&amp;rdquo; and connects to your pinky and half your ring finger (the other half is the median nerve).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So they did an EMG to see what was up with my nerves. See, my symptoms are wrist pain and numbness in my pinky/ring fingers, so Carpal Tunnel Syndrome is kind of a weird diagnosis. The EMG confirmed that my nerve responses are fine, which is good news! I don&amp;rsquo;t actually have Carpal Tunnel Syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s going on then? Turns out that, in concert with how all office furniture is too short for my 188cm stature, my bad posture was causing me to lean forward and apply pressure on the underside of my forearms. That&amp;rsquo;s where my ulnar nerve is. I&amp;rsquo;ve since noticed that I do this a lot, especially while typing. There is also some shoulder pain that is being referred down my nerve, so I feel wrist pain but the source of the pain is in my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I&amp;rsquo;d sought a second opinion earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since starting physiotherapy four weeks ago, the pain is gone from both wrists and the numbness is gone from my right hand (still working on the left, but it&amp;rsquo;s improving). The therapy has mostly concentrated on strengthening scapular muscles to help my posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyways. I was chatting with Orta on the walk home about all this, and how I&amp;rsquo;d felt left out of the Apple Watch hoorah since watches aggravate my wrist pain (and have for years). But since I&amp;rsquo;m making such great progress, maybe I&amp;rsquo;d look into getting an Apple Watch. He mentions that Artsy still has a first-generation test device, it&amp;rsquo;s at his apartment, and why don&amp;rsquo;t I come fetch it and say hello to his new puppy?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Ba_1zPNDXn_/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by Murphy (@murphys&lt;em&gt;paw&lt;/em&gt;nyc)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-11-02T15:14:46+00:00"&gt;Nov 2, 2017 at 8:14am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obviously I said yes; the puppy alone makes it worth climbing three flights of stairs. But the point is, I tried out the Apple Watch for a while and I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you might remember that when the watch was first announced, I was&amp;hellip; &lt;a href="/blog/crestfallen/"&gt;less than enthused&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty skeptical, but whatever. It was no risk to me to try it out. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it, or if it started hurting my wrists, no problem: I give it back to Artsy to sit in a drawer forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after upgrading the device to watchOS 4 (which was it&amp;rsquo;s own thing) I started wearing it. Not many of the apps I used have watchOS extensions, but I found the built-in support for Activity and stuff pretty cool! I like getting more in-depth data about myself and the gentle encouragement throughout the day was really nice. I also re-enabled some iOS push notifications so I&amp;rsquo;d have an excuse to use it more, to give it a fair chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy with the first-gen watch but I could definitely see it strain under the weight of, well, of anything.  And I discovered that I need to wear it on my right wrist, at least for now, because my left one is still recovering and the watch irritated it. I also discovered I&amp;rsquo;d been wearing wristwatches wrong my whole life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;[poll] So I may have been wearing wristwatches wrong my whole life. They apparently go above the wrist bone and not on top of this wrist where it flexes? Sound of in the comments hey&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ashley Alonzo Hale Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/928283229068644353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 8, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks on Twitter told me to get a contemporary model but I wanted to get a feel for it first. Well I finally did get one of my own, a Series 3 (without cellular, you monsters), and it&amp;rsquo;s great! A &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2hlM5Do"&gt;knockoff watchband from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; helped it look snazzy and provide more granular adjustments, which I really like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upgrade from first-gen to Series 3 is&amp;hellip; well it&amp;rsquo;s quite a leap. UI transitions that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think were animated on the old device were actually just really, really laggy. So the new one is a big improvement! I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only problem has been the dearth of apps for the Apple Watch, even a few years on. The apps that &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have watchOS extensions are hit-or-miss. &lt;em&gt;OmniFocus&lt;/em&gt; is probably a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; example of an extension done well: a thoughtful subset of functionality with an easy UI. Other apps, like &lt;em&gt;Airmail&lt;/em&gt;, go all-in on feature parity with their iOS apps, which is a bit excessive in my opinion. And some apps, like &lt;em&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/em&gt;, offer a kind of in-between where the functionality is limited but in ways I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with. So who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some games even designed specifically with the watch in mind, like &lt;em&gt;Pocket Bandit&lt;/em&gt; where you use the digital crown and haptic feedback to crack open locked safes. And there are some that take advantage of how infrequently/briefly users check their watches, like &lt;em&gt;Lifeline&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m on the lookout for more of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting a watch has also stirred within me something I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt towards native apps for a long time: a desire to build something new and the resulting search for a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I wanna make an apple watch app that uses the accelerator etc to do like an exercise monitor but for petting cats 😹&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ashley Alonzo Hale Furrow (@ashfurrow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/929340577291923458?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it may have been premature for me to dump on the watch (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/st607cjBit/"&gt;oops&lt;/a&gt;). But I get the impression that the hardware and software are still not really reaching their full potential. I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s similar to the iPhone 3GS in that regard: getting closer, but still a ways off from what it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be. What it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing how the device and ecosystem evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>So I Have Been Struggling</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-i-have-been-struggling/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/so-i-have-been-struggling/</id>
    <published>2017-11-04T15:02:21+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-04T15:02:21+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; update time I guess. I&amp;rsquo;m kind of writing this for me to help me work through some stuff, and it&amp;rsquo;s probably not that interesting. But I&amp;rsquo;m putting it on my blog so that others can see that &lt;a href="/blog/normalizing-struggle/"&gt;struggle is normal&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully realize that they are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past August had me feeling happier than I&amp;rsquo;ve been since roughly 2011, when I graduated university, got married, and moved to Toronto. In university, I had struggled with depression but I had overcome it with talk therapy. I felt great in 2011, and I think I felt that great in August. I even got to enjoy a vacation back home to see my family before things changed suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was taking two medications: an SNRI and another &amp;ldquo;booster&amp;rdquo; drug that augments the SNRI. It was the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; combination for me, it worked &lt;em&gt;so well&lt;/em&gt;. I had even &lt;a href="/blog/therapys-end/"&gt;stopped going to therapy&lt;/a&gt; because I had worked through what I needed to work through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well see the problem is that the booster I was on has an uncommon complication. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly rare, and I was on a very low dose, but I had been told to watch out for certain signs of this complication. This neurological complication. This complication that often is permanent and persists for the rest of one&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped taking the booster at the very end of August. I knew what withdrawal from this drug would feel like, I&amp;rsquo;d been through it a few times. It starts out seeming like it won&amp;rsquo;t be so bad: a few weeks of no change at all, but then a sudden and steep drop in my mood. Drop in my appetite. Drop in hobbies. In motivation to work. Motivation to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke with my psychiatrist and the next step we&amp;rsquo;d settled on was to use a different booster, one that I had used before and had seen &lt;em&gt;partial&lt;/em&gt; improvement with. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly conventional approach and I wanted to pursue this before trying something more radical: a change to my main anti-depressant. From an SNRI to, something else. I&amp;rsquo;m nervous about this option.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BbEu3vmA3DM/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-11-04T12:50:25+00:00"&gt;Nov 4, 2017 at 5:50am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Artsy changed insurance providers at the end of August and my old therapist was no longer in my health insurance network. And he&amp;rsquo;s more of a psychoanalyst than someone who could help me with coping strategies in the moments when I&amp;rsquo;m feeling hopeless. What I need is a Cognitive Behavioural Therapist. My psychiatrist had offered to help me find someone specializing in CBT. I was secretly resistant to this idea for, I don&amp;rsquo;t know, really dumb reasons. Rationales that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t shared with my psychiatrist or my wife, Ashley. After talking it through with Ashley, I decided to find a new therapist. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s kind of where I am right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to my psychiatrist for a checkup to see how I was feeling on the alternate booster (these drugs take weeks-to-months to &amp;ldquo;kick in&amp;rdquo;). I told her: I&amp;rsquo;m feeling better, I guess. I can concentrate more easily, I manage to get showered and leave the house every day, which is a big improvement from when I crashed mid-September. But I still felt totally flat, &lt;a href="/blog/depression-graphed/"&gt;unable to experience any emotion&lt;/a&gt;. She was getting concerned that the conventional booster wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be effective and started discussing an aggressive change in my primary anti-depressant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See&amp;hellip; psychiatrists all have these little questionnaires that measures changes in different symptoms of depression. Things like mood, appetite, sleeping patterns, interest in activities, and of course, thoughts of suicide. I took the usual questionnaire and my results were only a &lt;em&gt;slight&lt;/em&gt; improvement from September. Not promising. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My psychiatrist noticed that one score on one questionnaire had significantly worsened, a really important question. And so I got to have &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; conversation. You know the one, right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;And how often would you say that you think about ending your life?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s quite a lot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you have access to any firearms?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you think you would do if you decided to act on these thoughts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always hate this conversation. I feel so ashamed of myself. I know I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t but I do. I feel like a dog getting its nose rubbed into a mess it&amp;rsquo;s made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation continues. I answer a question with vague euphemisms. They re-ask the question, reworded so I can&amp;rsquo;t wiggle out of it with an &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; and a hapless shrug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I don&amp;rsquo;t even why I&amp;rsquo;m afraid of switching medications. It just seems scary. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;ll get worse I guess. But I&amp;rsquo;ve kind of realized that though it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; make things worse in the near-term, my current prescription isn&amp;rsquo;t healthy or sustainable. I have an appointment next week where I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss crossfading between prescriptions and the associated blood work (ugh).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird, but, I&amp;rsquo;m kind in better spirits now that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to be more aggressive with medication. I guess I was kind of ashamed, but talking through things Ashley and another friend helped me realize that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to feel that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking helped improve my mood in the short term and I hope or believe I guess that it&amp;rsquo;ll improve things in the long term too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend and yours, Orta, had spoken highly of &lt;a href="https://www.blueapron.com"&gt;Blue Apron&lt;/a&gt; on several occasions. I was really interested but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t pursued it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, my appetite is pretty low right now. I have to remind myself to eat and if I forget, my mood drops significant. And my motivation to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; things was &lt;em&gt;verrrrrrry&lt;/em&gt; limited. So I was eating pretty poorly because it is &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; easier to microwave another frozen dinner or order food using the internet than it is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan what to eat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of things I need to buy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go outside and buy them (or, more likely, order them using the internet).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare the food in the tiny kitchen that I share with my roommates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is a real fucking shame because I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; to cook. I used to anyways. Here&amp;rsquo;s me in university 2010 cooking for a community breakfast that I&amp;rsquo;d organized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/so-i-have-been-struggling/pancakes.jpg" alt="Me making pancakes" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to Toronto was like, the peak of my enjoyment of cooking. Actually, it was and remains the most joyous part of my life. I had a &lt;em&gt;kickass&lt;/em&gt; kitchen and bought all kinds of doodads to make all kinds of food. I started experimenting with baking, even making goddamn &lt;em&gt;macarons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to Amsterdam put up a lot of barriers to me enjoying cooking. Barriers like a totally different grocery store where everything is in a totally different language and cashiers assume you speak Dutch, and folks interact according to very different customs. Barriers like this weren&amp;rsquo;t by themselves a problem but after moving to Amsterdam I ran out of anti-depressants and struggled to find reliable medical help. I didn&amp;rsquo;t cook anymore, my appetite was gone, I was feeling suicidal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Footnote: the time I was feeling the lowest coincided with my first few months with Artsy, and I was really worried that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t performing adequately enough. Artsy colleagues, and Orta in particular, were a reliable source of validation. It got me through some tough times.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to New York reduced a lot of the barriers to cooking I&amp;rsquo;d had in Amsterdam, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really in the habit anymore. Plus there are &lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt; cool takeout places around the city to try out. Well, to order over the internet. Anyway, the point is I haven&amp;rsquo;t really cooked since Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve come to rely upon in New York while I&amp;rsquo;ve been depressed in the past few years are, like, &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; bougie. The part of me that wants to buy off-brand Kraft Dinner to save thirty cents is in utter conflict with the part of me that is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; into doing my laundry online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt ashamed of paying extra for convenience. Ashley had explained that, logistically, it makes more sense to pay a little extra for conveniences than to languish without the basics of living. That made sense, and was the kind of justification that I&amp;rsquo;d used when I felt bad about things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Blue Apron. It was something that I had felt ashamed of even considering. But after Orta helped connect the dots for me that Blue Apron could &lt;em&gt;remove the barriers to cooking&lt;/em&gt;, I brought it up with Ashley. She&amp;rsquo;s handled everything to get us set up (aside from carrying the heavy box up four flights of stairs).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BbDyar7BFhp/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by Ashley Furrow (@ashleyfurrow)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-11-04T04:02:10+00:00"&gt;Nov 3, 2017 at 9:02pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been three weeks now and I. Am. Loving. It. Blue Apron has brought some joy back into my life while I struggle through all the shit I&amp;rsquo;m going through right now. It reminded me that &lt;em&gt;I like to cook&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that hard stuff? The planning and grocery lists and going to store and cleaning the kitchen? Well I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten, but I like that too. Yesterday, I noticed an &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; grocery store literally on my walk home. It excited me. I went in, planned not one, but two meals! I had a goddamn &lt;em&gt;conversation&lt;/em&gt; with the cashier about what I was planning to cook and &lt;em&gt;I enjoyed it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not completely at ease with my feelings about the modern conveniences of New York and the internet. Maybe parts of me will always be at odds: a struggle between rigid parsimony and practical indulgence. But embracing convenience and starting Blue Apron sparked something with me. It re-ignited a source of joy for me, and is responsible for a much-needed reprieve from the things I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have realized that the most effective solutions to my problems &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; involve talking it through with someone. It&amp;rsquo;s a mix of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rubber_duck_debugging"&gt;Rubber Duck debugging&lt;/a&gt; but for emotions, and advice from trusted friends. It came down to talking, but I had to be honest and I usually had to start the conversation. That was really hard. Like, &lt;em&gt;the hardest thing&lt;/em&gt;. But I did it. I worked up the courage for days and finally sprung a conversation about suicidal ideation on my unsuspecting wife while seated in a bustling café. But it worked, and I felt &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with the kinds of problems I&amp;rsquo;m having, I want you to try talking to someone you trust about how you&amp;rsquo;re feeling. Please. I promise that you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; worth the struggle it will be to ask: &amp;ldquo;can we talk?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
