<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Ash Furrow</title>
  <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog</id>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/"/>
  <link href="https://ashfurrow.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-04-13T13:57:45+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ash Furrow</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Mastodon Hosting Migration Plan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-hosting-migration-plan/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-hosting-migration-plan/</id>
    <published>2017-04-13T13:57:45+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-13T13:57:45+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href="/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/"&gt;running Mastodon on Heroku&lt;/a&gt; for about a week now, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a blast! Heroku is really convenient, but it&amp;rsquo;s also expensive. So I&amp;rsquo;m looking at an alternative hosting plan. Because I&amp;rsquo;m learning as I go along, I wanted to write a post about my migration plan, to hopefully get feedback from people who&amp;rsquo;ve done this kind of thing before. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the current infrastructure: two Heroku apps, one for streaming and one for everything else. Estimated costs are ~$150/month. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect from AWS, but from my experience I&amp;rsquo;m guess that it&amp;rsquo;ll be a lot less than I&amp;rsquo;m paying now. Additionally, as the community scales up, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to more easily scale my instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered Digital Ocean, since it would probably be even cheaper, but I would have to do a lot more to administer Postgres and Redis instances, which seems boring and tedious. I&amp;rsquo;d rather use RDS and ElastiCache respectively for the convenience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mastodon-hosting-migration-plan/heroku.png" alt="Current Heroku Infrastructure" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of is an AWS infrastructure that replaces Heroku Add-Ons for AWS services. I figure if I&amp;rsquo;m getting into AWS hosting I may as well dive right in, to get the most advantage from fully participating in their ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mastodon-hosting-migration-plan/aws.png" alt="Proposed AWS Infrastructure" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(Note that both infrastructures use S3 for static asset hosting, which is not shown.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the big question is, how do I go from one to the other? Well here&amp;rsquo;s my plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migrate Postgres from a Heroku Add-On to AWS&amp;rsquo; RDS service&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the highest priority since Heroku&amp;rsquo;s Postgres Add-On is currently the highest cost. I expect some downtime as I put the existing app in maintenance mode, export the database, and import it into RDS. I&amp;rsquo;ll do a dry-run first to make sure things work; maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll set up a fresh Heroku app that points to the new database. The nice thing is, if things go wrong I can just point back to the existing database. Once I verify things are working (maybe give it a few days?) I&amp;rsquo;ll retire the existing database Add-On.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migrate Redis from a Heroku &lt;a href="https://redislabs.com/products/redis-cloud/"&gt;Redis Cloud&lt;/a&gt; Add-On to AWS&amp;rsquo; ElastiCache service&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a lower priority because I expect it&amp;rsquo;ll take some figuring out, and there&amp;rsquo;ll be some downtime. My plan is to set up ElastiCache to replicate the existing store, put the app into maintenance mode, give the new store a chance to catch up, and switch the app over to the new store. Let me know if you&amp;rsquo;ve done this before and see any problems with this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migrate from Heroku Dynos to AWS EC2&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the biggest question mark for me. It&amp;rsquo;s going to require a lot of effort because I&amp;rsquo;ve not run a server like this before. Basically I&amp;rsquo;ll get an EC2 running the web server, streaming server, and Sidekiq jobs, make sure it&amp;rsquo;s working, and then switch the DNS to slowly move everyone over to the new server. Once DNS changes have fully propagated, retire the Dynos. If I have to, I&amp;rsquo;ll separate out the web, streaming, and Sidekiq responsibilities into separate instances. Let me know if this is something I should do from the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deal with the little things&lt;/strong&gt;. Stuff like setting up cron jobs, making sure logging is working, that kind of stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aaaaaaand I think that&amp;rsquo;s it. Hopefully minimal downtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a learning experience for me. It seemed really scary at first but writing it out made things make more sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reckon this will take a solid weekend of work, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy to do it because a) I really like Mastodon and contributing to a distributed community is rewarding, and b) I&amp;rsquo;ll learn a tonne, which is its own reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And again, any advice you have would be welcome. &lt;a href="http://mastodon.technology/@ashfurrow"&gt;Toot me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="mailto:ash@ashfurrow.com"&gt;send me an email&lt;/a&gt; if you have any advice, and I&amp;rsquo;ll amend my post.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Running Mastodon on Heroku</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/</id>
    <published>2017-04-07T15:50:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-07T15:50:03+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href="/blog/mastodon-administration/"&gt;running an instance&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; this week. It&amp;rsquo;s be a fun adventure! I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure where it&amp;rsquo;ll end up but I&amp;rsquo;m learning a tonne. So let&amp;rsquo;s share some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned by running Mastodon on &lt;a href="http://heroku.com"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to help out with some of the hosting costs, please head on over &lt;a href="https://patreon.com/user?u=3581610"&gt;to my Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/info.png" alt="Extended info" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First, a few things. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; Heroku; it&amp;rsquo;s server administration that&amp;rsquo;s friendly to iOS developers like me who don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about server administration. But! Heroku support for Mastodon is  e x p e r i m e n t a l . That&amp;rsquo;s fine, this whole thing is an experiment! Life is an experiment. And like life, there are some issues I&amp;rsquo;ve run into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon/issues/1007"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;Animated GIF upload doesn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. GIFs are transcoded on the Mastodon server, and that requires ffmpeg to be in your buildpack. But that will put you &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; over the 300MB slug size on Heroku.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon/issues/1119"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;Streaming API doesn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Not sure of the cause yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: These are being addressed in more long-term ways, but for now I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten them to work. Check out the issues for more details.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to the good stuff: how to get Mastodon set up. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/resources.png" alt="Heroku Resources" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The initial deploy (use the &amp;ldquo;Deploy to Heroku&amp;rdquo; button &lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon#deployment-on-heroku-experimental"&gt;in the readme&lt;/a&gt; is going to install two dynos, Redis, and Postgres. You &lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon/blob/4e41cd9ab8f51120d558b70528b163c98993be53/config/puma.rb#L11-L13"&gt;only need the first Dyno&lt;/a&gt;, the web one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I registered a domain (&lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology"&gt;mastodon.technology&lt;/a&gt;) with &lt;a href="https://www.hover.com"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; and used Heroku&amp;rsquo;s SSL support to serve the Mastodon instance over HTTPS. It&amp;rsquo;s 2017, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Heroku, your limiting resource is going to be RAM. I&amp;rsquo;m using one 2x Dyno for the extra RAM, and I&amp;rsquo;ve set the &lt;code&gt;WEB_CONCURRENCY&lt;/code&gt; environmental variable to &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; to avoid scaling issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://elements.heroku.com/addons/papertrail"&gt;Papertrail&lt;/a&gt; is logging service. I tried their free tier but exceeded my daily log limit the second day.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/postgres.png" alt="Postgres" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I had to &lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/upgrading-heroku-postgres-databases"&gt;upgrade my Postgres instance&lt;/a&gt; almost immediately. It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult to do, which was nice. Heroku makes a lot of this &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; easy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/redis.png" alt="Redis" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I also needed to upgrade my Redis instance almost immediately, to avoid &lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon/issues/957"&gt;500 errors&lt;/a&gt;. Redis was the first scaling problem I hit. It looks like a super-useful service, but is priced really aggressively on Heroku. I understand why – Heroku is a business trying to make money – but it&amp;rsquo;s frustrating that costs double for a few extra megabytes of RAM. Or maybe I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand how Redis works &lt;code&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/scheduler.png" alt="Scheduler for cron jobs" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I added a &lt;a href="https://elements.heroku.com/addons/scheduler"&gt;scheduler&lt;/a&gt; add-on for some of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon#tasks"&gt;cron tasks&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m still experimenting with the task frequency, but you can see what works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so that&amp;rsquo;s the Heroku setup. I also used &lt;a href="https://www.mailgun.com"&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; for email sending (the free tier is fine) and &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com"&gt;AWS S3&lt;/a&gt; for storing media that gets uploaded (dunno costs there yet). Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;m using free &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com"&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt; as a CDN in front of S3, and to host the S3 bucket on its own domain (static.mastodon.technology) that has a Cloudflare SSL certificate. This is important. Without HTTPS support for your media uploads, you&amp;rsquo;ll be serving mixed content (HTTP assets on an HTTPS page). This causes problems on iOS and some web browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst part was just waiting for the DNS changes to propagate. I&amp;rsquo;m using Cloudflare for DNS, and pointed the domain name servers from Hover to use Cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after all this configuration, I&amp;rsquo;m still running into performance issues. The site completely fell over this morning and I have no idea why.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/running-mastodon-on-heroku/perf.png" alt="Performance" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It leads me to wonder how long I can keep this up, but like I said, life is an experiment and I&amp;rsquo;m just rolling with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heroku support is experimental, and like Mastodon, it&amp;rsquo;s continuing to evolve. If you have small needs, I&amp;rsquo;d say go for it. If you want to be the next big instance, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to invest in a more sophisticated hosting solution. I looked at Digital Ocean for using the Docker image but quickly got in over my head; Heroku is it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update on Medication Changes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/update-on-medication-changes/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/update-on-medication-changes/</id>
    <published>2017-04-06T00:01:54+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-06T00:01:54+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been open about my &lt;a href="/blog/good-bad-days/"&gt;recent changes to antidepressant medications&lt;/a&gt; and I wanted to provide an update about how things are going. In a word: well. Things are going well. A lot better than they&amp;rsquo;ve gone in a long time, in fact. I attribute this improvement to a recent change in medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depression saps energy from me. There are days I can&amp;rsquo;t even get out of bed because it takes too much energy. What I miss most about &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; having depression is the abundance of things to do. There were days in university where I would stay up all night configuring drivers for a hackintosh because I was just &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; excited to do it. Or times in Toronto when I&amp;rsquo;d walk myself to exhaustion taking photos all day, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss feeling &lt;em&gt;compelled&lt;/em&gt; to do something: the ecstasy of borderline mania that accompanies me when I&amp;rsquo;m accomplishing something I have my heart set on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling a trickle of that energy. Not a lot, but more than, you know, none. I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the projects I get to work on at Artsy, I&amp;rsquo;m writing on this blog more I&amp;rsquo;m taking guitar lessons, I&amp;rsquo;m hosting an &lt;a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon/"&gt;OSS social network&lt;/a&gt; for crying out loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time in a while, the things I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;excited&lt;/em&gt; to do exceed the number of hours I have to spend on them. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to play guitar, but also excited to write this blog post. I have to pick one, and here we are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, it&amp;rsquo;s introducing some FOMO and I&amp;rsquo;m having a hard time dealing with that kind of anxiety. This is progress. Recovery isn&amp;rsquo;t a straight line, and if my recouped energy leads me to a little anxiety around what to spend my time on, well then I&amp;rsquo;ll have to deal with that. No problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mastodon Administration</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-administration/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon-administration/</id>
    <published>2017-04-05T22:44:43+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-05T22:44:43+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I &lt;a href="/blog/mastodon/"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about starting my own Mastodon instance. It&amp;rsquo;s like a federated Twitter, and it&amp;rsquo;s really fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a place for tech folks to hang out, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of experience with server administration. So I chose Heroku. Things have gone&amp;hellip; okay. Mostly good, even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve run into a number of scaling issues, 500 errors, questions I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to, yikes. So I&amp;rsquo;ve spent time searching for answers, scaling up Heroku Dynos, configuring DNS settings, and upgrading Postgres databases. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mastodon-administration/resources.png" alt="Resources" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My hope is that these resources will be sufficient for some time while the community scales. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on starting a Patreon to help cover the hosting costs, and maybe even a little of my time. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to start asking for help unless I&amp;rsquo;m certain that this is something I want to build in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this has taken time away from the rest of my life. If that cost is largely upfront, with ongoing costs not taking up a lot of time, then that&amp;rsquo;s great. But I can&amp;rsquo;t afford to give dozens of hours a month to this project. If things start looking dire, at least I know who to ask for help 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, here are the metrics for the Heroku app. The red numbers worry me. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how things go. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of migrating the whole instance over to a Digital Ocean instance, which would bring the costs down considerably, but the limiting factor is my time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/mastodon-administration/metrics.png" alt="Metrics" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At first I was really overwhelmed because things weren&amp;rsquo;t always running perfectly. Then I realized that this is just a process, an experiment, and I should relax. People have been thanking me for setting up the instance, which has felt really nice. Even if this space turns out to be ephemeral, it&amp;rsquo;s still its own community, and creating that community is really rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I accepted that the instance won&amp;rsquo;t be around forever, that at some point in the future it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; shut down (all websites will eventually), once I accepted that fact, things became a lot less stressful. So what if GIF uploads aren&amp;rsquo;t work, or 2FA is broken? I&amp;rsquo;m opening GitHub issues to ask for help, and I&amp;rsquo;m getting helped. I&amp;rsquo;m contributing back documentation improvements. I&amp;rsquo;m learning a &lt;em&gt;tonne&lt;/em&gt; about how to administer websites through firsthand experience and experimentation. And I&amp;rsquo;m helping contribute to an entire community of online communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology"&gt;join&lt;/a&gt;, if you like, in a social media experiment and experience. It might not last – but nothing does – and in the mean time, you can have fun and meet new friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re keen, I&amp;rsquo;m going to need help. Things on my agenda are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define a code of conduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help to establish community norms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;respond to reported abuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in helping, let&amp;rsquo;s chat.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mastodon</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/mastodon/</id>
    <published>2017-04-05T01:11:09+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-05T01:11:09+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love Twitter. I have a community there of people I talk with, learn from, it&amp;rsquo;s great. But Twitter also has serious problems that stop everyone from being able to participate in that community. That sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was keen on App.net, when it was around. It never really had the chance to get off the ground, I feel, since they tried a pay model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, a free-and-open-source distributed microblogging service. Sarah Jeong has great things to say in her article &lt;a href="https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/mastodon-is-like-twitter-without-nazis-so-why-are-we-not-using-it"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mastodon Is Like Twitter Without Nazis, So Why Are We Not Using It?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I was intrigued and signed up to one of the more popular instances that Jeong mentioned in her article. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t around too long in &lt;a href="https://awoo.space"&gt;Awoo&lt;/a&gt; before noticing that the existing community was starting to feel uncomfortable with the influx of outsiders. One of the posts said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While queer furries are the &amp;lsquo;old guard&amp;rsquo; of mastodon.social&amp;hellip; here we run the joint. You are in our house, and we expect safety and calm to be the order of the day here. If you want something more lively or tech-y, find another instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still wanna stay? If you behave and respect us, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am 100% on board with respecting people, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want my presence to make anyone feel like their space is not theirs. So I decided I&amp;rsquo;d try to run my own instance for tech folks like me. If you&amp;rsquo;re keen, head over to &lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology"&gt;mastodon.technology&lt;/a&gt; and sign up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the instance took a few hours of configuration (I&amp;rsquo;m not that great at this) and some email providers aren&amp;rsquo;t letting the confirmation emails through (if you don&amp;rsquo;t get an email, &lt;a href="mailto:ash@ashfurrow.com"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ll get you confirmed). I put it on a Heroku hobby plan, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how things go. If costs become a burden, I&amp;rsquo;ll throw up a Patreon or something. (&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I &lt;a href="https://patreon.com/user?u=3581610"&gt;did start a Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t promise that this instance will be around forever, or ever around next week, but I think that Mastodon&amp;rsquo;s distributed nature makes it a great bet for the future of microblogging (&lt;a href="http://micro.blog"&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; looks promising too). Come hang out, help me build an inclusive community, and have fun. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RxSwift Book Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/rxswift-book-announcement/"/>
    <id>https://ashfurrow.com/blog/rxswift-book-announcement/</id>
    <published>2017-04-03T08:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-03T08:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Furrow</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well well well, look what we have here. After months of toiling in secret, I can finally announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve helped the &lt;a href="https://raywenderlich.com"&gt;Ray Wenderlich team&lt;/a&gt; complete a brand new RxSwift book! &lt;a href="https://store.raywenderlich.com/products/rxswift"&gt;RxSwift: Reactive Programming in Swift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.raywenderlich.com/products/rxswift"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ashfurrow.com/img/blog/rxswift-book-announcement/cover.png" alt="Book cover" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been serving as a technical editor to help make sure the book is correct, awesome, and cohesive. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a blast working with Florent Pillet, Junior Bontognali, Marin Todorov, Scott Gardner, and Chris Belanger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been really hard to keep this under wraps, partially because I&amp;rsquo;m so excited about it and partially because people keep asking me for a Swift version of my existing &lt;a href="https://leanpub.com/iosfrp"&gt;Functional Reactive Programming on iOS book&lt;/a&gt;. Well it&amp;rsquo;s finally here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is much more than I could have accomplished on my own, from a team that&amp;rsquo;s used to writing top-notch tutorials. I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of what we accomplished, and I hope you enjoy reading it as much as we enjoyed making it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
